Good morning. It's odd. I'm recording in the morning today
What you may have noticed was I guess the the main thing people are gonna be talking about is gonna be that
Reverend governor governor Ron DeSantis announced his presidential race on Twitter
No, I'm not political. I don't
Whatever you believe is what you believe. Everybody should research
Everything don't just pick a side just research things and choose what's best for you. And sometimes that means
Voting across the aisle on things believe it or not
so
why am I interested in talking about the
Ron DeSantis
announcement of his presidential campaign on Twitter
Well, I think there's a couple of things. I the main thing is it was pretty neat to see
the Twitter being able to support something like
300,000 people in a room and of course
all the
I'm sure all the news outlets are gonna talk about the botched initial
run of the
the whole thing
because
it was ran from Elon Musk's account and he has some hundred and forty million followers or something like that and
then you combine that with half a million people listening to the Twitter spaces and
that I think is a
Tiff huge technical challenge to be able to host that many people in real time. Of course. I have some questions like
when you talk on Twitter spaces with that many people is it delayed as it's
syndicating the the communication across all these servers or was it taken down because
Was it I'm just curious on whether it was taking down because it scaled too fast too many servers spun up too quickly
or
Was it taken down because maybe it's it's trying to simultaneously send all of this information all in one go
which
is
difficult
300 300,000
People listening it's 300,000
Streams of audio it needs to send out and that's that's a pretty that's a pretty difficult task for for
any
infrastructure, so
That was super interesting now on the more
I guess
Human level of the whole thing. I think that
politicians
launching on on things like
social media is very interesting because now we're seeing the politicians move from
And we've seen the shift where politics moves from the realm of television
You know how people get their information that way so they move from going on the road
Driving around talking to people in towns. They still do that obviously
But then they move from that and then they moved on to the internet and then they moved
Or they moved to TV and then they moved to internet and now they're moving even further away from from kind of more traditional
Ways of doing it and I think
it also is interesting because
You know normally we watch these
Politicians they go up on a stage and they've spent I don't know a million dollars or something on this production
And having all these people come in and you know
They play it they've they've paid some rock and roll artists to play their music while they walk on stage
to a huge fanfare like there's some sort of rock star and
To me politicians are just dudes that are supposed to go and you know
I vote for them and they do what I voted for or something like that
I don't I don't I didn't vote for a rock star
I think it's weird to to have this this whole thing personally personally now you like I said
There's no right way if you like them going on stage like a rock star to a cheering fan like playing all this music
That's your thing
The Rhonda Santas announcement on Twitter circle was not that it was it was almost like a podcast
is
Quiet is straightforward. There's some weirdness that comes that came with the start because you know
The dudes talking as if he's talking to a crowd that's gonna cheer and and you know
That's just how politicians talk. I mean, they have a way of speaking for for crowds and
You know when when you're done speaking is just quiet and the guy then the next person goes say, okay, let's ask some questions
so it was definitely an interesting experience whether you love them or hate them and so
that whole experience of I mean
You could see it pop up in your head and you're like, okay, okay
I mean you could see it positively that you know I don't know how much money is
spent in in politics on announcing that you're running for a presidential race
on Twitter. I feel like it's maybe eight dollars a month or whatever governments
pay but you know rather than having this stage and paying for music and all this
other stuff it seems very dare I say it conservative to announce kind of on this
more or less like less fanfare-y kind of scenario. It's interesting. Now I'm not
talking directly about Ron DeSantis himself. He's had plenty of these kinds
of rallies and stuff and in fact inside of the spaces he asked for you to go
fund his account or whatever his political account. I don't send
politicians money. They figure out how to make lots of money on their own.
But yeah it's nice to see something so I don't know it felt more
human in many ways because it wasn't just some dude yelling at you on a stage
to some rock and roll band or something. It was you know there was that initial
you know rah-rah but then there's just a bunch of questions like you're just
talking to the dude and people came in and out and I don't know. It was
definitely interesting take and that's that's kind of my perspective on what
happened with the Ron DeSantis Twitter announcement. So yeah if you don't want
to check it out don't check it out. It's not that interesting. It's
definitely boring like every political thing on the planet but the technology
wise and seeing that there was that many people listening live and
imagining kind of the server stack and all this sort of stuff that had to go
behind the scenes and it's interesting that also that Twitter
recovered pretty quickly from what I understand. The first one crashed and
then the second one spun up pretty quick and they were able to diagnose the
issue I think was related to Elon Musk having 140 million people and
syndicating to that many people. Their servers couldn't handle so they used
some other dude I don't know his name is they used his account. Much smaller
follow base and I looked at his follow base just to see you know what was the
difference and why would you know how much does it can these Twitter circles
handle and he had like 500,000 followers so way way way way way way less than
Elon Musk and I think that was why it was able to kind of sustain. Yeah I'm
interested to see what kind of technology that what kind of special
magic that Twitter uses for syndicating their Twitter circles or spaces or
whatever it's called. It's interesting. Now I would be disappointed if it's just
spin up a whole bunch of AW2 instances which is if you don't know Amazon web
services they host like they allow you to host web servers for reasonable price
and you can spin up these servers and tear them down depending on demand and
how much throughput you have on the network so how many people are trying to
access it. And then they have back-end load balancers so it can detect where
you're trying to to connect from to the server and then the load balancers can
direct you to the servers that have less less people on those servers and closer
to those people so they can spin up servers near where people are listening
or viewing the content so yeah be disappointed if it was just AW2
EC2 scaling so yeah I don't know I'd like to see a postmortem
technical report on this particular tech because you know it's not video. Video
streaming is another thing but we already know through Twitch and all
these other platforms that video streaming is just highly delayed and I
don't think spaces is delayed that much because one of the key parts of its
technology is you can just bring somebody from the audience and start
talking to them in real time. Now you know behind the scenes when you bring
somebody from the audience to speak perhaps it it changes the server but
that would be a huge disconnect if you are listening somebody says oh let me
get somebody in here and then they pull them in and they start talking to them
if there was a delay in anywhere in that in the audio it would be a really weird
experience for that person coming in. They would be hearing something from you
know some time in the past and then just all of a sudden be pulled in to speak
and they wouldn't know what they're speaking about. So I think that it has to
be real-time just for that scenario. So very interesting tech I'd like to know a
little bit more on that I think. So if you so happen to know what they do there
I haven't I mean I guess I can go online and see if they have done a blog post or
anything but yeah just let me know be pretty freaking sweet. So beyond the
politics and the tech behind politics there's a whole bunch of little things
that happened in tech recently and also in science. I wanted to share this
because it completely ruined my childhood. So there is this article here
you know these dinosaurs hold on let me fix this you know these dinosaurs that
have the the dome head and you just imagine that they always bash each other
in the head whenever they were you know you saw it in in was Littlefoot what is
the end anyways and the Littlefoot movies Land Before Time. They would bash
each other's heads and you know any dinosaur movie even Jurassic Park I
believe had a few of these dudes and they would bash each other's heads. Well
the the article here I don't know where the title went but it basically describes
that oh here it is a new study suggests that dome-headed dinosaurs did not butt
heads with each other and that ruined my childhood. Like what are they supposed to
do with those heads? Are they thinkers? Did they all just you know these were
the smart dinosaurs and they I don't know it still looks like a tiny section
based on the size of their skull. If you don't know normally we we measure brain
power based on the size of the body I think is the easiest way to explain it.
So that's why birds are smart but whales are dumb is the the size of the brain
relative to the the size of the entity matters and so people's brains make up
you know a pretty good chunk like this part of their head and if people are
about five or six head tall and half of their head is dedicated to the brain
you know that's that's why we that's why we smart or sometimes smart but anyways
yeah my childhood was ruined. I don't know I don't know if I can like
these dinosaurs anymore without knowing more about them. If they were like you
know the the philosophers of the time because they were smart or something
they just had this big old dome you know I don't know maybe I should read this
article at some point I was just I saw the headline and I skimmed through a
little bit of the article and disappointment settled. So that was a
little fun kind of on the side thing that I was looking at. Okay so to a
little bit of a larger thing that has happened recently Microsoft has been in
the rounds basically all day yesterday. They had their build announcement which
is their you know it's kind of like Google I oh they're not there to sell
products but they partly are there to sell products and they're also there to
tell developers. These conferences they start off with a good heart and
then wind up like E3 so they do these things they originally do these things
to tell developers about all the APIs and services that are available now to
developers because without developers developing things for your platform you
you're useless nobody's interested. You want people to take all the APIs and the
services that you write and then go and write things on top of it in order to
promote your platform. You get more sales, you get more traffic, etc etc. Now I
think Google and Microsoft it's kind of like GDC if you guys are game developers
GDC the game developer conference it starts off you know very tech heavy and
all this sort of stuff and sure it's still tech heavy and they go into tech
stuff but it slowly creeps into advertising where it's about promoting
your game and showing off the game you're working on and showing off these
technologies for games and selling you products and of course the the
conference itself has to make some money and the incentive structure for companies
to go and tell their secrets and all that not really tell their secrets but
just kind of talk about how they develop stuff the incentive structure is they've
got to make money so it does it does make sense that it it would be a natural
progression from talking about tech to trying to sell you products. Anyways the
Microsoft build announcements were a lot basically AI lots of AI stuff there was
a lot of new Windows 11 things in fact Windows 11 two nights ago updated on me
and moved a bunch of stuff around they may have fixed my start menu search so
far so good on that I if if you had that problem you know what I'm talking about
essentially you'd start up your computer you'd hit the start button you start
typing and it was just broken it just didn't work at all it was just
absolutely atrocious you had to hit escape a million times and the open and
close the start menu a few times before it started responding correctly and
where you can type into it and search for things and all that sort of stuff so
that I think is probably the happiest thing for me that came out of that is
just fixing my start menu so what all kind of came out of this well if you've
gotten the Windows update Windows 11 update you'll see that there's tabs
inside of the folders now when you go into Explorer you can now have multiple
tabs they move some things around I know this just from experience they move some
things around and removed for example if you're used to the I'm busy mode on the
was it called like snooze notifications or whatever they've moved that to the
date time so you click on the date time and it's in the top right if you're
curious about that they move that on me you can no longer put it inside of that
window that pops up when you click on the battery sound and an Ethernet button
but the most important things that they came out with was all AI stuff they
expect to have an AI copilot inside of the web inside of the directly inside of
Windows and essentially it's just chat GPT on Windows so that's interesting I
feel like it's a little weird because chat GPT all runs on their servers I
mean if you're running Windows are they already collecting all that information
about you or is this kind of a way to to collect a little bit more because this
information has to go somewhere and it goes through chat GPT I don't know what
their security or their privacy is for with with Microsoft on this I'm
transferring the data is it stored in chat GPT do they even tell them do they
even care I don't know but lots of AI stuff for Windows 11 came out so the
summary I have here is Windows copilot a feature that lets you ask questions and
perform tasks using natural language it can also work with your clipboard
content and system settings so clipboard content I'm not that security line has
already been broken for for me because you can like turn on history of copy
paste which is stored on Windows servers from what I recall because you can use
it across machines so that's not a huge surprise security there that's already
in my opinion insecure I have that feature off I think it's pointless
there's no reason to have clipboard content go to the Internet but in
general Windows copilot is essentially chat GPT on steroids on Windows it does
have some cool stuff you can ask it to search for documents or summarize
documents or convert speech to audio or audio to text and as far as I saw and a
bunch of other stuff so imagine just having a thing on Windows that can
understand more human language and convert that into doing tasks such as
changing system settings and opening up things and summarizing things and finding
things I imagine you'd be able to do stuff like where is some document and
it'll go through the different kind of databases that it has in Windows to
locate the document that sort of stuff so there is some some definite utility
there to improve your your productivity on Windows but at what cost like I said
I don't know what the security of all this is there is also being in chat GPT
being is now the default search engine for chat GPT a popular conversational AI
everybody knows what chat GPT is this will enable chat GPT to obtain new
information and answer more questions being in chat GPT will also share
plugins so is this just being going in a chat GPT like they're taking a Bing
model that does the internet searchings and just kind of fusing the two so now
it's a pipeline between being in chat cheap chat GPT so anytime chat GPT kind
of improves something it just automatically goes to being that'd be an
interesting take and probably smart business wise for them but there you can
see that Microsoft is is trying to intertwine a lot more with their gigantic
multi-billion dollar investment into open AI so I would not be surprised if
Microsoft puts out a deal to buy them or absorb them or Microsoft owns a huge
portion of shares more than just giving the money I don't know I I think we're
gonna see a much deeper integration there one of the main things is that
anyone can use the chat GPT or any of the open AI services themselves with the
API and a lot of search engines and various other kind of Microsoft
competitors are using that so by integrating themselves into it is an
interesting way to cut out the competition I think that's definitely a
business move file Explorer redesign we talked about that a little bit my
summary is Windows 11 we'll have a new file Explorer with modern look and new
features blah blah blah it will take a new it will take a new address bar file
actions navigation recommended files and gallery view so I think they're updating
the Explorer because all the different Microsoft things have to be updated to
better interact with this AI these this upcoming AI doom that we will all be
forced to use if we're using Windows Microsoft Store improvements for those
of you might use Microsoft Store I actually do use Microsoft Store every
now and then I I like that I can buy for example affinity products on there like
affinity photo and just be able to install it on different Windows machines
without having to fill around with keys and seats and all that sort of stuff
that's it's pretty nice feature for it and Windows 11 features Windows 11 will
support a taskbar ungrouping native opening for more archive formats as you
know everyone's making the meme about Windows being able to unrar RARS is that
what it's calling do you call it unrar ring anyways and you know they're just
more zips format compression formats kind of like limit Linux and Linux pretty
much any flavor of Linux you use can has many different types of compression
formats that it can extract or compress so similar thing so Windows for a long
time just defaults to only having zip there may be other features of
compression deeper in in the software but exposing it up front is really nice
and reduces the need for third-party programs like winrar rest in peace as
the as the meme goes
dynamic lighting for peripherals, running Windows 32 apps in isolation, Bluetooth
low-energy, and one of the most important things is ARM 32 app support will be
dropped. So they are progressing more towards ARM and you can see it. I think
they also announced that they are gonna allow for ARM virtual machines in Hyper-V.
So ARM is gonna be a big deal. Everyone knows it. I mean ARM ironically has been
around since the 70s. It came in Acorn computers I believe and the architecture
is designed for code generation. So when you write inside of a programming
language and you go and compile it, it generates assembly code or machine code
for the computer to run the program. Intel computers in x86 and x64
architecture have an advantage that they can fine-tune different actions of the
CPU to be faster. So you can imagine it can do stuff with artificial
intelligence, it can reduce, it has you know SIMD instructions, all these other
things that can make certain tasks much faster. And with ARM architecture the
whole concept is I think it's called RISC, reduced instruction set computing
or CPU. I don't know what the C stands for. It's about 52 instructions I believe
and they're very set and so it's perfect for generating code because you can just
generate code simply to this machine. It's not really made for handwriting
assembly like x64 can be because it's so expressive. It's more for generated code
because there are very few actions and you repeat yourself a lot. So anyways
those are the updates on Windows 11 build. It's pretty interesting stuff.
Go check out all the changes. I'm sure some will affect you if you're on
Windows 11. I'm on Windows 11 just because new computers come with it and
so I don't like fiddling around and downgrading. I like to sometimes just be
on the new operating system and see how it handles. It usually gets better
security and all that sort of stuff. Usually, not always. They put more focus
on fixing the new thing that's for sure. So that's Windows 11 and that's you know
fun stuff. I'm curious to use some of these APIs. We'll see if they how well
they integrate them or if they're just web requests. Now the I think yesterday
one of the more surprising things that popped up was this goofy handheld from
PlayStation. Now you probably have already seen this. It is not it's not it's
not a handheld like like a Steam Deck or a Switch or anything like that. So don't
get too excited. It's a streaming device. How it's different from the Wii U, how
it's different from Nvidia Shield, how is different from like that Logitech thing.
It's different because it plays PlayStation 5 exclusively as far as I
understand it. You run the game on the PlayStation 5 and it streams to the
handheld. Now that's I mean that's kind of cool. I can see the applications to it
for you know laying in bed and just having your console in the living room
or something. But you're locking down to a specific device so you have to have a
PlayStation first of all. And you you're only streaming. So this is worse than a
PlayStation PS Vita or PSP in my opinion because you can't just take games
with you. That's what people want to do with handhelds. They want to take games
with them. And of course you know Sony might be thinking, ah well everybody's
working from home and stop going to work these days and stop going places these
days. So you know why you even need to take games you can just stream them. I
don't know maybe that's their perspective. Or maybe they saw that Steam
Deck and like the Asus handheld that just came out and you know the
Switch were super popular and they were sitting around in their business meeting
they're like these gaming devices are getting a lot of money. Obviously people
like viewing games on screens in their hands. So that's why those devices are
selling and that's what we're gonna do. We're gonna focus tons of money on
this. I don't know how they didn't look at the basically the failure of the Wii U
and the failure of Nvidia Shield and say hmm maybe we shouldn't spend a whole
lot of money making this handheld for just our console. And like I said you can
you can make this exact device except that it'll work on Xbox and PC and
you know all those other platforms by just buying a connector for your
controller to your phone. So you could just put your phone and connect it to
your controller. Literally the same thing and way cheaper. You can buy one of those
little phone clips for like 10 bucks. So superfluous I think so. This is the main
problem with these streaming devices is that they're very niche. They really I
don't think have an audience and people. There are gonna be some people that are
hyped about it that are super like into PlayStation but yeah it's you know when
you and when you advertise 1080p 60fps that's neat. I mean that's lower
resolution than a phone and lower refresh rate than a phone normally is.
So most people have way better screens in their pockets than this will ever
hope to be and you can use that same screen to stream games on it. I don't
know. I think this was a goofy take on Sony so just wanted to bring it up. Kind
of funny. I mean it would be really cool if it was if maybe they have some kind
of update later to actually play games but I don't think so. I think this is a
screen with controller sticks on the side but I don't know. You be the judge.
If you really like it that's I'm not saying it's bad. Go get it. You go
try to test it out. Maybe it's more it's probably more convenient to have a
separate thing for just your console. I don't know. I don't have a PlayStation 5
so yeah that's the main thing for me. I still can't play PlayStation games.
So more in the tech world news. Meta which is just Facebook is selling Jiffy.
I guess it wasn't making the money they expected to be or something like that or
or they're losing a lot of money and they need to make up some more money. I
mean it like I said in the last episode they made something like 28 billion
dollars this year so far you know in just five months. So interesting that
they've got to start selling off assets. Probably maybe it's to focus a little
more or something like that. I have no idea. This wasn't a huge win. They sold
Jiffy and they lost three hundred and forty seven million dollars on the deal
because they bought it for... what did they buy it for? Let's see. Okay well they
bought it for four hundred million dollars so this says in May of 2000 and
in May of 2023 so three years later they sold it for 53 million to Shutterstock.
I mean Shutterstock made a huge deal there. They got Jiffy. All they had to do
is wait and they got Jiffy for like a super discount. So I think that those
numbers are maybe a general search but it's about those numbers. So yeah it's
interesting that tech companies will buy these with big hopes. I mean for all we
know Facebook kind of bought the service, learned the technology, cloned the
technology and then sold off the title, the name or something like that.
They very much have the assets that they needed which is probably just getting
you know the repository from Jiffy. Is it Giphy or Jiffy? I don't know.
I guess it depends on whether you're a Gif-Jiff person. So they've gotten all
the assets. They probably stored them all in the database and now can present them
themselves. So in a way they made a little bit of money back and spent less
money. I don't know. I don't know what these companies are doing. That's that
was just a weird interesting I guess not really that interesting but it was a
weird story about what was going what happened with with Facebook purchasing
and selling stuff. And companies buying and selling these things is nothing new.
They'll set a loss sometimes. I don't know exactly what each business decision is
but some companies will even buy other companies in order to shelve the product
because they're working on something themselves and they want they don't want
the competition. So normally they don't sell it in that scenario. So you can also
buy companies to essentially get their assets maybe get their talent their
workers their employees and you know just kind of absorb a bunch of resources
and then selling off the husks to somebody else to either do the same or
just get you know it's a benefit to whoever buys it I believe in this case.
But yeah companies do this kind of stuff all the time so it's not super
surprising but it's interesting seeing that company get passed around
right now. Okay in the artificial intelligence realm they have they have
this new stuff they have new things ever like every day and there's there's
websites that are dedicated to specifically just showing you you know
the thousands of trained models that people have out there and the thousands
of trained AI services you can use. It's it's pretty mind-boggling how many
there are. But this one is pretty interesting I think I was talking to a
friend of mine and there are you know applications in art for this. As you
know I do some art stuff. I like to draw and animate and that sort of stuff
well time-permitting. So I'm interested in things that affect art in this way. So
researchers in this one use AI to identify similar materials on images.
That is to say they can take a video or they can take an image or a sequence of
images which is a video and be able to track parts of that image that are
similar. I don't know you know a lot of the times we don't fully understand how
the AI is operating but my guesstimate is that it bases on color and the way
the thing the things similarly like feel when they look same kind of way we see
something and and guess that it's the same material. Here's a image of it
showing isolation on these pants that this person is wearing. They're flowing
and swilling. So one of the things my friend brought up was this would be
really cool for rotoscoping. You'd be able to isolate and rotoscope your your
2d animations using this. And of course you know you're gonna have people to say
what's the point of rotoscoping when you have AI that can just generate stuff.
Look people have their own styles built in their heads whether an AI can copy
it is is irrelevant. We want to see our drawings kind of go out and and kind of
how we see things. It's not always just big corporation money-making for us
people who draw. I don't know why people think that. I mean there's a lot of
people that are really loud out there where it's all about the money but
sometimes it's not. It's just about the fun of drawing. I mean yeah anyways
that's a whole other rant aside. But this is really cool because you can like you
saying you can use it for say rotoscoping and one of the ideas I had
based on that was that you can use it to study. So you can take flowing movement
things and you can isolate them in an image very easily with this kind of
technology without having to open up you know After Effects and tracking things
and deleting the background and all that sort of stuff. You can you can actually
take just a video and then isolate it and then study the flow and the
movement and the bounciness and how how it reacts to stuff so that you can
better animate for people who animate. Just people who draw in general study
but people who animate study a lot because they have to see how things move
and interact and what's the natural movement of things and all this other
sort of stuff. So it's actually pretty neat for this technology. There's a lot
of conversation on it on this on this website but you'll see that it detects
the changes. So you can see they're trying to detect the top of the matches
here and as the matches get burned it slowly whittles away and they have
it in white the focus the focus material that is similar. And so you can see it
changes over time so it's not just tracking its position obviously we saw
that with the pant legs it's actually trying to determine the material based
on the the images it's being fed. So really cool AI. If you guys ever run into
any sort of AI that could be really helpful in art just studying it and
having fun with it and kind of isolating things so you can try out new art
techniques let me know I really love that sort of stuff. I'm not a doom and
gloom AI person I'm in tech and I love artificial intelligence it's a neat
technology and I I like to see it as a tool more than a doomsday. So if you've
been having trouble getting GPUs recently I don't think you should
anymore I think the sales are coming down because all the crypto stuff. It
looks like Nvidia is losing some money on gamers right now you can pick up
cards pretty cheaply that sort of stuff but really what Nvidia is banking on and
it says it's has the same exact concept in this. I mean let's roll back
Nvidia has been pushing artificial intelligence a lot. Everybody's pushing
artificial intelligence it's the new cloud it's I mean is way bigger than the
whole cloud buzz was so it does have that it's like the new automobile or
something like that it's it's a big deal because it's it's a big deal in the
digital space currently because it's kind of changing all the stuff that
we've done digitally it's becoming more noisy it's filtering out noises it's
doing all kinds of weird stuff right now it's messing with jobs that are all
digital program from programming to art the entire spectrum anything you do on a
computer is affected by this sort of technology. So naturally Nvidia has been
focused on producing cards that optimize AI and if you don't know why GPUs are so
useful for artificial intelligence it's because GPUs have many cores you can
think of your CPU having many cores like now they have 20 or 24 but GPUs have you
know an order of magnitude larger than that for example you can get very easily
get a GPU that has 512 cores and you you can pay more money to get more cores and
why this is important is because these algorithms for example your brain if you
think of it as a big old matrix of neurons you just have a bunch you have
imagine you had a cube and then that cube is a bunch of little dots and those
dots connect to each other and they fire off and in order to make decisions they
kind of go through these processes of firing off and determine or not firing
firing or not firing and it's a big old grid of them so when you have a GPU that
has that exact makeup and it looks like that it's a big old grid and you can run
a little program that that essentially goes through these this grid system and
can pass information one quarter of another or can run in parallel because
if you know CPUs you can run you can run functions in your program in parallel
which you can run up to the number of cores or the number of hyper threads
that you have on the CPU so when it comes to the GPU it's the same thing
except you got tons and tons and tons of them so GPUs are extremely good at
producing images for example because you can you can say you can take a pixel on
the screen and associate that to one of the nodes in the grid so if the more the
more of those you have the more pixels you can calculate for example in this
very simple example let's say that you know let's say that we had a hundred by
a hundred all right so you that means you could generate simultaneously on
your screen a hundred by a hundred pixels all in one call just
simultaneously so you see this is why GPUs are powerful they can run a huge
amount of similar calculations across many cores and that's very helpful for
artificial intelligence and now they have tensor cores but it all comes back
to this concept of you know stacking these cores into a grid system and all
this sort of stuff and you see this when you use APIs like tensorflow whatever
it's very similar to CUDA programming if you've ever programmed in CUDA I've done
some ray tracing stuff with it you can you can essentially define how many
cores you need and on what layout 2d layouts linear layouts all this other
stuff so Nvidia has been pushing artificial intelligence a lot so you
know some people are mocking them losing money on these graphics cards and why
are they raising the money's why are they raising the price so high look when
you're when you're a monopoly because Nvidia has a pretty strong monopoly on
artificial intelligence right now you can do that so what we're witnessing is
the birth of a monopoly so we need we need other graphics makers great
graphics cards makers which is like one of them one real one to come in and
compete otherwise we're gonna wind up in this scenario but yeah there's a there's
an article I think a PC gamer that says Nvidia doesn't care if you want if you
don't like its new graphics cards AI is going to make 11 billion dollars in just
three months and that's something I haven't even read this article I just
saw that and it made me think about it yeah I mean if you're a customer who
really likes AMD I press them in all their stuff like hey get into if you're
if you're a shareholder or anything like that say get into AI like Nvidia is just
double down on it because that's the future and and you know whatever we
learn in AI AI is gonna come to game so you know it already is it has been for a
long time I think was that that Forza that came out like years ago where it
would play as you would play online or whatever I don't know how effective it
was but that was AI we're gonna see a lot more of that in games so it would be
in any graphics cards best interest to get into artificial intelligence and
look there's a lot of potential for making more interesting games with AI I
think it's gonna be is gonna be a really goofy period for a while and I'm all for
it I love weird goofy games where AI is gonna do weird stuff but AI already does
really weird stuff in games when it's hand-coded so making artificial
intelligence go in there and do it I think is is interesting because now you
can have some weird stuff you just have to figure out how to how to curate it so
it can swap between the AI and physically you know hard-coded scenarios
for say story you don't want if you're in Skyrim you don't want a main
character that you need to decide that he's having a midlife crisis and jump
off a cliff so otherwise you won't be able to complete the main story so
there's gonna be some guardrails but yeah definitely AI in games is a big
thing and I think that if you're a GPU manufacturer you've got to focus on it
you can't let in the video just monopolize that space on the AI front
there is also I think if you have seen in the news somewhat recently there was
some European Union kind of legislation that they were pushing through for
specifically for open AI but for AI in general I believe it had something to do
with the transfer and collection of data same thing that Facebook was hit with a
1.3 billion dollar fine on let me see okay quick little search says that it
has to do with the aggregation of data you know that EU has a lot of strong
requirements for data collection and that sort of thing if you recall I mean
you don't even have to recall if you go to any website and you're hit with that
pop-up saying accept our cookies terms and services that was an EU thing that
every website does it and most of them don't even do it right they just throw
it up there and don't even it's just placebo it doesn't actually work and
there's also all kinds of plugins and tools to just delete those from the page
whenever you load them so they are quite annoying and really you should just if
you're worried about that sort of stuff you should use a browser or plugins to
stop tracking and all that but this isn't a talk about tracking or any of
that it's a talk about open AI in the EU so what open AI is saying is that you
know is they can't comply with the regulations because you know the way the
artificial intelligence has trained it's devastating for the for an artificial
intelligence that they're training to understand the internet and and
everything that's going on that has happened in history and what's going on
and that sort of stuff it's difficult to train something that is supposed to be
equivalent to a search engine because that's how for example chat GPT is being
designed it's being designed as an assistant in fact in the code you refer
to it as an assistant so it's being designed to be this thing you can
replace a search engine with you can query it you can ask about history you
can ask about you know news things that happen and all this sort of stuff so the
the argument is the same argument that they use for AI with art is that if you
put your art out there publicly no no watermarks or anything just for anybody
to see that the person then can kind of copy your style or even copy your image
use it to train their brain how to draw better and so AI they say the AI is just
doing the same thing this isn't an argument about whether that's moral
ethical or whatever I'm just saying that's that's the argument so the same
thing for the Internet if the documents and if people post their lives like if
somebody in Europe is posting about what they ate where they ate it at and you
know what what time of day that they did it that's on them that's their security
and privacy problem that they need to curb it's out there whether the EU likes
it or not and artificial intelligence other people stalkers you name it are
going to be consuming that information so you can't just you can't just be like
ooh AI spooky you know American technology that seems to be the theme of
the EU recently spooky American technology stealing our stuff I don't
know what their point is on this I mean all companies including European ones
are taking as much data as possible look I'm gonna say I've said it once the
1,000 times I'm gonna say it again if you put your information on the Internet
as a personal person of freedom with a freedom to do so it is your fault if
something happens it is not the company's fault it is not the
government's fault it is your fault you have put yourself in this situation now
you can complain about being educated on those kinds of things I don't think
it's the business's it's not the business's fault that you don't
understand perhaps lawmakers should probably fund classes for students
because we all have to go through schooling perhaps the government should
put their money into funding schools to educate children on privacy and data
privacy and tools that they can use and what to look out for these are all real
things once upon a time you would teach kids how to hold a bank account what is
a bank account what are investments you would teach them about all these things
that are part of our modern society that we have to deal with that's part of
schooling it's also part of the parents job so you know I'm leaving parents out
of this equation because we're specifically talking about people doing
legislation and legislatures and all this sort of stuff so it's not unheard
of to have these sorts of things in schools to teach children rather than
attacking other countries and attacking businesses and all this sort of stuff
because I'm a big believer in that if you attack the problem you're not
solving anything you're just causing everyone to be upset and you're just
making chaos for the reason of chaos what you need to do is find the root of
the problem where does it all come from what is the stem of it and it may be
completely unrelated to the specific problem you need to go to the root and
then solve the problem at the root that's how you solve any problem in
programming and life and legislation and anything else so it just frustrates me
that that we have these kinds of things happening and I get it I too I'm a huge
security and privacy nut I too don't want to just give my data to these
companies I don't think it's the government's job to to manhandle
companies for for this purpose and I don't think it's the company's jobs to
have a moral high ground in fact it's better for me to know that they don't so
that I am more cautious at what I do and how I control now companies should have
some sort of mechanism for me to completely wipe what I put up there from
their servers obviously all the other servers that scrape their servers and
copy it all have already cloned it out to the internet but at least I can
delete it from theirs I don't know that's as one thing but yeah there's a
big stink going on I don't know what's going on and Europe like I said I love
my credit my cousins over there in Europe all the people are amazing and
wonderful and you know it's it's got so many charms to it but the legislation is
a little goofy just as it is everywhere in the world and the US has just as
goofy and weird legislation itself so it's not special to you but this topic
on open AI is so yeah leave our leave our robots alone
letter little robots spy on people in peace would you so that's that kind of
wraps up all the the main things that I had saved for today my last couple of
days my I'm gonna be a little sporadic these next few days I'm about to have a
child can't wait I'm super excited I'm getting prepared for that it's not my
first child so it's not gonna be any surprises or anything but there are
gonna be surprises with every baby there's always a new surprise and just
being prepared make sure I got everything ready get a room ready all
that sort of stuff yeah I just you know so within the next week I should have a
new baby I hope and if so I will probably disappear for a little bit and
up till then I'm a little sporadic anyways thanks for watching and bye for
now