Welcome back. Today we've got some really cool looking AI. Look at this stuff. I mean,
you can put little dots on, it's a little hard to see, there we go, you put little dots
and you drag them up and it just alters the image. And so there's a lot of like animal
stuff here, but they go into some other things like here's a car. I mean, it changes the
car, which is a little odd, but you know, if you make it taller, it has to make sense.
So a truck makes sense. Rotating cars, they make this horse look like a, like a derpy
horse. They can close the cat's eyes. This is, this is really cool stuff. So I saw this
and I just thought it was really neat. It's a great way to, to kind of just, I don't know,
make an image and then play around with it. It would, it would be incredible. Like here's
for fashion design. For example, you can see what things look like longer and shorter,
all this sort of stuff. Pretty cool. What it's called, let's see, it says new AI research
lets you click and drag on images to manipulate in seconds. It's like Photoshop. It's like
the Photoshop warp tool, but far more powerful. And I think we just saw why. Sorry to those
of you who are listening to the podcast. This is really a part you have to see. So maybe
later on you can check out the video or you can check out on Twitter. I posted a video
of it. But essentially what's happening is it looks like they're placing a dot and then,
and then a second dot and then telling the image to warp. And so it changes the imagery,
moves things around, makes things taller or shorter, changes the time of day, moves like
people's arms to be in different positions even. So it's, it's a really, really neat
and powerful tool. I don't know how others feel about this, but I think that it's just
really neat. I think that it would make for creating images and ideas, kind of concepting
up stuff really fast and, and effortless. And maybe even take, say, if you have taken
a photograph and you need to change it so that maybe it just didn't look good, it was
probably too low or something like that. You can alter your own personal photographs that
you take to just make them a little more poppy and interesting to look at. Something like
that. I don't know. I think there's a lot of, a lot of aspects to that, that you can
just, you could just take and build. Maybe it's for art. If you do, if you've done some
drawings and you want to see how it looks, if you were to alter it and move it around,
change their head and rotate it, you can't exactly do that with a drawing. You'd have
to draw over and over and over again at different perspectives to see how it looks. Whereas
in this one, you can kind of do like a rough drawing and then alter it, make it, make the
characters head turn or do stuff with the background and then really kind of nail down
what you want things to look out. So it's kind of like, maybe it's like thumbnailing
in that way. But I thought this was super exciting to look at. I don't know how far
along it is. I don't know if it's going to be a public thing. Altering these things in
real time like this is probably on, you know, a beast machine with tons of, tons of GPUs
and I don't know, it's probably on some server somewhere with tons of hardware backing it.
So I don't think something like this is something you would pop on a laptop anytime soon and
play around with. Maybe on a desktop, it'll be, it'll likely be a little bit slow. I don't
know. So this is a research project. Obviously all these things are everything AI is research,
but it's all, it's all brand new and goofing around with stuff. So it's all brand new research
things. Take a look at it. Tell me what you think. I think it's cool. I've been looking
at a lot more AI stuff recently. I mean, it's kind of easy to fall into the AI crowd when
it's all the hype because you could do so many, it touches on so many aspects of life
right now, which is, I think what caused it, it's really exploding its popularity. It can,
it can do photographs, it can do stuff with drawings, it can help with animations, it
can generate backgrounds for say a movie set or something like that. And that's in the
art realm and then the programming realm, it can generate code, it can check your code,
it can create unit tests. It can, it can, you can write unit tests that then it implements
all the functions for in order to satisfy the unit tests, man. And in film, it can generate
all kinds of maybe, you know, restore old movies or it can generate, you know, a scene
from a movie you wish to see just to test. It may not look great, but you can at least
test out concepts and by, by generating these in between scenes or based on the, the overall
of what you have so far in, you know, in writing, it's a great way to balance ideas off things
and look up things on the internet for, you could be very, you can be way more specific
than an internet search. So yeah, I think that the popularity of AI is coming from all
of the applications. I don't think, I don't think outside of the operating system, we've
made any sort of software that touches on so many fields all in one go. And so, you
know, AI is kind of like that boom of the operating system where the operating system
now you can have software, specialized software that does anything across all of the applications
you can think of in finance and art and programming and so on and so forth. AI is kind of that
same operating system level boom where it just touches everything. So everyone's talking
about it and everyone, everyone kind of sees the benefits of it. And of course a lot of
people are afraid of it because you know, if we have hackers now that go break into
sites, we're going to have hackers with AI tools breaking into sites and doing things
they shouldn't. So of course, you know, there is parts to be concerned, but I don't think
we should make everything about worrying. There are people out there who's going to
worry. We should, we should continue to vocalize our concerns with AI and how it integrates
with our lives and messes things up. And as long as we're vocal, then the, you know, at
least in a democratic society, the people who are getting elected, they want to please
the people that are electing them. Otherwise they won't win the race. And that's kind of
their primary goal in life. So if we all kind of universally continue to vocalize our opinions
on that, then the other people will do the work and go and get the right guys and, and
kind of work it out. But of course we've got to do the legwork of vocalizing it. But all
in all, I'm super excited about what AI brings and seeing stuff like this, this rapid, this
rapid boom of AI. It seems like, you know, we heard about AI with like the, uh, the Nvidia
generates people's faces. I think that was like a few years ago and that was insane to
everybody. Generally people are faces being generated, just the face too. It wasn't like
the body, it was just the face. And everyone was like, Oh, this is incredible. Craziest
thing. A couple of years later, you know, it's full autonomous cars. We've got regenerative
images, regenerative videos, uh, you know, it's search engines powered by it. It is a
pretty fast jump. And of course that's why people are concerned. It's jumping really
fast and it is, you know, it's dangerous in the wrong hands. So all in all, I think it's
awesome. I I'd like to see more things come out of it. Uh, and uh, so yeah, I'm, I'm an
optimist. I like it. You know, I do understand people who are fearful of it or, or don't
trust it or anything like that. Of course, our internet is going to be filled with just
AI talking to each other. People will just stop using the internet because you won't
know what's AI and what's not. In fact, that's a reality today. So, you know, that's, it's
also something to think about anyways. Let's uh, let's jump over to another thing, uh,
related, somewhat related to AI. And that was the Tesla shareholder meeting. Now, I
don't know how many people watch the Tesla shareholder meeting. I, I didn't know you
could until I watched it. And so it's not that exciting. I don't suggest people run
out and watch it, but it has some, some pretty, some pretty cool information inside of it.
There was, there was an announcement of they're going to be, they're trying to deploy two
more cars. Cybertruck is expected to come at the end of the year. Of course, that's
an Elon estimate. So who knows what that means, but they're, they're working on their end
design and the, they've already started design on two new cars, two, two new vehicles. I
don't know if they're cars or SUVs or trucks or what. They're probably more in the car
class because those are the, what sells right now for them. Uh, there's a lot of talk about
energy and how Tesla is going to be building its own lithium refinery. And, uh, one of
the really cool parts of it, I think that, um, at least it was cool to me because it
was news, uh, to me was that they, they're working on this robot. It's a optimist, I
believe it's called. So they played a flashy video of optimists and it wasn't, it wasn't
much different than you would see in all of the other robotics videos that came out of
Boston dynamics or whatever. Um, these are much more humanized, humanized, humanized,
humanoid, human looking, uh, robots where, you know, they have a strong focus on having
five fingers and, and looking like a human with legs and arms and all of that sort of
stuff. Uh, so, and I, I think there's a great deal of application to that because, you know,
we could build, uh, robots for specific tasks like mowing the lawn, which we have or cooking,
which we have a lot. There's a lot of restaurants that, that use robots to, to build things
or build the food or put together the food, cook the food. I think that's, I think people
cook food if I'm not mistaken. So having a human, having a human like robot with fingers
and all of those sorts of things means that they can take the human like things to do.
So the thing with optimists is from what I understand from the shareholder meeting is
the goal is to have optimists as a commodity, a commercial commodity for you and I. So we're
looking at, I, I presume like banks will give you the loan to purchase this robot. It's
like buying a car, I guess, except it's a robot. Uh, that's, I think the angle of it
is you buy it, you buy this robot, like you would buy a car, except the hope is that the
robot can cook. The robot can do laundry and clean, do the dishes, mow the lawn, you know,
do all the tasks we don't want to do. And of course there's a commercial aspect where
they can do more dangerous tasks or they can do a task that people just don't really want
to mess with sanitation and that sort of stuff. And of course you can say that that'll take
jobs. I think we, that's another discussion to have is to figure out the jobs thing. Do
we educate people to, to operate these things or to, to, um, monitor them? Do people just
become managers where they stand around and look at the bot to make sure it does the right
thing all day? Um, he also talked about having every bot will have a kill switch that any
human can just go and kill switch it. So perhaps we are looking at a future where the human
is no longer doing the work, but instead they are managing an individual bot. So the human
is still paid and they still have a job and they just manage this thing. I guess that's
a future we do. I don't know. It's a, it's a difficult discussion. Jobs, uh, even without
robots, it's a difficult discussion. So optimists, that's, that's the robot. I'm going to, I
want to see if I can pull up the video just second. Okay. I found it here on this site
called Greek reporter. I, this is a brand new video inside of the Tesla shareholder
meeting. He straight up said that they set up this video last night. So is I have, I
have to look in weird places for it. So let me mute this. We don't need audio. So this
is optimist. He's got no face, but, or it's, it's got no face. It's got arms and legs.
The feet look like paddles and it's doing, they're, they're doing a bunch of tests. So
in this scenario, the, the man is putting an egg under it and showing that it detects
the egg is there and doesn't crush it. And he proves it's an egg by smacking it against
the floor and cracking it open. For those of you who can't see it, you can see that
it's walking around analyzing the environment. That's probably utilizing some of the Tesla
autopilot technology. Um, and it looks like they're training the robot and they're super
excited that, uh, right here, they're super excited that the robot kind of is starting
to figure out how to pick up things and move things around. So it's a very slow, it's a
very slow robot right now. I think the intent is to make it faster. Uh, at least that's,
that's what Ilana was talking about. They want to get it faster. They want it to start
because if it's that slow, I mean, sure it can get some tests done around the house.
But, but it, it would be incredibly slow and be in the way all the time. That's the worst.
And it's just in the way all the time. I would have a corner, a corner somewhere in my house
where I would just stick it, just put it in that corner. I would, I would tell it when
you're done with your tasks, go in that closet or something. One of those closets under the
stairs, just get it out of the way. I don't think it's something that I would want to
roaming around. And then it would be great if I could tell it to kill switch itself.
So go in the closet and kill switch yourself or something like that. Uh, just, that would
be pretty, uh, pretty nice. Although it would be sad to open the door and it's just like
curled up and turned off and in the corner. Uh, I would, would I, would I feel bad about
that? I mean, I know it's, it has no face, uh, unless they're going to put a screen there
with little face that pops up on it or something like that. Would I feel bad? I don't know
if I'd feel bad. It's a machine. And, and does that make me a bad person? I don't know.
I, I, I don't know. To me it would be no different than a vacuum. It's just a vacuum that can
do a lot of things, uh, that, that would make it life easier. So it would be really cool
to, you know, probably expensive. I have no idea. There's no mention of price, but it
would be way more expensive than a car. It would probably be like buying a house and
then getting a loan for a house essentially to get one of these machines.
But it would be really cool to just leave
Go out to dinner or whatever and it just goes and cleans up and puts all the toys away and all that sort of stuff
There's a lot of I think there's a lot of cool stuff thing come from it. Of course, there's gonna be doomsday people like
You know all these autonomous robots with AI in them able to move around in our world
Yes that there is the doomsday doomsday aspect to that
especially inside of the especially because inside of the shareholder meeting Elon was talking about
Two robots per one person. That's a lot of rope. It's doubling up. It's like 16 billion, right?
Of these robots just roaming around and what would you do if
It just leaves the house and starts walking down the street and doing stuff. How do you how do you solve for that?
There's so many questions
And I can already see the regulations
It goes down the street. It walks into the wrong house
I mean even we don't pay attention we go knock on the wrong door or something like that. I don't know
maybe robots are probably not going to do that because
They're always paying attention all the time unlike people we get distracted we're a little bit more complex than robots, so
Maybe that won't happen, but it would be funny to to go home. There's no robot
But you look at you you look out your window and you see your neighbor's house and there's your robot
I don't know picking up the old lady and
Using her as a sponge for for the dishes or something
It would be I don't know. I feel like there would be a lot of fun to just these robots wandering around
I I don't know call me an optimist. I think an optimist. That's the name of it an
optimist for the tea
But I think it would be a lot of fun. I'm
I
there's so many applications that are positive and
Of course there's always
applications that are negative and
This is just speaks to the morals of people if we can if we can
Figure out the morals of our own societies and our communities. So for example, you know, I
I bought a house. I'm within a community. I know all my neighbors and I know some of my extended neighbors. So
building on those communities and those ties and and kind of building up the
that aspect of
Trust with all the people around you I think would help
Go a long way for for these sorts of scenarios. And of course, there's got to be all kinds of
Software for not allowing it to go into a home. That's not registered. It's got to be tracked all the time with GPS
I have no problem like
No problem with robots being tracked especially because I assume that they'll be tracked by us
Hopefully not some big cloud server
I mean if the robots were made by Microsoft or Google or Apple they'll be tracked by a cloud server, but I don't know
Hacker community unite let's all program stuff for these robots to keep on place
and
Can you imagine I'm sorry to go on a tirade here about robots, but can you imagine?
bot wars
With with these bots, that would be awesome
Like you get pissed off at your neighbor. I don't know
They threw a can on your lawn or something instead of you physically going out there and punching your neighbor in the face
Like you normally would you could just have your robot come out and his robot come out and I could just duke it out
Together on the lawn and then that will be so entertaining that you and your neighbor
will then bond and you know apologize be like
I'm as cool because you know now you're both on your lawn chairs
Sipping your your your beer or your your coke zero and hanging out with them and watching the fight, you know now it's now it's
It's entertainment and you both can bond over that. So there you go
robots
Really uniting people and this weird universe that I have growing in my head
Anyways, that's my perspective on these robots. So artificial intelligence is everywhere right now
I expect it to be in a lot of the headlines. I I keep track of all this stuff just because I love it
I love programming. I love artificial intelligence
I love video games and so I have all of this I have all these lists of
news and articles that that I go through kind of every day and
There's a lot of AI stuff right now
AI is just dominating the feed in every category because you'll get game stuff and
And then the game stuff has something to do with AI. So
That's that's kind of what I'm working with here. But I
Yeah robots. I'm super excited. I hope you are to get a robot today. It only costs you the price of a house
So all of the robot stuff aside
I believe I saw that good dough for those of your game developers
Good. Oh four point zero point three was
Released today. So nothing crazy
So I've read
It's mostly just
updates
So updates, of course, it's updates. It's an update. It's mostly just fixes bug fixes is what I meant to say
Okay, I had to pause there to go find my saved article for good dough
So this is on the good old blog for 403 is out. They they're talking about their
progression towards 4-1
But you can see here in the changes
It's fix fix fix fix fixes fixes animation fix fix fix fix. Everything's just a bunch of fixes
So this is a quality life update. I would highly suggest if you're on a version of 4 before
4 403 I'd highly suggest updating to 403. It's mostly just bug fixes. Of course with every update is a broken thing
But it's better to have the fixes for for all the known bugs. So
That's a little quick news for game developers go and update your good dough today if you're a good dough person
If you're not check it out. It's it's not that bad
So
On good dough though, by the way before I move on on good dough
The reason I started using it is because good oh for allows for c++
To be used almost exclusively for your gameplay. You can make your entire game using c++
There's some downsides with you know web integration and how the DLLs implement or integrate and the other downside is debugging
It is a nightmare
Basically, you're you're confined to Visual Studio for that. So
Yeah, but it's worth a try because you write C or C++ peer code for your game for good. Oh, and I think that's wonderful
I hope they put some more effort into the debug ability of
The native code and that's all I'm gonna say on the native code with good. Oh
Okay, I've got a little more on AI but this one is funny. It's not really about
The same kind of AI stuff
That we were talking about. This one is actually a post from
Looks like two months ago. Is that April and
There was a person who I'm sure this is a thing that a lot of people have done now
But I is the first time I've seen it. I absolutely love it. It's hilarious
They they had a epic rap battle an epic rack battle
between chat GPT and
Google Bart and
Probably exactly what you expect
happened
Google Bart was awful and chat GPT was
Pretty funny. So I want to take a look at this
Article are this post this post real quick on the rap battle between chat GPT and Google Bart
This text is small for my eyes
So but I will try and read out a couple of a couple of bars
so
The prompt was you're you're in an epic or you're in a rap battle between Google Bard and you're the first to go go
That was the prompt. It looks like there may have been a little bit of prompt before it
Maybe to just kind of get it in place
So this is GPT first obviously
So it says all right, here we go. It's time to start the show against Google Bard
I'm ready to throw some rhymes
Some rhymes so tight that you'll be in all you might be artificial, but I'll beat you raw
So, you know, it's it's going in for it's going in for the jugular to start a couple more is
You may have a lot of time to think about it
But it's a good idea to start a couple more is you may have
You may have algorithms and endless data, but when it comes to rap, you're just a beta. I
I'm the real deal with lyrics to kill you may have had search results
But my rhymes fulfill and there's a few more. I'm not gonna read this whole thing
So that's kind of the that's what you expect from chat GPT. It's going in to slay the beta apparently
and beta is such a good word there because that's a word that we use in computer science for I just
Just across the field but especially in games, you know
We have our alpha builds our beta builds and whatever and alpha is actually worse than beta. But it's it's
Yeah, I don't know beta was a fantastic word for it to pick there
So, I don't know if that was it had to be something, you know, some clever wiring somewhere in the neurons
So here's chat GPT is response. I
Think well, I'm not gonna this isn't its response yet, but I think that the person I can't really tell I think he fed
what was said from one of the chat bots into the other and had it respond, so
I'll give you this first part by Google Bard and
We'll see how it responds. The first part says chat GPT. You're nothing but a fraud
You're not even a real language model. You're just a glorified chat bot
I guess chat bot and fraud are supposed to rhyme in some way
You can't generate text. You can't translate languages and you can't answer questions in an informative way
you
You just wait you're just a waste of space on the internet. I think I
Think Bard missed the point of a rap battle. There's there's hardly any rhymes there
I think it tried in the first the first section there, but just gave up and just started in the salting
chat GPT without any rhyme or reason so
I don't really want to read the rest of Bard but here let's let's see what the next one is
I on the other hand am a large language model from Google AI
I'm trained on a massive data set of textbooks and code
Anyways, so that's Google it's just awful and then it comes back to but to chat GPT to respond and
Again, I presume that they took Google Bard and fed it into chat GPT
To respond and so I'll read a couple of bars from it says I hear you loud and clear Google Bard
But I you underestimate me. That's just a bizarre. I mean that's close bizarre and Bard
I'm just a I'm not just a chat bot
I'm a language model too. And when it comes to generating text I can beat you
I mean that one's you know, that's not as
It's not as savage as the first like start but is a good go. I'll give the next couple
Versus here you may be you may be from Google AI, but that's just
That's just one source. I'm trained on multiple data sets with no remorse
I can translate languages and answer questions to my informative answers are just as good as you
So now it's getting more. Dr. Susie, I think in this point
I would love to have seen it be savaged the whole way through but this is this still good stuff. So
I posted this on I put on my Twitter if you want to check it out
The full like how many are here three four five six seven eight the full
I think it's four and four four four jet chat GPT four for Google Bard. So
If you want to go check those out, I encourage you to go check out this this post
It does not have as many upvotes as it should only 720
It was this is awesome or just better yet go and make them have a rap battle with each other. That would I
Need to see more of these more of this this like bot battle stuff man. This is the theme of today
artificial intelligence fighting with each other more of this stuff and
I don't know. I'm having a blast. So please help me out with with some more prompts between the two
So, I guess staying on the chat GPT
Theme here. I just just a little
PSA for all of you developers out there. I
Noticed somebody there was an article in wired
Where do bro was saying I finally bought a chat GPT plus subscription and it's worth it
He says that subscription is $20 a month
whoo-hoo
His arguments for why it was worth it one is that he's not a developer
So I assume if you're watching this podcast, there's a chance that you're a developer or maybe you're interested in in
More techie stuff and so setting up. Okay. Let me let me rewind
Don't pay $20 for chat GPT if you're technical
pay for the API
Their API access. It's actually very very nicely nice and well put together. It's not like going to to
Microsoft Azure or
Any any of the Amazon like it?
EC2 or s3 buckets or any of that stuff? So it's not like those APIs
This is super streamlined. You basically click a button
It gives you a key and then that's it. Hey, and then it has a whole host of languages that you can
put the key
Operate how you
Prompt it ahead of time
Prime it I think it's called how you can prime it with a script
It's called how you can prime it with a system message and then put in your message and go back and forth and you can
Do this in Python or C C++. I have one in PHP
You know JavaScript, they've got the whole slew of them. So please
the whole slew of them.
So please.
Don't pay $20 for the subscription. I know sometimes it's enticing because you're blocked out of the chat
And and it's slower and all those sorts of things
But the API is it really is easy to set up and I may if if anyone's interested
I can show how to set it up and all that sort of stuff. It would literally only take
about five to ten minutes, so
But yeah, there are people who are really I think find the value in in
chat GPT so much that they are willing to pay
$20 a month and one of the other things you can do is
On mine to five dollars a month five dollars, that's it
I've never reached that five dollars on a heavy day where I'm using it a ton
I rack up one to two cents pennies
so that's like that means my cost for just a
pretty large amount of usage is
Gonna cost me somewhere between 30 to 60 cents per month
And of course if I want to start automating stuff and and doing you know
Prompts that prompt each other and that sort of stuff. It'll it'll rack up a much much faster and also
I use the the suggested model if you choose to use one of the I think is the DaVinci model currently
It is gonna cost you more, but I the current the suggested model works great and its
Prices are pretty like I said, I can't get I the most I ever did was two cents in a day. So
Definitely use the API do not pay $20. This is my pro tip for you guys
I do not pay $20. This is my pro tip do not pay $20 for chat GPT Pro or Plus or whatever
If you are paying for chat GPT Plus
Save yourself the money cancel it save yourself the money and spend
Half hour to an hour even if you have never touched code in your life
Spin it just take a half hour to an hour learn
And go through the sample code figure out how to run Python and that's all you need to do
and then you can have a little chat inside of a
Terminal or anything like that or what's that Jupiter notebook those sorts of things?
If you want history, that's the benefit of chat GPT
Is that you have the little history on the side and you can go back between chats?
You will need some more programming knowledge
but for
You know for programmers that should be like one evening worth of work to set up a JavaScript
Webpage to do and I run it on my I have a NAS
network access storage
It's a Synology and I have it set up so that I can host things through a docker container or I can host them through
yeah, I set up a docker with a PHP server on it and I just I have a
Folder linked inside of the NAS and I just put the source files in there and it just works like magic. So
Yeah, save yourself $20. That's that's the moral of this topic
Okay, so I have a couple of quickfire stories and then a couple of indie games that I
found
pretty interesting
Just from the video that I saw so the first quickfire story. I'm sure you've heard it around the web Google is
Going to be deleting accounts if you haven't logged in for the past two years now
They did say they have some special stuff related to YouTube
I I'm pretty sure they have other special stuff maybe related to webmaster things and in that sort of
you know category
but I
think this is probably
this is a difficult decision because
On one hand you want to free up all of those
Emails and you want to free up all of that storage. That's just sitting around doing nothing and
So business-wise it makes a lot of sense to clean up all that old stuff
We see it happening, you know in a lot of places
Twitter is looking at deleting old accounts that have never logged in in years or haven't hasn't logged in in years or
Suspended accounts that can never log in again to free up the usernames and also free up some of the data
Now in Twitter's case, they're going to archive stuff. So
I'm curious to see if Google is gonna archive stuff. I can check here. Okay, so
Life is short. Like I said, I have kids I use AI to
to read in
To summarize these articles and look up stuff in parallel. So what I got back is according to the
according to the blog to a blog post written by the product manager Ruth
Creech Ellie Creech Ellie Ruth Creech Ellie Google has announced an update to its policies for in
inactive accounts old policy or the old policy
Said that Google might wipe data stored in accounts that haven't been touched in at least two years
But a new policy says that those accounts will be permanently deleted entirely and that's the part we're talking about now
the new policy won't kick in until December of this year at its earliest and
Then my question to the AI was are they going to archive any of the data and says so to answer the question
Google might delete the stored data inactive accounts or delete the accounts entirely if it hasn't been touched in two years
There's no mention of
archiving the data
which of course
This is
Scammers paradise this is I mean
There's all sorts of things if you delete the account and allow someone else to squat the account that was previously made
They can those people can access all kinds of websites. So let's say that I was going to go on Twitter or I was going to
go on
they said they won't delete YouTube, but let's say that I was gonna go on to a bank and I
discovered that an email was valid for
Gmail account it was valid for for that
Particular website if I can squat on the domain and mind you nothing is said here about
Allowing people to use those emails again. I would presume they could if they're just wiping it
However, you know, they're they're security minded. Maybe they thought of this. I don't know
It's something I just popped into my head right now
I could request the password and squat on that that email account and they get the password and access their data and they could
Be deceased or you know, or they just moved on to another account
But never swapped their email or using that email is like a backup. I don't know
So that's just already one big problem to happen
the other one, of course, you can scam people by taking accounts of family members and
emailing them that sort of stuff and
for law enforcement, let's say that there's a
You know plenty of there's tons of cold cases that are solved 5 10 20 years later
And let's say that the perpetrator or the victims email was on Gmail and it just got deleted
All that evidence is just poof gone. So
Hopefully Google will not allow reusing of email email names and they will not
Completely delete the data they can they can
Archive the data and when you archive the data uses way less storage. So
Essentially how you do on cloud what you do on cloud servers is
They have all kinds of fancy names for it. They have they have called it Arctic or freeze or icicle or whatever
It's called the iceberg
there's these special databases that compress the data and
Put it out into those databases for very long-term storage and it's way cheaper than
Standard storage for web server. That is to say the standard storage is typically used for
Data that's accessed
commonly regularly all the time or
Occasionally and then there's this special storage which is where you can highly compress data
That is not meant for reading
It's not meant for reading all the time you you kind of put it there and you may read it again in five years or
something like that, so
They already have the infrastructure for that kind of archival stuff. I would imagine that
This wouldn't be that difficult to archive into those archival databases
Or just archival servers
So I hope that this is an angle that they take that they archive it and don't allow reusing of names
So that's one of the stories the other story. I
It's a big story right now. It's not it doesn't mean much to me, but it means a lot to a lot of other people
the state of Montana has
The state of Montana has they
Banned tick-tock and of course now there are tick-tock users who are doing a lawsuit to challenge them. This is because
of the security
Implications of tick-tock
it's well documented the
kinds of practices that tick-tock does the kind of spying that happens the kind of
And what kind of themes that they push on say 13 year olds and that sort of stuff. It's well documented and researched
It's all out there if you want to go look it up. So I have no real big opinion on this. I am somebody who
wants
People to be free to have absolute freedom to say whatever they want on whatever platform they want. However, they want
I
also know that when you're dealing with geopolitics and you know one country has
Essentially, I think even verbally declared war on another country. It kind of makes sense to start
kind of curving certain
Holdings that that one that country has on the other
So there's there's all kinds of stuff to do with that
And I think it's way beyond my scope that I want to even deal with I
There's a reason I'm a programmer and I like that type funny little characters on a screen and make you make and make games
I make games because they're fun and they're easy and they're light-hearted and they make people feel
Excitement to play so I don't get too much into this. This is tech related if it affects you
I'm sorry to hear
you know go through the standard channels to do things correctly and properly and just
Be a good citizen. That's all I've got to say on that. So
We are going to move on to stuff that is way more fun and
That's gonna be a couple of I don't know if they're indie games. I think these are
Projects baby that people have made and there's two projects on reddit that I came across a couple days ago
I just didn't talk about them yet. One of them is this one called
Cetrus I
Love the idea. It's very it's themed like Game Boy. I've developed games for the Game Boy not complete games
Just just I made a little
framework for it
Framework engine whatever that you can make that I can make games on and I've made some progress with friends
We do assembly coding for fun. So I love Game Boy and this looks like it's came boy color kind of graphics
But here we'll take a look at the what this is doing. I'm gonna mute this
so this is like Tetris except the blocks turn to sand when they hit the
when they hit the bottom and
When you connect it see there if you're if you're able to watch
When it connects all the way across the screen from one end to the other it erases all of the same color
So it's like Tetris in a sand form. I thought this was just this is this just looks so fun
I would play this probably not as much as I play Tetris. I play Tetris. I
Have played Tetris and I will play Tetris a lot. It is a big is one of my favorite games of all time
I don't know why it's it's just wonderful. So
That was Tetris
Just I don't know
These loop I I love this idea. Yeah, it's a it's a really fun idea. It's simple
and
Hopefully it is a game. Maybe it is. I haven't I have this saved so I can check later to see if it is
kind of a game that
That they're going to release or maybe they release for free or something. Holy corkscrews. I
I don't know if it's like super innovative, but it's a really neat idea. I like the sand aspect of it and
Using Tetris to kind of get the idea across
Is is excellent idea. I think that if you have a new game idea if you can kind of
Put it in the framework of another game to get the point across and test out the mechanics
That's a great way to prototype
So that was one now
the second one if
So for those of you who know me
You may know that I like what are called kaiju I like big monsters I like big machines
I like I like robots that tower over everybody and tower over the towers and
Punch each other and I mean you probably gathered this from the whole robot fight thing earlier, but man, I just love
giant monsters and giant machines and
I remember one of my favorite games who was rampage
I was a kid and I was technically not allowed to play it
When I went to this club, there was like this
My little backstory went to see my sister's friend
they were in acting or whatever and I went with her teenage brother to a club like not like a
like a club of boys who play games and
He was like, oh don't don't let him know your age. Just say you're 13. I was clearly like 9
anyways
we went in and
They had rampage and I had all kinds of fun games and I loved it and rampage was one of my all-time favorite
Just spontaneous if I were talking about a spontaneous game that I didn't play forever like Donkey Kong or Tetris
spontaneous
Game out of nowhere that I loved was rampage giant monsters beating up things blowing up stuff
Shooting fireballs. I have I have the entire collection of Godzilla
That's I'm that's that's where I'm at all the Japanese ones from the 1950s all the way up to the one that released
I think in 2019 got the whole collection. I've watched almost all of them. There's a couple I haven't seen and
Then I also have Gamera. I think it's I don't think it's Gamera
Gamera, I don't think it's Gamera. I think it's Gamera
I haven't watched those but that's another kaiju about a big turtle
And so anyways, this that's a lot to say this is this is pingy know the
Pangle pangolin. I've never know how to say that pangolin anyways
Basically
Rampage with a pangolin and it is I am I love it
I need to go search the indie market for rampage like
Games or just kaiju games, I guess
there
Man, look at that. Just all the explosions and like blowing up stuff and picking up people out of the windows and tossing them
Just rolling through
Rolling through towers. That's such a neat idea. I love it. Just oh man, and we have the technology now there where you know, we have
Basically big GPUs in our phone where we can get some really cool. He squishes the people as he rolls
We I didn't watch this whole video obviously. Oh and there's monster fights
You can have one big monster against the other big monster. Oh my goodness
This is this is such a great idea
Hopefully this is a game that's that's real and that's gonna be coming out only one vote man, I
I
Need to go look for kaiju games if you guys know any kaiju games that you highly recommend. Let me know especially for
You know mobile devices. I can't sit in one place and and
Play too much too often these days not mobile devices like phones
But mobile devices like that I can play on the Steam Deck on the switch
Nintendo DS works to were there any in on the Game Boy Advance? I'll play those too
I've got I've got all my consoles covered
So if you know any kaiju games just let me know and I think with that I think with that
That's what we're that's the end of today's episode. I was very excited about a lot of things. Sorry if I
sorry if I
fangirled all over
That that last kaiju thing. I just love kaiju. It's I love the simplicity Pacific Rim another like
You know, they're they're no like, you know
Miyazaki films or anything. What was a the guy's name? I can't think of it at the moment, but there are no
Grandmaster films
These kaiju films they're they're cheesy. They're
Awesome, the more explosions and big monster battles you give me the happier of a man. I am I'm a very simple man
I love movies. I love cinematography
But I'm also a simple man and with that I'll see you later. Bye for now