Hello and welcome back. This is gonna be I guess episode 2. Well I started zero for
indexing right so this will be episode 1. Welcome to episode 1 of the
podcast. I just saw recently that there was kind of an uptick in people who
are streaming and they hit alt tab or they have they just have things on their
screen that they shouldn't have. You know everything from like home addresses,
web searches, adult videos, the websites, you know and that sort of stuff. Just a
lot of personal information that is just going out there and it's kind of a
it's kind of a problem you know with people streaming a lot and exposing all
this stuff and there's a lot of easy ways to combat these problems especially
on Windows. Windows has a lot of tools for you to not fall prey to this to this
I don't know what to call it these self-destructive problems. It could be
out of laziness or whatever else but I have some some thoughts on how to solve
that and just some things people can do when they're streaming and it's not even
just streaming there's a lot of people who record videos. I've watched people
who record videos and they think the the animations and the things moving around
is fast enough to not worry about people seeing their address you know on a maps
location or seeing their private messages with their with their wife in
this case that I'm thinking of wife or husband or whoever else. So there's
there's very easy things you can do whenever you're recording whenever you're
streaming on Windows that'll solve this. So I'm going to start off with talking
about those things just some tools that you can use to to not fall prey to that
and then the second part I'm going to talk a little bit about programming
mainly about optimizing and making your code a bit faster and just things to
think about I guess. So staying private while you're streaming one of the most
common things that people do is the alt tab and alt tab is nice it allows you
get through things really quickly. Let me suggest to you alt escape let's say that
you have two windows you can put the window that you want to kind of look at
on the screen behind the game and put your other stuff on the other monitor
and you use alt escape to go to the background window and then come back to
foreground so it's kind of like going through them in that way it just allows
you to simply switch between it basically sends the current program to
the back of the stack and the next one shows up so if there's only two you're
just gonna be swapping between the two. So that's just a quick alternative if
you're kind of wanting that that velocity of alt tab but of course we
have lots of tabs we want to tab through them and we want to find the one that
we're interested in. So the next thing that you'd want to do is virtual
desktops. Not many people I've seen through their streams or anything like
that use virtual desktops they kind of just stick everything about them up on
their primary window. So I like to use virtual desktops to separate out this
stuff and the great thing about virtual desktops is that you can shut down your
computer you can restart your computer and it'll come back up and you'll still
have your virtual desktop so you don't have to reset them up. In fact here's a
example of what it looks like we have I have a primary desktop here and I got a
podcast desktop here you can guess which one I'm using right now. So the primary
one is gonna have you know chats and that sort of stuff on it and then the
podcast one is gonna have podcast related things. The great thing about
this is when you alt tab you're presented with just the programs that
are running on that desktop so in this way you don't have to do much you can
just set up these you can even give them a name as you saw just right click it
hit rename there you go. Another problem that people have is browser tabs lots of
lots of browser tabs also when you type in the browser it shows history of your
searches I don't want to know what kind of weird things you search for but I am
only human so when I see that pop up a little nagging part of the back my brain
is like what's in there what are they what are they interested in not in a
nefarious way but you know people you like to watch they have some information
on things you wonder where they're getting it from so it's very tempting
for a lot of people. People are curious by nature and they're going to wind up
looking through that stuff that pops up especially if you have tabs search
history all that sort of stuff. So how do we solve this if you're a gamer you can
use the Steam browser I think you press shift tab and that'll open up the the
Steam overlay and you hit web browser and you can search on stuff in there and
that's a kind of an easier way for people that don't want to hold tab out
or anything like that. The other one is to use browser sessions this is something
I use quite often as you can see I have a few sessions here so when you're in
your browser there's a little icon in the top right and you click on it and
create you'll basically get this window with the sessions so you see I have my
personal one I have one that is explicitly for Google things only I have
one that's for the podcast I have one for Japanese stuff so you can guess that
I'll be using podcast one whenever I'm going through this and so the podcast
they have their separate histories they have their separate logins and you know
data and plugins and everything else so separate out your separate
separate out your browser stuff don't don't go streaming with your main
browser and you know bank tabs open and all that sort of stuff so yeah it's very
easy just set these up and you can you can decorate them you just hit the add
button you can add as many as you want very simple so that's kind of how you
can separate your browser how you separate your desktops one of the
problems that you'll have with even if you separate out your desktops is you're
gonna have your file system if you are a programmer and you're doing a programming
video or a dev log or whatever you're gonna show your file system so it's just
inevitable you have a file window open or you know you'll have files that you
have to load up or something like that so if you want to show off that stuff I
think we all use git we all use you know subversion I guess or perforce or you
know all the different kinds of repositories so we can clone that stuff
over to a separate user account it's very easy to create a separate user
account I create one for family members I create them for just random stuff I
want to lock myself out from or if I want to sandbox and like test around
with things but you can create a user and then do all your videos and your
streaming in that user you know if you're a big game streamer you just
create a this is my game streaming account and you set up a user and it has
its own file system and you can lock it out of access from your main file system
so in that way you can prevent showing off your files whatever files you may
have you know court subpoenas or whatever yeah they they'll now be kind
of hidden away especially if you use the preview I sometimes use preview instead
of Explorer and you know you accidentally click on something it'll
show you preview on the right and you don't want that going up on your stream
or you know up in your video and you didn't notice so creating a user account
super easy you just go into your settings you look for accounts and
there's other user accounts right here you just click add account very easy I
don't think you have to have a Microsoft account for this for these you can add
it as a family member I don't know just add an account and it's very simple and
that'll make it so that you can separate out your file system and this will also
make it so that you don't need virtual desktops or have to make different
browser stuff so this is just another vector of attack for hiding you know not
hiding but you know not not displaying your goods to the world there's a lot of
important stuff on our computers and we have a lot of computers with a lot of
stuff strung around that we don't even notice especially when we're clicking
around real fast and a lot of people when they edit their videos they'll just
load up their video and they'll skip ahead and you'll just miss those flashes
of frames that pop up with sensitive information so please use user accounts
if you need to protect your file system and those sort of things so another kind
of thing that you can do is Windows Sandbox unfortunately you need to have
Windows Pro your BIOS has to allow for virtualization you need to have it on in
your BIOS and I think you need to have Hyper-V set up so there's a lot of
prerequisites to this and it may cost money if you don't have Windows
Pro so this is kind of for the other people that have Windows Pro and all
the virtualization enabled in this one it's very simple you have apps and
features just search features it'll show up apps and features here and then
you'll have a list of features I suggest you turn on Windows subsystem for Linux
as well if you're a developer and if you're watching this you probably are so
turn that guy on if you don't already anyways Windows Sandbox is right there
you turn that on restart your computer you'll be good to go and I guess I can I
can show sandbox another problem I had with sandbox is once I installed it I
could type in sandbox and it doesn't show up in all my apps so I actually
have to go and go to all apps and then scroll all the way down to the W I'm
actually gonna pin it pin to start you'll find in there just pin it or open
it from from that and that will open up this Windows Sandbox and you'll see that
it's just a regular old Windows looking instance I think I can scale this down
so that it'll fit on the screen here there we go so you'll see it looks like
a regular Windows instance you can set up a configuration file so that this can
have access to certain folders when it launches which is nice you can make it
run programs at startup which is also nice if you want to install stuff that
sort of thing and then of course you can copy and paste from your primary desktop
over into here so you can kind of set up your Windows Sandbox to present
something or anything like that and this is a nice way to not have to make a user
and also it's a nice way to clean out stuff if it's temporary and you're just
showing off something and you don't want to keep all those files and it's it's
just a waste of space and you don't have to clean them up yourself using the
Windows Sandbox is cool because it destroys everything that's in its
session of course it doesn't destroy the linked folders but if you put files and
stuff in here on the desktop or in its own file system that's not the linked
folders it will destroy them which is great especially if you're let's say
that you're showing off something in your program and it installs or whenever
you build it it makes like a makes like 30 gigs of files of assets or something
it's really nice to have it in a sandbox so you just close it and not worry about
it it's just gone once you hit that X you'll see you sure you want to kill
sandbox yeah
and for you if you're not interested in having people see all of your goods now
I kind of did want to show what happens what people do instead of YouTube if you
don't know this you know other web players have this and you probably do
know this I'm sure a lot of developers know this but you can actually play
frame-by-frame on a video so let's let's just let's just open up a video I have
here and you'll see that I have it paused here and if I use the period key
or the comma so the period a little forward a frame and the comma will go
back a frame so I can press period period period so you can see I go
frame-by-frame and view what's going on now I didn't want to bring up anybody's
any of the particular videos that I've seen and I've seen a lot of them where
you could just tell from one frame you can see the file system is exposed the
browser tabs are shown all sorts of stuff is shown in one frame and they
don't even notice it you very easily press pause and then just use the period
and comma to go frame by frame to view this sensitive information and there are
channels that are dedicated not dedicated there are channels that are
kind of like reaction channels and they will very often use this this
frame-by-frame feature to look at stuff in the background and comment on it or
you know look at what's going on you know and their tabs and all this other
stuff and they'll just comment on it as part of their gimmick so it's not just
you know malicious actors who know how to do it there's a lot of YouTube
channels that just promote this this frame swapping which is fine it's a
fantastic feature like I've I've used it for animations when I watch some really
cool animations online and I want to see how they they did the tweening or
something like that I can use the the comma and the period to go back and
forth the frame to kind of see how they they did the tweening and it's really
nice it's a really nice feature honestly it's just in the wrong hands and with
experienced video creators you'll find that they you know malicious people view
it or as though you know it's maybe they're not malicious but it's just
information they shouldn't know and shouldn't have in their head it's
information for your head so that's kind of my perspective on on all of that sort
of stuff now there is one more thing that you need to be aware of and this
one is a lot has caught a lot more in people's videos but sometimes they're
not and that's notifications so you'll get notifications on phones and you'll
get notifications on in on Windows so if it's on the phone it's a little bit more
difficult but if the phones on the desk and the cameras pointed in such a way
that they can see it it'll be very easy to kind of see you see information there
maybe it's hard because in the background is blurry but still you
should just put on is it busy or you know yeah I think it's like busy on your
phone where you it doesn't present any notifications turn that guy on if your
phone is gonna be in the video or if you're reviewing phones or anything like
that just if it's on the screen on a table in the back a lot of people have
tables on the side or they put their phones and yeah it's it's not the
greatest so just turn on busy or put it face down either one works and on
Windows you can use quiet hours and it is important that you click it twice or
quite time I don't always called is port you click it twice to alarms only
because there is one that shows important notifications which may be
work or emails or things like that so it's pretty easy you just hit on the
down here where the little speaker thing is and the this is from a laptop so the
little battery and the Ethernet just click on that and you click on this moon
icon twice if it's not there then just hit this little pencil and add it hit it
twice go to alarms only you're not gonna get any notifications a lot of this may
be redundant for people but I've seen a lot of technical people don't follow
these and it's just information that people shouldn't see so that's my rant
on that that bothered me a lot recently it's happened way too many times and I
also have a friend he's he's goofy anytime I put up a video and I'd like
alt-tab that I'm just sending him for you know I trust him and all that you
know he'll send me a screenshot be like what's that that sort of stuff and it's
like a single frame so it's it's just part of human nature to be very curious
on what's on people's computers and desktops what's in there it's kind of
like you know there's a back room and the door is cracked slightly open pretty
much everybody yeah who's who's not boring is gonna be you know trying to
see creep over there and kind of peek or maybe even just ask her outright so yeah
it's just something I thought needed a PSA but hopefully you follow all those
so now I'm gonna talk about programming so part two I guess this is I don't know
what to call it I think we'll call it it's very it's not groundbreaking but
I'll call it grapevine coding it's where you hear something about how to program
and you kind of take it as law of programming so programming back in the
past may have been closer to that where there are paradigms that you can tell
each other and they would be pretty reliable at being fast efficient saving
size all those sorts of things and those paradigms first of all we're still using
ones from three years ago three decades you'll still run into programmers who
ask you know about these very old problems and that no longer exist so you
kind of hear it on the grapevine and you you base your code and and and how you
design your code on it which is even worse so one of the first things I want
to mention is premature optimization we've all heard it we've all had leads
we've all had friends who have said it preemus premature optimization is the
root of all evil and they're quoting some guys from you know 60 years ago or
so and they're guys I respect like Donald Knuth is it Knuth? Donald Knuth? I
don't know I have his art of coding series it's like a big stack of books he
kind of repeated it and one thing we need to realize is that quote was from
the time of assembly and if anybody's programmed in assembly you know exactly
what I'm talking about and you know exactly what they're talking about when
they say premature optimization is the root of all evil because in assembly it's
as programmers we can count the clock cycles and we can think oh man I if I
can shave off a clock cycle here and a clock here you know I could do a cool
effect or something or I can add I can have extra performance and those were
very dangerous because you would design pretty pretty ridiculous code the code
would be completely unreadable even with comments for assembly code and it's just
awful to work in a team where parts of code you just don't understand
especially if they're using some kind of hack or anything like that so it's that's
kind of the root of it now that's propagated itself into modern era and in
the modern era people use it for high-level languages now of course over
optimization some early over optimization is not helpful on a team
but you should always think about optimization as you're designing the
code as part of your design not over optimization not ever you can't even
really you can't even count clock cycles in a high-level language but you can
think about how things are going to interact how slow they're going to be
and so you really don't want to get that premature optimization is a root of all
evil as like a base you want to work from in any project that is that is not
good advice for high-level languages now the reason I say that is because
high-level languages are much more easy to become spaghetti code you start
adding a bunch of libraries your classes become super intertwined and is just
almost impossible to undo things once they've get way too set in stone
especially on a project where there's timelines involved and you've got
project managers you're not going to get time to go back and rip out that whole
thing to redo it so you do need to optimize those things up front and you
need to think about the optimization you don't want to over optimize it it
shouldn't be something that supports every test case scenario it should be
something that supports the desired scenario and maybe design in a way that
can extend it at minimal effort something like the visitor pattern is a
great pattern for that sort of thing where the business logic comes into the
system and it works off of that and you can swap out the business logic very
easily so you do want to optimize ahead of time and that does want that should
be something in the back of your mind you shouldn't just hack things in to get
them going get them going quick you will regret it and it will waste a lot of
your time and a lot of everybody else's time who has to use it and just to kind
of show where I got this from this is actually a pretty nice book so let me
set up my overhead camera here so we can look at it first of all it's from this
book I like no scratch press this is a nice book thinking low-level writing
high-level it's it's a kind of a thick book I have their x86 assembly x64
assembly and a couple others of their books because they're they're nice I
don't read books from start to finish so at programming books I don't read
programming books from start to finish so that's definitely kind of one thing
to keep in mind
Just a moment, I've got to set up this overhead camera. Let's see. Okay, pretty sure I got
it set up here. Let me move my keyboard out of the way. Thinking low-level, writing high-level.
I just want to show you kind of where I got this. I've kind of always thought this, but
it was put nicely into words in this book here. Let's see if we can't get a little bit
of a zoom. There we go. So it actually talks about this here. Let's see. Although it's
often attributed to Donald Knuth, who popularized it, Tony Hoare, another fantastic computer
scientist, who said, premature optimization is the root of all evil. This has been a rallying
cry of software engineers for application performance until the very end of time. However,
it did not say concern with application performance during the early stages of application development
is the root of all evil. And that's kind of the important part there. It was in a time
of counting clock cycles. If you've done assembly programming, like I said, it's very tempting
to count clock cycles. And I've done that quite a few times, and it's always bit me
in the butt. And the people I code with on that, they regretted it. They were upset at
me. So that's the book. I highly recommend it. I wouldn't go, I don't know how much this
book was. It was kind of expensive. It's like $50. I don't know what it is now. But maybe
if you can pick up a used copy, thumb through it, it's a pretty nice book. I like the no
scratch press books. They're pretty sweet. So I'll put that back down here. So that's
my long-winded part of premature optimizations. And I agree with the book. So let me turn
off this phone. Okay. So that's part one, premature optimizations. So now that we've
said that part, I'm going to counter that a little bit. That isn't a free pass to over-optimize
all the time. Here's another example of programming and doing premature optimizations. So this
is an example of something I did in my C library for my game engine. I was doing UTF-8 strings.
And in those strings, I kind of put it, I knew I could go online and check out how other
people have dealt with getting the length of the strings and all that sort of stuff
and validating the strings. And I went online and I saw that, oh, it has tons of if statements.
It has like four if statements just inside of a loop to determine if the UTF-8 string,
to figure out its length, how many characters are in it. And for me, I was like, well, branching
is not very good. All that branching is going to cost you in the long run. So I set up for
myself a solution to the problem. Okay. I had to set up my web pages there. But I set
up what I thought was a solution to the problem, I should say. And it was not, it did work.
It was indeed faster. So this is my website. I had a little UTF-8 thing here. And you can
see that I don't use any if statements. It's all just shifting logic and multiplication
and addition, which can vectorize. It's not vectorized here because I'm not going to assume
people are going to turn on vectorization. But here it's set up and then I have a validation
function below that. So when I go to, when I went to run it, you'll see that it did go
faster. It was 1.4 times faster than the internet common, or my previous attempt, I should say.
And I do have the internet common one somewhere as well. Let me double check here. Okay. Unfortunately,
I don't have the previous one. I do have one that I worked on a little bit. It did have
a couple of if statements in it. This was like my first attempt at messing with it.
And that one was 1.6 times faster than the, I guess it's five cases in the common internet
one. So you can see that I can, I got faster than even one that was faster than that. 1.4
times faster than that. Now, one of the problems I had was as the string scaled and it repeated
itself, the internet common one, which is the one with all of the if statements, wound
up being faster than my implementation without any if statements inside of the loop. And
that's very, you know, surprising for anyone that, you know, talks about branching being
very slow. Now I could try and run it. I do have the updated version here. But my problem
is that the benchmarking software or website that I'm using here stopped working today,
I think. So let's try to run it. I'm just going to paste it in here and then let's use
cling 14. That's the one I used for my C++ engine. I'm going to run the benchmark. I'm
not going to make you wait for this. I'm going to pause and see if it breaks. Okay. Yep,
it's still broken. But you can take my word on it. When it was a short string or a string
of random characters, I would see that my implementation was a little bit faster or
quite a bit faster depending on the scenario. But when it was a really long string of repeating
characters, the one with many if else branches wouldn't work. And this isn't even the right
one. It's supposed to be this one. Anyways, it doesn't matter. It doesn't work anyways.
So there goes against the conventional logic. Of course, the reasoning for this is that
whenever it's a repeating string, the CPU, and this is modern CPU, I'm assuming, that
is running on these cloud servers that this is hosted on, it detected the pattern and
it did the branch selection much more efficiently. The other alternative is that the compiler
saw the pattern. And since it's a very common pattern for UTF-8, the compiler optimized
the code to a better performing UTF-8 function in assembly code. And so the compiler is kind
of in the way there. Or useful? Useful in my way for my test, but useful overall.
So essentially that's one of the things about tribal knowledge. The tribal knowledge of
this will go faster if you remove the branches is not always true. So you don't want to just
remove if statements to make it faster. Now, I do use my version of UTF-8 because it's
better in most scenarios and it looks nicer to me. I think it looks pretty. It's better
in a bunch of if-else cases. But that kind of shows you that you really do need to test
on your hardware. There's nothing beyond testing on your target hardware.
Now I've talked a lot about kind of just general things of optimization early. Over-optimizing
doesn't always work. But now I want to talk about ways that you can improve your code
on any system that either has these features or some features they have to have, like memory
stuff. But these are surefire ways to improve the performance of your code. They are, you
know, kind of like magic bullets. Basically, it's hard to go wrong with them unless you
really don't know what you're doing. The first one is turn on the MMX or AVX or SIMD or for
Android turn on NEON with flags like in Clang I think on Linux it's minus M-A-V-X. On Windows
you can set it in Visual Studio. But turn those on and the compiler itself is going
to vectorize. And vectorization, if you don't know what it is, SIMD stands for simultaneous
instruction, multiple data. Essentially, you can provide lots of numbers and it can run,
say, an ADD instruction in one of, it's not a single clock cycle, but in one of its virtual
clocks for that. And so it will run in one instruction. So, you're not always going to
know exactly what to do. It will try to vectorize where it can. It'll do it pretty efficiently
in the standard libraries. So you will get some magic performance even if it's a little
bit out of turning on vectorization. You can code vectorization yourself and it's not that
difficult. The part that's annoying is that Android NEON uses something different than
the standard AVX, MMX stuff. So you do have to if else case some of those things. The
other problem is that on desktops you have access to doubles, larger, like a 256 byte
vector. Whereas in Android NEON, I think you're limited to 128 byte vector. So you can't use
like doubles, I mean you can do doubles, but you can't do, say, four doubles all together.
You can do two, which is basically four floats. So there are some gotchas on that, depending
on your platform. So it is a little annoying to support both. But you can write your code
for this. And I wrote my own math library for my game engine. So all the vector math
and all the matrix math, the whole shebang, I wrote by hand in C. And I used SIMD instructions
to make it faster on desktop and make it faster on Android. Any CPUs that support those simultaneous
instructions. So that's one way that you can, it's like a little magic bullet sometimes.
You won't see much performance at all. And other times you can get some pretty big performance
based on what you're doing. The other kind of magic bullet for making things faster is
caching a lot of stuff. So of course, access to memory is slow, but caching things that
are complicated or big structures, you know, if you're reading a file from a disk, whether
it's binary or text, you've got to go read the file, do some stuff with it, read the
file again later on. I don't know when, how often you do this. But if you were to load
that into memory and just hold it in memory, just hold more in memory and not have to access
it from the network or from file systems or, you know, kind of just those just elsewhere,
you will gain performance. And of course, don't overdo it. Don't put your, I mean, we
do that now. I think Unreal does that. It loads basically everything you need or as
much as possible onto the GPU in this case, so that it can access it really quick.
It is a very common practice to load up your memory with stuff you're going to use. That
can go for shaders, it can go for GPU stuff, it can go for CPU if you're just processing
data. Loading up that stuff into memory, caching things. In fact, one of the things, one of
the software that you'll use in web is called Memcached or Memcached, I don't know how to
say it, I'm pretty sure it's Memcached, where you can save things in a local cache or even,
not even a local cache, it could be a remote cache, but it's all in memory, so it's much
faster than a remote database and reading from the database, which reads from file system,
even with SSDs. So, caching stuff in memory, kind of a magic bullet if you do it right.
Checking your memory alignment. Some platforms like Raspberry Pi 3 will actually crash if
you don't align your memory. So, some platforms force you to do this. But Intel, for the longest
time, does not force you to align your memory. And aligning your memory properly will improve
your performance, not significantly, but it is a nice performance boost. Reading data
into structures, writing data, holding data, transferring data between multiple objects
or cloning your data, it's going to be much faster, not much faster, it's going to be
faster if you align your data properly. So, I think compilers have the option to align
the memory for you, but it's not that hard to put an alignment in your structure. In
fact, if you're using like Vulkan or Raspberry Pi 3, you do have to align your data structures
to use it. So, in Vulkan, whenever you're setting up all your structures that interact
with the Vulkan API, you align that data, because when it goes through the GPU, it expects
to have a very specific alignment. So, it's not that much work, but it can gain you some
performance. I don't think it's worth the effort most of the time, but it is probably
a good practice to align your data. And then, aggregate commonly accessed data. I'm sure
everybody's heard about this. They've heard about dots in Unity or, you know, what is
it called? Entity component systems, stuff like that, where you have a system and then
you have entities as an array and it accesses them, multiple enemies to the system. And
it goes through this flow of accessing linear data, and that's much faster than accessing,
say like a linked list. With a linked list, you have an object over there, an object over
there, who knows where they're at. The memory is virtualized, so who knows where they're
actually at in the physical memory. So, if you use, and by the way, like a linked list
inside of lists, for example, inside of C Sharp are vectors, which are internally arrays.
So, I'm talking about linked lists, when the data is disconnected. So, having your data,
especially frequently accessed data, that is relative to each other in consecutive memory.
If you want to do memory pooling and then have a big chunk of memory, and then, you
know, virtualize your own addresses within that space, and you want to, say, put your
entity for your game object in there, and its components and all that stuff that it
has to access, you can put it in there. If you have a set of entities that all do the
same thing, but they have individual datas, but you want to update them collectively,
consecutively, you can use that memory pooling to kind of put them all in this consecutive
memory. And knowing your CPU is good for this, because if you know how much cache you have
on the CPU, you can actually optimize for cache, so that it'll load in a big old chunk,
and it'll just blow through it really fast, and then you don't have to worry so much about
your access to memory being slow. And that's the bottleneck of pretty much most programs
outside of file system access and that sort of stuff, network stuff. So, aggregate your
data together. That's one easy way to surefire, make your program faster.
So those are some things you do to have magic bullets to solve a little bit of performance,
but you're not going to make huge gains out of that. You're going to make little tiny
gains, and it could be fun doing that sort of stuff. So there's no magic bullet for doubling
your speed. Usually that just means fixing your overall algorithm, your business logic
and how it operates. So even quantifiable algorithms that, you know, you've tested
two algorithms and you've quantified mathematically, and one algorithm is better than the other,
does not mean that it's going to run faster than the other, unless it leaps and bounds
faster. If it's slightly faster, it does not mean it's going to run faster. Like I said,
the CPUs are very smart. They figure out branching, they figure out caching and all that sort
of stuff. So you can have a quantifiable, faster algorithm that will get beat by a slower
algorithm just because of the architecture. So I really liked, you know, Game Boy or Xbox,
PlayStation 3, you know, all those computers, Commodore 64, where they all have the same
hardware and that means it's known and so you can test it very easily. Our problem nowadays
is we have tons of different CPUs, tons of different iterations of CPUs, even along,
like if you said, I support only Intel CPUs, there's tons of different Intel CPUs, you
know, released every year and you don't know which one your players are going to be using
or your clients are going to be using. So you don't really want to test and really hyper,
make the performance hyper fast on a specific CPU, aka your development machine, at the
cost of flexible code or readable code or elegant code or any of that. So it's just
something to keep in mind. If you are using a very well-known, specific set of hardware,
usually game consoles, more power to you. Just knock out that performance on that CPU
because it's a known CPU that you can, you're programming against. Everybody, everyone who's
going to play your game on that device has that device. So that's, you can optimize in
those scenarios and just go whole ham for that. So yeah, just test specific hardware.
If you have minimum requirements, suggested requirements, test on those guys, test the
performance. You may very well find that one performs better in one scenario and worse
in another. So that's kind of the thoughts on optimization. Now I do want to wrap this
up with a famous optimization and I've been asked about this optimization. You know, it's
something that a lot of people know because it's a very popular one. And this is the inverse,
the fast inverse square root. You know, it's a 30-year-old square root that they did for,
was it Doom or Quake? It was probably Quake. I don't know. John Carmack made it but he
got it from someone else. I'm like, I don't know the history. History is not important.
The fact is you shouldn't be using this. This is a 30-year-old algorithm made for the machines
of the time which didn't have branch prediction, for example. And they didn't have built-in
signs or they didn't have built-in square roots. Nowadays, we have built-in square roots.
We have built-in square roots for floats. We have built-in square roots for doubles
and they are single instruction on the CPU. So it's not worth our time to implement 30-year-old
algorithms and computers change often. And it's just one thing that I do see developers
getting caught up on is some of these, some of this old knowledge that doesn't really
apply anymore. So I've got a little thing here we can take a look at. So if we take
a look here at this code, we're including math. It's just a little C file. And we're
going to do the square root float, square root double. And I'm just going to put a break
point here. This is debug mode. Nothing is optimized because otherwise it will strip
out the stuff and I don't want to fight the optimizer to show an example of something.
So we're going to run this and what we're going to do here, I already have it open,
but you can go to debug, windows, disassembly to see the assembly code that's generated
for this program. And if we just look at the disassembly here, we can see that we have,
this is the C code and these are the functions that are set up for it. I don't know exactly
what it's going to be when you optimize the code. It may even strip the square root based
on the cons that are going in and all that sort of stuff. But anyways, you can see here
it uses implementation of square root F here, which is going to be an internal function
that does magic things. But what you can see here for the square root of double is that
it is a single built in assembly instruction. Well, it's calling this function. And this
function, the reason it's calling this function is that vendors can implement it how they
want. Most of them are going to implement it. You can see this is using XMM by the way.
Most of the vendors are going to implement it the way that is fastest. So CPU calls,
it's going to be based on the architecture. But this is going to be way, way faster than
the inverse square root function from 30 years ago. So do not use that. And don't use knowledge
from 30 years ago. Use wisdom from 30 years ago. Generally how you work with teams and
how you work with code and how you design code and think about how things interact.
That sort of stuff is super valuable. Those guys did a lot of research mainly in those
fields. They didn't optimize these little instructions. And that is the useful information
for you. Not inverse square root or any particular algorithm. If an algorithm has been used for
30 years, take a look at maybe making a new algorithm. Because there's a lot of stuff
that gets added to CPUs. We have now artificial intelligence parts of our CPUs. We've got
matrix stacked CPUs. We've got all kinds of new stuff that can use a different algorithm
and perform much faster. Say whether it's distributed across multiple cores. Or maybe
you even use the GPU to do the algorithm. Because we do have compute GPU now. Like compute
shaders or CUDA. You can just write an algorithm that runs across a huge amount of cores and
blow through things way faster now. So that's kind of my general advice on optimization.
Don't over optimize. But do think about optimizing ahead of time. And don't stress out. Have
fun while coding. Think about it. Think more about your overall design. Who you're working
with. Whether you're working alone or not. And just think about those aspects of your
coding. And you're going to have a wonderful experience. And you're going to be much happier.
And you're not going to get caught up in all the fights on stack overflow or whatever people
do on stack overflow these days. So, cool. That's basically it. If you guys have any
suggestions on things to take a look at or think about or talk about or anything like
that. This has been quite a lot of fun. So, yeah. Let me know if I missed anything. If
I messed up anything. If I got any information wrong. You know, if things have changed or
maybe I just misinterpreted something. Let me know and we can always pin the comment
so that other people know too. So, bye for now.
Hello. This is an amendment to the podcast. You can tell that it's a different day. Sun's
out and everything. But I was going to sleep last night and I realized that I said 256
bytes for SIMD instructions and 128 bytes for the NEON instructions for ARM. And I meant
to say bits. So, I don't know why that bugged me. Clearing that one up. Second one, the
one that actually bothered me was the system calls to the square root functions. And that's
because we were in debug mode and it was getting late and I wasn't thinking about it. So, I
have now set up a release mode demo here where we will see the x86 instructions for square
roots. So, you can see I have to print them out so that it doesn't optimize my variables
out. And then if we run this and check out our disassembly, it will be in reverse order.
The key is going to be up here. But you see it calls the assembly instruction square root
PD and then square root single signed or signed single. I don't know which one of the S's
is signed and which one is singled. But there you go. That's the actual assembly instructions
I was expecting to see. I was a little bit surprised when I didn't see them last night.
But it's because I was in debug mode. I wasn't thinking. So, yeah. And that's basically my
amendment. See you guys.