Welcome back! Today we're one step closer to Microsoft buying Blizzard. Some new C stuff,
I got a PHP note, we got, there's a lot of stuff about programmer health and some other
stuff to go over today. So, I guess the first big story that happened today was Microsoft
is one step closer to buying Blizzard. Of course this is all part of the industry consolidation
that everyone's talking about for the game industry. And it's part of, I think it's related
to something I mentioned before which is we have an issue where a lot of stuff, there's
just a lot of games being published out to Steam and app stores on both iOS and Android
and a lot now even on the Nintendo Switch which used to be a really walled off garden.
And with all that noise it's really hard for people to punch through it and become successful.
A lot of them have to go through YouTubers and YouTubers have a very specific show to
put on. So a lot of games are being kind of developed in a way that YouTubers can use
them to be funny or entertaining. And so we've got a lot of noise in that at respect. There's
a lot of games that are getting published with Unity Asset Store stuff. They just pull
some stuff off the Asset Store they pay a few bucks for, throw it all together, do some
very light coding and then they put out a game in less than a week. And sometimes they're
really successful on YouTube. There's a lot of channels out there constantly looking for
more content and games to play that are different and so that constant stream is really nice.
That being said, that makes for a lot of noise in the game industry. Lots and lots of noise
on all platforms. We have a lot of adult games coming out of nowhere. My wife complains a
lot about how many adult games she's getting on Steam even though she has so many filters
to block them. They keep coming through. I think it's kind of the joke now. Everybody
kind of sees that. So with all that madness, big companies, they have the money to push
their games, to push their products. They can market to millions of people. They have
hundreds of millions of dollars to put into marketing and research and influencer campaigns,
lots of influencer campaigns. A lot of streamers are paid to pay the games to promote them.
And sometimes, I don't know if the streamers even mention that they are paid to promote
them and if they do it's probably at the beginning of the stream and a lot of people aren't
there for that so they just think that the streamers playing this game that they really
just found and enjoyed when those streamers are paid a ton of money to stream. I know
this because I've worked with companies that do those kinds of campaigns. And they're a
valid marketing campaign because you can get a lot of people to play your game using this
technique.
So how does that relate to Microsoft buying Blizzard and consolidating of the game industry?
Well, like I said in some previous videos, these companies are able to spend millions
and millions of dollars to get eyeballs on their games, to buy their games and they make
tons of money. And all the little companies that can't compete with that wealth have a
very hard time even with really incredible games. There's a lot of incredible games that
just nobody ever hears of or that never can get completed because they can't get the funding.
So, these big companies get bigger. They spend a lot of money to make a lot of money and
then they spend that money to buy up all the other medium-sized businesses. I think every
company I've worked at for the last three companies, all three of them were purchased
by a much larger company and one of them got purchased twice by a large company. So, it's
a very real thing, the consolidation of all these companies.
So the European Commission has approved Microsoft's Blizzard purchase. Some other European country,
I don't know what it was, probably England or something, denied it. But there's, I don't
know how this works, but it still goes through and they're still going to be working towards
it. I am frankly a little bit ambivalent to big companies buying up other big companies
or big companies buying up medium-sized companies. It's a great way for developers, if they get
equity in a medium-sized company, it's a great way to get an extra paycheck. And it's kind
of just the way the system is, what can we do? We can't tell people to stop developing
indie games or we can't make them promise that they'll spend more than a week on an
indie game before they publish it to Steam or any other game store. So, just getting
past that noise is already a high bar. Even if you do a Kickstarter campaign, a lot of
the times your game has to be some kind of meme to just stand out and punch through all
that noise. And that can be frustrating for people who don't want to make meme games.
They want to make games that maybe tell a story that means something to them or make
a game that's a story for children or they want to make a game that's more puzzle-related
but there's no gimmick and it's just a bunch of series of different kinds of puzzles, that
sort of stuff. And those developers are basically developing games for themselves and their
friends because it's a hard market to compete with. Like I said, I'm ambivalent to big companies
buying up other big companies. I think the consolidation just happens. Maybe it'll lead
to some kind of tipping point where people get tired of it. Maybe developers will get
tired of making stuff. Of course, then we get into the whole AI stuff and then putting
AI into games for really quick and easy content. So, I don't know. It could be noisy forever.
Maybe we can band together, all of us game developers who spend a good quality amount
of time on our games. There's a lot of us. So, if we got together and bought and sold
each other's games and kind of collaborated in that way to create our own kind of group
marketing strategy in that way, maybe that's the way we can punch through with great game
ideas and stop leaving it just to the big guys to be able to get their games out there.
So, beyond this kind of business news, the next thing I want to talk about is C. C is
my favorite language. I love C++. I love C Sharp. I love JavaScript. Python I'm okay
with. I'm learning the Python variant in Godot. I've used Python for over a decade now. It's
not one of my favorites, but mainly because of the whole tabbing thing and spacing and
all that sort of stuff. But it's a lot different than it was back then. So, I give it some
credit. Anyways, back to C. We got some great news for some C people. GCC 13 now supports
C2X stuff. And some of the notable things that people like to point out is null pointer,
which comes from C++. That one I'm iffy about. It doesn't really matter to me. I'm fine with
null. This null pointer makes it a little bit more explicit, better compiler support,
that sort of stuff. It's not just a macro that evaluates to zero. So, that will allow
some better compiler checking for things like that. Enhanced enums. Oh, also for null pointer,
not only for compilers, but kind of, what are they called? Static analysis tools will
have, you know, they won't have to deal with evaluating macros by name to figure out what
the context is that people are doing. So, there are some benefits there for the static
analysis and the compilers. Enhanced enumerations. If you've used enum, you know that it evaluates
to an int. An int on a 16-bit system is going to be different than a 32. 32 and 64 are basically
the same. Int evaluates to 32 bits. But it's ambiguous, right? That's why we have stdint.h,
which allows us to use very specific sizes for our integers, like int32t, uint32t, and
all that sort of stuff. So, the enhanced enumerations, if I recall correctly, allow you to put a
colon and then put the size of the enum. You see this a lot, like in Unreal Engine, whenever
they're doing enums. It's not like in C++, the class enum stuff. This is just allowing
enums to be a little bit safer in that way and adhere to a proper ABI. Because if you
put an enum instead of a struct and then you compile it on two different systems, you can't
guarantee, or two different compilers even, you can't guarantee that you're going to wind
up with the exact same ABI, especially across the network, if you're talking to like some
super small embedded device. You want your ABI, especially in C, to be consistent. So,
enhanced enumerations will help a lot with that. Another thing that I think my friend,
a good friend of mine, he really, really wants from C++, which is the auto keyword. Now,
you may know that C++ hijacked the auto keyword. Auto comes from B, which comes before C. Dennis
Ritchie worked on, when he worked with B, he wanted, you know, C is supposed to be somewhat
backwards compatible. I don't know a whole lot about B, but the auto keyword came from
that. And it was for, I think, locally scoped variables or maybe something like that. And
it just got deprecated and unused over time. So, the auto keyword, you'll notice, is a
keyword in C. And now they're deciding, you know, bring auto in and detect types. Of course,
you really need that in C++ because some of those types with the namespaces and everything
else, the namespaces plus the long class names plus the, you know, the templating make, just,
just declaring the type of a variable alone takes up the full 80 columns. For people like
me who like to code in 80 columns, you know, you're going to wind up with like 120 minimum
just to define your variable, not even assign it. So, auto is super necessary, in my opinion,
for C++. Not as necessary in C, but is nice for when you just, you just want to auto it
in and you don't want to have to worry about it. I don't, I don't change type names that
often. If I do, I use a refactoring tool. So, not crazy. I'm not like banging down the
door to get auto in. Another one is const expression. Now, I know you C++ guys, you
know what const expressions are. They're a great tool for the compiler. We are not talking
about the same const expression. This is like a lightweight version of const expression,
which does allow some compile time stuff. It's been months since I read the spec on
const expression for C, so I don't recall it all off the top of my head, but go check
it out. It's kind of like a nice little addition. Again, C is supposed to be lightweight, and
I can take or leave any of these. I can code in C99, but I do like to stay up to date in
C and mess around with like the generic macro or, you know, some of the modern atomic stuff
and things like that. It is nice to stay kind of up to date with computers and just what
CPUs and all the CPUs and GPUs are doing these days. So, it's good to stay up to date. That's
what's happening in C land. Now, I'm going to take a second to talk about PHP for you
web people who still use PHP. I don't, I love PHP because it's so simple. I use Node.js
for websites too. I use things like Firebase for a random website every now and then to
throw it up. You know, I, but I do love PHP because it's very flat, straightforward, simple,
and it's well supported on basically everything. Like, coding on Windows is pretty easy, debugging
in all Windows and all that, at least since I've been doing it for a while. Maybe I'm
cheating because I've used it for many years. But PHP 8 came out a while ago, and now I
have a little bit of a rant for people who are using PHP and not using PHP 8. I love PHP,
and I love the flexibility of it, so I get it. You want to use kind of the old tried
and true, but please try out PHP 8, and especially try out the, what are they called, type names.
Being able to type name and kind of strongly type your PHP is very nice. And it's great
because it's not all or nothing. You can use some strong types, or you should use strong
types in many places where you know what the type is going to be. And then you can just
not use strong types in places that you want to deal with, you know, strings or network
requests or things coming from the client or going to the client or just arbitrary data,
like collections or an array of, you know, if you want to make an array with mixed data
types inside of them, that's completely fine. But try out PHP 8 and do use the type name
syntax. The reason I bring this up is because I don't see, I continue to see PHP being used
in the modern era, and all of them are like, I've even seen stuff on PHP 5, which I used
like a decade ago. So PHP 7 is pretty popular, but try out PHP 8, get up to date, it's faster.
Type safety, whenever you add type names, you automatically get some magical speed up
in your code just because it's known. Anytime you have something known, your code's going
to go faster. This is why native code, like C and C++, are so fast, other than them not
having garbage collectors or being interpreted. Everything, you try to make everything known,
like you duplicate functions, that's what templates do, they just duplicate the functions
for different types, and everything is just statically known. And so it can be really
fast because it knows what it's doing, it knows the size of variables that are going
inside of functions, it doesn't have to dynamically allocate the stack. So just a little aside.
In assembly, whenever you compile C or C++, there's a thing called a shadow stack, and
there's also home space. This is a space when you call a function, it has to allocate, it
uses some registers for the first few arguments, but then it has to allocate the stack, some
memory on the stack to be able to know the size of the arguments going in. If the size
is arbitrary and jumping around all the time, it's going to have to determine the size before
it can allocate that stack space, or it's going to over-allocate the stack space just
to support some unknown type. So, yeah, type safety is also good. Just FYI, for all of
you PHP programmers out there, give it a try, I promise you'll love it. I love it. I still
keep the flexibility and simplicity of PHP, I can write a whole routing, I can write an
entire router for a request that comes in, I can take the URL and figure out which, like,
get or post request or even to return some content with. In less than 30 lines of code,
I can write a PHP router. And that's using all the PHP stuff. So give it a try.
The next thing that I want to talk about is programmers' mental health. I saw a lot of
news articles recently about programmers with mental health, not issues, but like they're
burnt out or, you know, they stopped coding for a while and they're coming back or they
just, you know, they can't seem to keep a job or get a job, the job market's hard right
now. I'm not looking for a job, so I don't know about it. I know there's been tons and
tons of layoffs recently. I don't know how many of those are programmers, but I'm certain
there's got to be quite a few programmers within there. And probably a lot of web programmers,
and just because I think they got overstaffed during, you know, the stuff that went on in
2020, 2019, all that stuff. So they kind of overstaffed and, you know, now it's hard to
find work apparently for some people. Yeah, if you're getting burnt out from programming,
I don't know what to tell you, take a break, I don't know. Maybe you're not coding what
you love coding. I have coded almost nonstop, no breaks, for nearly 15 years. Hours and
hours a day, every day. I still have a wife, I still have kids, I still have a job, I still
do random stuff on the side like this thing, and, you know, I still code. I love code.
I sit here and read articles about code. So if you're getting burned out, maybe you're
not focusing on what matters most to you. Maybe you're chasing after trends. Maybe you're,
you know, not, you're trying too hard to complete projects that you're not interested anymore.
I think the key to my success in continuing to code and not get burned out is that I just,
whenever I finish coding a part of some big grand idea that I've had, I just quit programming
and I'm done and I move on to something else. It's not that important to finish the project.
And you know what, you don't always have to be the guy. You don't have to go make a million
dollars, you don't have to be super, you know, you don't have to make some super cool project
that everyone uses or anything like that. You don't have to be the guy. Give yourself
some slack, have fun. Coding is fun. Most of it is creative and playing around with
different ideas. It's all just a game. It's a puzzle that you play around with and have
fun with. And that's the key. And that's also why I've programmed in so many languages,
I've dealt with so many different technologies and also programmed stuff for like Game Boy
and I've tried out and learned four different assembly languages. I just have fun. It's
just a puzzle to me. So don't burn yourself out. If you're getting burned out, it's probably
because you're doing something you don't want to do. This guy here, I'm not going to show
it, I don't want to point out anybody specific, but he's saying that he's having a hard time
with the job market. But he seems really like blase, super chill and like, you know, get
coffee and chill, sip on some tea. It looks like he mentioned, the only reason I know
he's a coder is because he mentioned it. There's like a one sentence where it was mentioned
in this whole thing. So maybe if you talk more about code and update your LinkedIn,
do some things like that. I'm not too fond of his advice. His advice is just like, if
you're doing front end, do back end. If you're like, I don't know, stuff about self care
and stuff like that. Look, if you want a job in code and programming, I'll tell you the
secret. Program a lot. Impress people. Do some math for fun. Make a whole bunch of websites.
Make some games. Update your LinkedIn. Recruiters are always looking on LinkedIn. Put a whole
bunch of keywords of everything you've done. So you'll see in the first episode of the
podcast where I read off a bunch of stuff that I have messed with, that list and more
is on my LinkedIn. And I'm, you know, recruiters. They look up these keywords and that's how
they find people. So update your LinkedIn, put in all the keywords of the stuff that
you know how to do because you will be tested on them. If you go for a job interview, don't
waste anybody's time not knowing how to do something. That being said, my first job,
when I barely started coding in PHP, I BSed it and said I knew exactly what I was doing.
And the guy, the owner had me come out to the back and he's like, look, here's my problem
with the code. And he left me with it. And I had to figure it out in 30 minutes. And
it was just a, it was a serious problem I had with their company. And this was a small
company and I figured it out in 30 minutes and I blew my own mind. And he was, he hired
me on the spot because he was so excited that I solved it. So sometimes that scenario can
work, but don't rely on it. Don't take my advice on that.
There's been also one other thing related to health and programming is people have been
talking about software development ethics. Now I have a very specific view on ethics
in programming. If it's a game and it doesn't hurt anybody and you don't steal anybody's
stuff and you don't take their money and all this sort of stuff. You know, if you, if you're,
if you buy a product and you own it, for example, like if you buy a game, a modern game even,
and you tear it apart to figure out what's going on inside of it and you learn their
company secrets that way, that's fine. In my opinion, that's you exploring and researching.
That's not the ethics I'm talking about here. I think their ethics is more about their focus
is kind of on artificial intelligence and it talks about, you know, using AI to steal
stuff or scam people and all that sort of stuff. I don't think, I don't think we're
going to change anybody's mind on programming ethics. You're just going to code the way
that you code. If you're going to get more ethical in programming, you need to be more
ethical as a person. I don't mean to make this less technical of a talk, but the problem
is at the source. You know, that's the same truth in code as it is with people. So if
you find that you're talking to somebody or know somebody that has, you know, they're
doing nasty things and stealing people's info and trying to scam them, you're not going
to, you're not going to change their mind by writing a blog post about programming ethics
and trying to get out there and teach programming ethics to groups of people. I've seen it on
LinkedIn. I've seen it in blog posts. I've seen it kind of, it's like, I don't know if
people are just trying to become speakers at some kind of event or something, but ethics
are at the source and the people have to change their own internal ethics. They have to be
willing not to steal from people. They have to be willing not to lie. They have to be
willing to have integrity and not run up the clock for their employer doing nothing. A
lot of programmers don't do as much as they should when they're at work or when they're
on teams. I have a little story about when I was in college. There was this, I would
always be on teams in college and I was the one, even though I went to school for animation,
I was the one who was doing the code stuff and I wound up doing all the code. And the
coders just didn't, they didn't do their work. Of course, I was a coder at the same time
because I was more focused on code at that point. But I wound up doing all the work and
they didn't do anything. And that's not their own software development ethics, that's their
own personal ethics. They were more interested, one of them was more interested in looking
at OpenGL and making a cube move or something. That's just people ethics. You can't preach
software ethics to people. If you want to preach ethics, you've got to preach people
ethics. Treat people nicely. Don't steal. Don't steal from your employer. Don't steal
their time. Don't steal their money. Don't steal from others. Respect others. All these
things, this isn't a podcast about morals, but you need to preach morals to people, not
software ethic. So please don't go to any of these software ethics talks. I don't know
what they really have to talk about. So yeah, that's kind of the mental health aspect of
today's thing. And yeah, I just noticed there was a burst in all these, I mean, it seems
to be constant ever since 2019. Lots of mental health and kind of existential crises with
programmers. I don't know why programmers have this. You know, I feel like I've been
playing a game for 15 years. So I haven't really felt this, but all I can say is what
I've done, and hopefully that helps somebody out there.
So I want to talk about now Google. Google is one of those, they're not part of ICANN,
I don't think. ICANN, the domain name, I don't know what to call them, the domain name consortium
or something like that. But they are kind of, they are associated to it, which means
they can come up with domain names. And one of the things that they decided to come up
with, here I've even got the site here to show you. One of the things that they came
up with is, here's the new domain names. Let me zoom in on this. Okay,.foo. Okay, I feel
like that's some kind of programming joke maybe. Okay, that's fine. Let's see, what
else? We've got.zip. Now, the eagle-eyed viewer out there will know that.zip is probably
not a good idea for a domain extension. What are they called? Top level domain name or
something like that, TLDN or something..zip is probably not a good idea. You probably
shouldn't use super well-known extensions for your domain names. And now, this is the
goofy part. Zip, this is their definition. This is what they told ICANN. And these are
approved, I believe. Please note that the launch schedule for this is, this TLD has
been modified since being announced. The schedule is published below and has been updated and
approved by ICANN. Zip is a secure domain name for typing, for tying things together
or moving really fast. Hosting content on a.zip domain means speed. This is kind of
like zip and zippies, zip, zip, zip, zip. So, maybe they didn't realize that's also
for the compressed file type. I feel like that's just problems waiting to happen. Like
who, first of all, I would never make a domain name unless it's a joke as a.zip because
you'll probably be put on all the spam lists and no one will probably click your link.
They'll think that you're scamming them with a zip file. That's already one problem. And
good on them too because I can tell you that.zip domains will probably be used to scam
people a lot. You know, freemusic.zip and it'll download a zip file when you go to
it. And then of course the kids or whoever is downloading this will then get a virus
because they went to this.zip domain. And I know it's not any different than freemusic.com
slash zip or slash whatever or freemusic.com and they get a zip file sent to you. But if
something downloads when you go to a website, you are probably questioning it. Even a kid
would be like, I didn't click on anything. But if you go to a.zip domain and it downloads
something that's a zip file, you probably won't question it as much. I'm just saying.
The other one is.mov. Let's see, this is a secure domain for moving pictures and other
things that move. For anything that moves you,.move is the perfect domain. This is
also a famous file extension. And if you download a.mov file by going to, I don't know, pocahontas.mov
and it downloads a movie called Pocahontas and it's not really a movie file, it's something
else, then you have another problem. I love.dad though..dad is a secure domain for
dads. And I'm a dad. I can get behind.dad. That's awesome. So I can't get behind.zip.mov,
but I can get behind.dad..phd,.professor. Hopefully these show off your teaching credentials.
Hopefully these are locked. I don't know if any of these are locked. Like.edu and.gov
are locked. You can't get them as an individual. You have to prove that you're an educational
institution for.edu and you have to prove you're a government entity for.gov. And that's
why those are successful and you can use a.edu for getting discounts and stuff is because
they can trust that those are locked. I don't know if PhD and professor are locked, nor
do I care. I don't think certain people in society should just get special, like individuals
get special privileges for domain extensions. That seems a little weird. Especially when
there's a lot of people with PhDs that study weird things and they have a PhD or they study
one thing and then they start preaching about another and say they're a doctor. We have
a lot of those on the internet. My wife shows me a bunch of them. Just these people masquerading
as actual scientists or whatever and they're not. So these are a little weird. I can see
these scamming people. I can see these scamming people with kind of just falsified stuff.
And even so, there are a lot of doctors and PhD people out there that kind of, they don't
have time to do the research. Let's say they're a doctor and they're a surgeon. They don't
have time to research some other field of medical science. So they rely on others. And
so if someone sent them, if they trust someone and that person's email got hacked and they
sent them a fake thing and then this other person started propagating it, we shouldn't
have like authority domains outside of.gov. So I don't know what ESQ is. I think we show
you are a bar admissions, Lamar work experience lawyer. Okay. Yeah. So I'm not super down
on lockdown domains outside of edu and gov. I think those were two good choices and the
only two that I think should exist. Dot dad. That's the one that wins it. I bet you I can
saw this list and all they saw was dot dad and it's like, yeah, whatever. I just let
it go. We're getting dot dad there. Oh, Nexus. I skipped that one. It's like a hub. Interesting.
Yeah. Zip and MOV are the ones I wanted to complain about and I have complained about
them. So let's move on. So another topic that I've seen fairly recently is, I mean, it's,
I've seen it recently, but I've seen it essentially the whole time I've done web development and
that's people trying to figure out what database to use. Now, a lot of these sites are going
to be one versus the other. So like graph database versus a relational database or a
no SQL database versus a SQL database. I don't often see vertical databases in here or anything
like that. So our memory cache databases, although my SQL has memory cache, it has,
you can set it up to have memory cache as a storage mechanism. So anyways, the debate
on which database to use, really you should be using many different databases for the
different parts of your program that does different things with data. So you'll use,
I think it's a, you'll use like a Redis for a leaderboard so that you can quickly sort
and select things. You'll use a MySQL for long term concrete storage. You don't want
messed up like accounts and no keeping track of very sensitive data like that. You'll use
no SQL databases for game data and quick storage of save data or like where enemies kind of,
I don't know if you have like timetables or something and you can put those in there.
Just kind of transient data that's not so important that's okay to refill. And you'll
use, you know, cache databases for very quick lookups. If especially this is you, you normally
front cache like a MySQL relational database. You front cache it so that you can, if something's
requested a lot from those structured databases, you can get to that information very quickly.
Another one is, what did I mention, the graph database. So a graph database is great for
data that is highly intertwined. Think friend graphs, I think we've all seen that. So you
have a lot of, you know, data that's connected to, that's interconnected and it can have
some blobs of information, you know, like account name and login date and, you know,
friends and the friends is the graph or something like that. So use a graph for that kind of
data. So what I'm getting at is stop arguing over database types. Use them all. They all
have a specific purpose for specific things. There's not one that's going to be a magic
bullet and there's not one that's going to solve all your problems. I know that if you
use things like Firebase or whatever, they may only support a couple variants of databases,
which is bad, but it does help with those types of like live apps or whatever. You should
use the database that you need for the time you need it. Cool. You know, key value stores
also. I know that NoSQL is often a key value store, but you can also just have a flat like
key and value, whether it's a blob of binary data or whatever. So just pick the database
that works for the task, not the program, not the whole app, for the task and you'll
be happy. That's one of the downsides of web development. If you're a web developer, you've
got to use different technologies all the time from the language to the stack to the
operating system to the web browser size, whether it's a phone or a desktop window or
if it's a database, it doesn't matter. You're using different tech all the time. It's the
curse of the job. So that's my view on all the arguments I constantly see over the years
of database selection. So don't fall into which database is better. Use the database
that works for the specific type of data. It is not unreasonable to use all the databases
because you need all those different types of data. And now I can't go on to the fun
stuff without talking about artificial intelligence. It's all in the news, so of course there's
a lot of news for it. Google has, you know, they had Google I.O. just recently. That's
the developer conference for Google. However, it's also part them trying to please the investors
and also consumers because a lot of people who are watching Google I.O. have never programmed
in their life because they wanted to see the pixel fold. I'm not here to talk about the
pixel fold. I'm here to talk about the goofiness of responsible AI. All these people are praising
this responsible AI, and I think that it's, you know, it's good to have responsible AI.
However, putting some metadata on a photo and embedding some data into a photo is not
responsible AI. Responsible AI comes from the source, not the output. So I know that
this is kind of one of the hot arguments on art and that sort of stuff. I'm not here to
talk about artificial intelligence, reading people's art and stealing it or anything like
that. I have no strong opinions on that. I love AI, and I also love art, and I want to
see both of them flourish. So one of the things that felt goofy to me was the responsible
AI stuff. And if you know the, if you're in the United States, you may know that all the
tech leaders except Elon Musk went to the White House to talk about artificial intelligence
and responsible artificial intelligence. So you had like Satya Nadella from Microsoft,
you had whoever was from Google. I think the CEOs left and came back. I can't remember
the names very well. And then of course all the other places, probably OpenAI and all
that. It was a room full of, you know, tech people and the president. So they had this
whole meetup about responsible AI. And what does responsible AI mean? Now, it's always
kind of goofy to have corporations and CEOs who are beholden to their shareholders in
those kinds of meetings to talk about their responsibilities to the human race at large.
But you know, it is a good thing that they talk about it. And of course, they get warnings
and say, hey, we're going to regulate this thing, probably. So stay in line. Anyways,
the one thing that irked me about the AI thing, Google I O was their big push on detecting
AI generated images. The image thing really got me because first of all, metadata, they're
going to put metadata inside of images. That's fantastic because you know what, whenever
you upload an image to any website worth their weight in salt, salt, sugar, worth their weight
in gold, they strip meta tags. So meta is useless. It just gets discarded by all companies
because well, first they read it, they read it for themselves. They want to get your GPS
location, all that stuff that's in your photo. By the way, turn off GPS on your photos. Nobody
uses the photos, where was I GPS thing on your phone. You're just giving people your
position all the time. It's kind of strange. And who knows who can get access to that.
But anyways, before they take that photo and send it off and propagate it to everybody,
they completely strip meta tags just so that it does protect your personal information
because photos, the meta for photos can have a lot of stuff in there that shouldn't. And
also if you're a web developer, strip the meta. Do not just take people's photos and
host them. Strip the meta. There's tons, you can just take a photo. If you're doing Node.js
for example, there's a library where you just take the photo and when it takes the photo
you can have it as part of one of the arguments to just strip the meta. And if you don't know
how to do meta stripping or anything like that, the easiest way to do it if you're kind
of new to coding or you're not well versed on how to access the metadata on a file, if
you take the photo and then use like magics or whatever it's called, just any kind of
image library and just crop it by like a, you don't even, I don't even think you have
to change it at all, but you probably should just so that you know that it's working. Just
like crop it or change something about it using the photo editing software or photo
editing library and then save it. And that just strips the meta automatically because
it's saving a new image. So strip the meta inside of the photos and videos please. Do
not, do not, do not read it, do not take it, do not sell it, do not redistribute it. Strip
the meta. So the second thing is, and this is probably the more clever one, but not exactly
perfect. That's where you can encode data inside of an image without changing how the
image looks. So you can inject data that's not metadata, you know, like, you know, into
the interlaced into the pixels or interlaced into the header or anything like that of the
file. Now that's obviously not something that gets stripped very easily, but if you open
that photo inside of a photo editor and save it, that's just going to be gone. It's not
encoded in the pixels. I mean, even if it is encoded in the pixels, it's just going
to resave the pixels in a new way when you export from a photo program. So it's like
the easiest thing to get rid of. So even if you use that library example where you just
take it and crop it or whatever and then save it again, that little encoded data that was
in there is now gone because it got resaved maybe as a different format or a format that
doesn't support interlaced data inside of the pixels. So that's my rant on that. That
was just lip service. The photos stuff, just pure lip service by Google on trying to make
people think that they're thinking about ethical AI. In fact, in my opinion, that's a complete
waste of money. You shouldn't be putting, you know, in fact, that doesn't even cost
them that much money to put that in, you know, on the output of the image. Instead of investing
money in ethical AI output and the file that gets outputted, you need to invest ethical
AI in the input, how you train the system, what you do with the system. That's ethical.
It's two different arguments. So don't believe the hype on when people talk about encoding
will tell you if it's a AI inside of the image or AI generated in the image. It's nonsense.
Invest in a service where I can upload a picture to Google and it has a memory of all the photos
it generated so it can tell me if that photo was generated by AI. That right there doesn't
need metadata. It doesn't need to put little tags inside of the binary. That just me send
you it and you tell me whether it is. Just do that. That's probably way more useful.
And then just make that an API I can call. So I guess that was kind of a rant on ethical
AI. I'm going to talk about some fun stuff now. I've seen in like programming humor stuff,
a lot of people are fighting over text editors. This is funny to me because we have people
saying I use notepad. Of course we all use notepad to do some code. But they're all ragging
on Visual Studio Code. I don't know why. Probably because Visual Studio Code came out and it
became really popular because it's Node.js, you can host it in the web, it has all kinds
of easy plugins, you can use web technology to write your plugins. And I've written like
language servers and stuff like that for Visual Studio Code. It's nice. But you have all kinds
of people talking about notepad or atom or my text editor runs inside of a terminal.
Visual Studio Code doesn't. My text editor runs a web page within it and all this other
stuff. So that's a lot of fun. Go into programming humor and please post some more text editor
jokes because I love them. They're funny to me. I think nobody's taking it seriously.
Of course there are people out there that are diards on their text editors. I can use
anything. I can use notepad, I use C-Line, I use Visual Studio, I use Visual Studio Code,
I use Nano, I sometimes use Vim, I use web div, editable divs. It doesn't matter to me.
Text is text. It's whatever. As long as I can press tab and I get a tab, that's all
I need. But those are kind of funny. So here's a, I have an example here of one. This is
just one. I saw like seven of these. I think there's a thing going on right now where everyone's
doing them. But go contribute to these. And now I'm going to talk about, I don't know
anything about this indie game or anything else. I just know it looked kind of fun. So
I thought I'd share it just because I kind of want to talk about indie games every now
and then that piqued my interest. It may be a copy of another indie game. It may be a
clone. It may be a stolen idea or whatever. The concept is pretty fun. I'm actually going
to turn it off. It has some music. I don't know if it's copyright. But the idea is that
you have these little paddles on the bottom and you got to slap the boxes that are coming
down. And as you rotate them, the paddles on the bottom sticks in place. So you have
the blue one on the right now. It can wind up all the way on the left. And I thought
that was kind of a neat little puzzle game. I love puzzle games. I love first person shooters,
puzzle games, RTS. I love all kinds of games. So I thought this one was kind of fun. So
I kind of wanted to shout out. Whatever game this is. It's called Swap I guess. Pretty
neat idea. It's fun. It's simple. Hopefully it's not just going to be a mobile game. Hopefully
there's going to be more to it. I'm not super into mobile games. But it does have iOS and
Android here. And it's coming on Steam. So I don't know. If you're a developer, add some
cool desktop perks. Don't make your game lock down. Don't lock down its potential to mobile
devices. And that's kind of another thing I guess I'll end on. If you're going to make
a game and you're going to put it on different devices, one of the things that I don't like,
for example, is old games like Grand Theft Auto, Vice City or something coming to mobile
because the controls are clunky. And I didn't buy it because I didn't want to play it on
phone. I have copies of Vice City on Xbox and PlayStation 2 I think it is over there
somewhere. So I didn't spend any money on it. But I doubt it has good Bluetooth controller
support. A lot of games on mobile don't. So if you put your game on Steam or whatever,
make some controller support on mobile. Put in the extra effort. I know it kind of sucks.
But let's make mobile games better by adding more support controls. Let's add a whole realm.
Let's force Google and Apple to have a little tag on there that says, you know, controller
required or something like that. Let's just make a whole category for it. That would be
fantastic. I would love that. But anyways, yeah, that was a cool little indie game called
Swap. Don't know much more than that video. That's all I've seen. So that's about it.
Thanks for listening and I'll see you guys in the next one. Bye for now.