Jobs for programmers. Some of us need them, some of us have them. I was curious
about remote work and how it affects the job market, what companies are doing with
remote work. I work remotely, a lot of you maybe work remotely, and just kind of
want to take a look at jobs. But before I get into remote work, I want to take a
look at losing jobs. Lots of people are losing jobs. Yet another story, today, not
today, a couple days ago Stack Overflow lays off 10% of their employees, and
that's not a lot. I was surprised to find out that 10% of the Stack Overflow
employee base was 58 employees, which is pretty astounding. I like that they run a
tight ship over there. I think that having, I mean, that means they've got 580
employees. I think that may be a little bit too high to run a question-and-answer
site. I don't know. I don't run a question-and-answer site. I just think
that oftentimes we hire too many developers. We hire way too many people,
and that's usually what is slowing us down at companies interworking with
people. So perhaps they're figuring this out and, you know,
laying off people. I've always said that programming is not an assembly line job.
You can't just add more programmers and then all of a sudden magically produce
tons more code. There's been studies of this that show that that's never the
case. You can look at the Mythical Man month from the 70s, and that still holds
true. Believe it or not, they did hire tons of programmers at companies even
back then when there weren't that many. So just taking a look at something like
that, and that information has basically held true this entire time, we can start
to see that you can't just hire more programmers and more developers and
expect things to go faster. That's just not how it works. In fact, I think the
CEO of Nintendo, he famously was shown Mother 3. I don't know which one it was.
Mother, the game that has like Ness as the main character. I think it's Ness. I
don't know who it is. Kid with baseball cap and the baseball bat. So it's
this RPG, and they presented it to him, and he said this is gonna take
forever to fix. And so he said, we can get it done in six months if we start over
from scratch. And that's what they did. They started over from scratch, and I
think it took seven or eight months to complete the game and get it published.
And that just shows you that sometimes having a lot of legacy code, it's easier
just to scrap it all and do it from scratch. And I'm a big proponent of that.
However, it's very hard to pull off in this day and age. Anyways, we have... so
Stack Overflow fired or laid off. I don't know. Is that any different than firing? I
think it's the more PC language. But they fired 58 employees, which is 10% of the
workforce. They were saying that the CEO of Stack Overflow perhaps, or his name is
I can't even pronounce his name. I'll call him PC. That's his initials.
Said that layoffs were also a result of taking a hard look at our strategic
priorities this fiscal year and the organizational structure. And that's
usually how it goes. They look and see, oh, we have a lot of bloat. We had a heyday
during that pandemic, hired people maybe for things we didn't need. And now
we're kind of overpopulated and slowing ourselves down, just kind of drudging
along. Once the ship gets bigger, it's gonna be harder to push it. So that's
essentially, you know, as vague as it is, why let it go? They want to pursue
agility and flexibility with the launch of AI ML focused offerings in the months
ahead. So everybody's going AI, obviously. I think everybody can can look around
and see that. Every company, I mean, most of Google I.O. is just AI. That's the
buzzword. That's what everybody's expecting. It's where all the investors
are going, even though they probably wouldn't have touched it with a 10-foot
pole like five years ago. And so Stack Overflow is in jeopardy, honestly. When
you have a, I mean, I think I've seen articles about a dip in their user base
ever since like ChatGPT was announced and GitHub Copilot and these kinds of AI
generated code. And I can see why. It's very easy to just write a comment in
your code, say, save a file, and it detects the language and it gives you
basically what you would have went to Stack Overflow for, a little copy and
paste snippet. So I don't know exactly what they're gonna do with artificial
intelligence. I think the only way they can save themselves is if they compete
with things like Copilot and they produce an artificial intelligence that
takes the entire base of knowledge of Stack Overflow and all the suggestions
there and kind of works from that. Although Microsoft, you know, they bought
GitHub for a reason and that was to have access to all the code on GitHub,
whether we like it or not, to train their AIs. So they have a much bigger code base
to work from. So that's, you know, just nature of the business. But I
don't want to focus too much just on Stack Overflow. Ironically, and this one
is ironic to me because we all know about all the layoffs that are
happening. There's layoffs at every big company you can think of. Games, software,
nobody is safe in the software realm. And I don't want to say the funniest, but
it is kind of funny. LinkedIn cuts 700 jobs and closes their China app. So I can
understand why they closed their China app. I mean, that's a whole other
discussion about, you know, Chinese firewall and kind of their regulatory
stuff that makes it very difficult to do stuff there. So besides the point, but
they cut 700 jobs at LinkedIn. It's ironic because you would imagine with
everybody getting laid off from every big company, there's a lot of people who
are going to be paying for LinkedIn and trying to get jobs. So it's weird to me
that a job search website, and I have an article here that says, let's see here,
let's take a look. It says more than 197,000 tech sector employees have lost
their jobs since the start of 2023. This isn't even talking about 2022. So, you
know, 200,000 people looking for jobs and LinkedIn is, they're cutting, they're
cutting 700 jobs from their company, which does that mean people are not
looking for jobs? Does it mean they're not looking through LinkedIn? Or they
just, is LinkedIn just not a viable thing for finding jobs? I don't know what to
take of this. I've gotten jobs through LinkedIn
recruiters, so it's a little strange to me. I think that it's pretty effective.
There's a lot of recruiters on there and there's a lot of noise. Daily I get
recruiters hitting me up for jobs. I sometimes feel like I need to close down
my thing whenever I take a job that I'm happy with. But there's a lot of
recruiters and there's, it seems to be a lot of jobs because I, you know, I get them
for artificial intelligence, games, mobile apps, just the whole spectrum. So, I don't
know. So it's very odd. I don't know what to take of it. I don't know if it's a
good omen, a bad omen that they're cutting jobs, but something to think
about. But they're not the only ones. So, it looks like May 3rd, Unity conducts a
third round of layoffs. This is the Unity game engine. If you're not a game
developer, that's the one I'm talking about. They've cut something, about
8% of their staff, which is another 600 people getting laid off. And I guess this
is the third round. I have no idea what happened in the first couple of rounds.
How many people got laid off in that. So, very interesting. Again, games
are doing great right now, but I don't know if it's just the trend. All the big
tech bros are talking to each other at their yacht meetups or whatever rich
people do and saying, hey, look, we can just cut a whole bunch of jobs. Look, Elon
Musk did it. He cut Twitter to nothing. And still the thing is running and
tons of people are using it and it hasn't totally collapsed. Maybe we
can do the same. I don't know. But usually, once one person does it, it really
starts a chain reaction. They all realize, hey, maybe we're bloated. We need to save
some money. Inflation is happening. All kinds of weird stuff's happening.
Banks are collapsing. Maybe we should start cutting people to save money. I
don't know. But it's very interesting. It's affecting everybody from
games to software to tech companies. The whole spectrum. Even LinkedIn. If
LinkedIn's being hit, then you know everything's being hit. That's the way I
see it. I did see something from Times Now News. Amid mass layoffs,
there's a particular IT company, an Indian IT company, that is hiring like
1,500 people. That's not unheard of. I actually was fired. I will call it fired,
laid off, whatever you want to call it. I was laid off. I was part of a
studio, a game studio, and we were making money. The company was already bought
once and they were about to be bought again. They decided to lean up.
What they did was they brought in a bunch of... I don't know if they were... I never
asked them. I think they were Russian. They may have been Ukrainian. The guy
that was kind of communicating with them and working with them, he was Russian, so
I don't know what the people on the other end was. They didn't really explain
it much. But after working with them and they got integrated with the team, they
laid off everybody in the United States for that company and offshored
everything. So it makes perfect sense that they'd be offshoring. Offshore
companies would be hiring tons and tons of new people. That could be
exactly what it is. I think that's gonna be unnecessary with all
the AI stuff that we're creating because it can do it much more efficiently and
you can have one programmer who's a little more effective maybe. He's got
a no code. You can't just hire anybody to just put in prompts for
AI. You've got to have somebody who knows code inside and out. So I guess the
upper echelons of coders, your jobs are safe. So don't worry about that. So
there's been a lot of layoffs. Intel did more layoffs on May 9th, it looks like. So
you've got Intel and Google, Amazon, Meta, Microsoft, and just tons of companies
just even this month laying off people. And I think that we're tired of seeing
all the headlines because we've seen them basically every month for like a
year but it's still going and that's that's pretty crazy.
Luckily I've not had any problems with this since way back when
and that scenario I was talking about. But it is unfortunate for a lot of
people. I don't know how to deal with job security there when you're in a huge
company like these some of these big companies, Intel, Microsoft. They'll
probably cut important people not even knowing. They just need
big sections to just disappear so that they can kind of reserve their funds.
So that's kind of the crazy stuff that's going on and the job stuff. I'm
not worried at all. If you're secure in your job you don't have to worry. If
you're a really good programmer and you know many languages and you can go
cross-discipline you really don't have to worry. You're gonna be fine.
And if you do get laid off like I said I get tons of stuff in LinkedIn. I
know there's stuff out there for you. So if you are laid off, if you're not,
something to think about. Everything's good. That brings us to remote work. So I
started thinking about remote work today because...
Elon Musk did a long interview and one of the things that came up with that was remote
work.
You probably know Elon's point of view on remote work.
And you know, I'm somewhat ambivalent to remote work.
I think that it has its benefits for those of us like me who have family in a place that's
not so techie and it has its huge downsides which we'll also kind of cover.
So kind of what he went over today was he opposes the work from home policies and called
out remote work and said it was morally wrong.
He suggested that work from home policies are fundamentally unfair since every employee
can work from home, pointing to a factory and food workers.
So basically what he's saying is there are kind of, I don't know if you want to call
them elites, who can work from home, people like me, who have a job that pretty much is
all done on the web.
And then you have the other part of the society who are equally important in holding up the
society and producing food and working in factories and keeping everything we enjoy
afloat.
And there is an unfairness to that and it could cause social tension, I think, is his
perspective on this.
He mentioned Amazon and Apple want their employees to go back to office, which is true.
Game companies like Blizzard and Microsoft want that as well.
And it's kind of a big push to get back to office.
For employees, the remote work benefits are obvious.
And that's kind of what was said.
That's like a quick summary of what was said in that.
Now my perspective on remote work, I know that I have a bias, but I also understand
this point of view.
I understand the unfairness factor to society.
Of course, there's always been a disparity between, say, programmers who sit and don't
have to do much.
We're not lifting heavy weights or heavy things and risking our lives like other people are
doing.
And then other people do that.
And somehow programmers get paid more.
And it all comes down to capitalism, supply and demand.
For example, if computers just died today, I'd probably be able to pick up and learn
construction or something like that as long as I'm mobile and able.
And that's not so easy.
If all the lumber in the world disappeared and all we had were computers, it would be
much more difficult for someone in construction to take a role that I work in.
And that's not to say one is harder than the other or anything like that.
That's just how capitalism works.
It's a supply and demand scenario.
And it can be unfair, but it's created the greatest nation in the world and the greatest
prosperity that the world has ever seen because we do share a lot of our prosperity.
So it's unfortunate.
I have no solution.
I have no opinion on a solution.
I'm just a family man who wants to feed his kids.
So from the perspective of working from home, I've worked with a lot of people who work
from home for the last couple of years.
I mean, my job all the way up till 2020 was going to the office and I would take a train
two hours to get there and two hours back because I wanted to live in a different place
than the job was or it was way too expensive to live where the job was.
So I sacrificed four hours of my day, five days a week just to get to and from work.
And I was on trains where people on the train before me were attacked by people with machetes.
And I've seen quite a few weird things on the train.
So I prefer not to do that, especially now that I have children.
So there is like a rah-rah and a lot of people who are remote work, working from home, they
have this like, let's band together and not allow it to happen.
Now I would like to say if you could make yourself valuable.
Now this is the same thing between programmers.
So you have a value hierarchy of supply and demand within programmers.
You have programmers who there's a lot of supply and the demand is met.
But then you have jobs that are much higher difficulty that have a very low supply of
programmers and has a very high demand.
Now I would argue that if there's a huge supply of programmers for a particular job, then
a company may be in their rights to say, come into work.
And that's because you don't really have arguing power there.
You don't, you can't fight for your position.
You can't do something like that.
Now programmers who are in much lower supply, let's say they're a systems programmer, game
engine programmers, those sorts of people, you have bargaining power.
It's hard to find people in that realm.
And you could say, hey, I'll take a little bit of a pay cut.
Let me work exclusively from home.
And we've got a deal.
And companies would gladly do that.
And they even before the whole pandemic, people would have, companies would have gladly done
it.
I've worked with people who worked remote.
So I think just on the perspective of remote work, there is, you know, you don't have a
right to just want to do it your way.
And the reason I say this is because I've worked with a lot of programmers who work
remote who don't do much of anything.
They, I know they came in late, came in late.
They push off things.
They go to a lot of meetings and just work doesn't get done.
And you can tell because timelines get pushed all the time.
And part of that is the hierarchy of the business, you know, management and all that stuff and
having too many programmers.
And that's a whole other thing to, to, to look at.
Now one thing I will say is I do miss working in person.
It is something that I do miss.
I actually liked going in and the camaraderie and, you know, making the jokes and eating
with the, eating with the coworkers and talking about code and projects and concepts and ideas
and game designs and hunting and just random stuff.
I do miss that.
And, you know, the free lunches were awesome too.
You get free lunch every day.
Those, those were great, a great incentive.
So there were definitely huge perks that I really miss.
Now as a father, I love being at home with my kids.
So working remote is a dream come true.
I, the time that I would spend traveling to go to work to come from work can be spent
with my children.
And really there's, that's, there's no, there's nothing that compares.
It's it's the dream.
So though I do miss the social aspect of talking to people and that does, you know, is a downside.
There is an upside to being with my family.
You gotta pay somewhere.
You can't get everything for free.
Now people who don't have families, I'm sorry, but you know, I would even encourage you to
go to work.
Staying at home all day is not good for your mental health.
If you don't have families, even if you just have a wife and you don't have kids, it's
not good for you just to be at home all day, locked in a room, same room every day, nobody
around you.
That's that's not healthy.
And I would say try maybe, you know, going into work when they have those, uh, they have,
uh, pretty much every job has open desks for you to go in and work.
The problem there is if nobody else is there, then you're just in a bigger room alone and
you had to travel to get there.
So there is kind of an incentive in that way for companies to request people to come into
work so that people can see each other so that it gives incentive to people who want
to come in, maybe not all the time to come in.
It's a very difficult situation.
I understand the perspective as a work from home person who does not want to change it
because I have children.
I will say though, if I didn't have children, I'd be going back to work.
I would actually be going in.
I would probably get a different job that was closer to me.
So I didn't spend four hours traveling, but I would likely go into work, uh, because I
just, I love that social atmosphere of being with like-minded people working together,
that sort of thing.
It's, I just miss it.
So really the only reason I don't is my kids.
So that's, that's kind of the two sides of the coin.
I feel the upsides, like I said previously of working from home for, even for people
without kids are obvious, uh, lower cost of living.
For example, I lived in a high cost area and in 2020 I moved back to be with family and
just my entire, you know, extended family, uh, were really close.
So by doing that, my cost of living went way down and that was a huge benefit to me and
made it much more comfortable to raise my children.
Um, and to know that I could provide for them a home and everything else.
So there's just so many benefits from working from home.
Um, but I do get it and employees are not as productive as they could be in office.
This is why, if you remember before 2020, um, we work was booming.
I think it's dead now because of everything that happened, but it was booming because
people would leave home to rent a space in an office, even if it was by themselves, if
they're video editors or whatever, just because they made them more productive or maybe it
made them feel more productive.
I don't know, but I think going to have a space to work at, especially with others does
make you more productive in general.
It's a lot easier to talk to people.
Now at my last company, what we did is we had a discord channel and we had a, uh, kind
of a structure that segmented the programmers into five groups.
And my group would be in discord all day long and we had pushed to talk.
So we'd press a button and talk.
And it was kind of like being in the office because there was a lot of banter.
We made some jokes.
We made, you know, as, as employer, as employees do with each other, made inappropriate jokes,
made, uh, just, just had, you know, shooting the breeze and having a lot of fun.
But we also did of course, use that to talk about random problems.
So there wasn't a meeting barrier, uh, where we'd have to set up a meeting to talk about
something.
We just press a button and say, Hey, yo, you know, I have this problem.
You guys seen it, you guys know what's going on.
And they would just respond.
It was very simple.
Uh, also meetings, I think exploded.
I don't even want to get into meetings.
Anyone who has a job in programming knows meetings are useless.
Uh, I think it's just a pad the hours of the day and people, uh, they say, oh, I hate meetings
but then the, they make the meetings go really long because they don't want to get back to
work.
Uh, you know, get back to work.
Uh, they want to be able to go into the standup the next day and say, oh, you know, I had
meetings for this and that and that and this other meeting and, you know, meetings all
day.
So it was really hard to get anything done.
Um, that's, that's common.
It's not as common as my current job.
My last job, super common.
Their job I think is a lot more, um, streamlined and they're, they're pretty effective at kind
of managing those meetings, at least for me, others maybe not, but at least for me and
the one I work at has tons of remote workers.
They hire tons of people knowing they're out of state.
Even, uh, I'm out of state and you know, everybody on my, on the engine team is out of state
from the actual office.
So I think they've just, they're much more educated and well-versed in how to work with,
uh, work with remote people, manage the time and get things done.
So it is kind of up to the business.
If it's a big business, it's hard to do that.
So at big businesses, you're going to see big businesses calling people in the, at the
more medium sized ones, uh, you know, or sub studios, you're probably going to see a lot
more remote work.
So that's my long rant on remote work.
And like I said, it has emotional health, uh, benefits and negatives.
I think there's a lot of benefits for families, people with children.
I think that there's a lot of negatives for people who are just, you know, I don't want
to say alone, but you know, they, they're not married or they don't have kids.
Maybe their spouse goes somewhere else to work or their spouse is just in another room
all day.
I can see there being some, you know, severe downsides.
People are social.
We want to talk.
Um, you know, I talked to my son who can't really make a full, he can't even make a full
sentence, but there's a lot of social to that.
And I play with him and you know, it it's, I think I fill my social meter if we're talking
about the Sims, uh, pretty effectively with that.
So yeah, that's, that's kind of the perspective on remote work.
If you're a remote worker, get on a good for you.
But um, you know, I'm, I'm not into the whole rah, rah, let's rally together and never let
a, never let them make us, uh, come into the office ever again.
I think that there are huge benefits to be in the office, um, and a lot of scenarios
and a, you got to choose your battles and you've got to have the skills that are worth,
uh, worth it to the company to argue for remote work in my opinion.
So that's, that's the perspective on remote work.
Alright, due to there not being a whole lot of news today I suppose, everybody is talking
about Sega raising its price to $70 for games.
Now I have heard the argument, games have been the same price for many many years.
Uh huh, I hear ya.
I mean it has raised $10 once before and $10 again, I hear that argument.
It would be a valid argument if all the methods of distribution were exactly the same.
The difference is that all the methods of distribution have changed.
A lot of people buy digital.
I would probably think that most people buy digital.
Just look at Steam sales and those digital sales still being full box price is crazy
to me.
It's crazy that the price is so high.
It's crazy that we're going to $70, we're going to be at like $100 soon.
I get that there's inflation and the whole economy thing that's going haywire, but still
the $70 for a game, that's a lot of money for people.
You can imagine everybody from kids who just started working, who left their parents' house,
maybe they're starting their career and they're starting to work and develop their skills,
they want to go home and play games too.
You're kind of limiting them to buying one game a year or something like that.
You can't buy that many AAA games at $70 a pop in those scenarios.
I know because I had a minimum wage job to start and I couldn't even buy ice cream.
So in that scenario I'd have to save $70 somehow because I had rent and everything else to
pay so I wouldn't even be able to buy AAA games.
I've got to wait until they go on sale.
But then you have companies like Nintendo that just don't go on sale for whatever reason.
And since they never go on sale and they keep their games at their top price, even when
you want to buy used, you're paying like $52.
That's insane.
How are you going to play any of these games you really want to play in that perspective?
It's unheard of.
So raising it to $70, that's a $10 jump.
You have digital distribution.
It does not cost you the same that it would cost you to put a box on the shelf of a store
because you have to make all that box art, you have to produce it, you have to publish
it, you have to work with the warehouses and shipping and distribution and overseas shipping
and all of that sort of stuff.
You don't have to do that anymore.
You just click a button and download it.
And server space is cheap, man.
So many cloud providers competing in the space, it's cheap.
They're cheap.
Especially when you buy it at scale, it's incredibly cheap.
So going up to $70 for games, I feel like it's a real shame because I remember myself
in that scenario and this would have just made it so I couldn't play any games at all.
I'd have to play like the throwaway sports games that everybody has.
As a game collector, and if any of you collect games, you know exactly what I'm talking about,
the wall of sports games would be like all you could afford.
So I think another problem why the prices have gone up is the same thing with the companies.
They overstaff.
They over budget.
They spend way too much time managing and meetings and planning and JIRA and tasks and
all this sort of nonsense.
They waste so much money and hire way too many people to make a video game.
I can't compare games now to games from the 90s where you had like five dudes working
on it at Nintendo and they'd produce a hit title.
Of course, games are way more complicated now.
There's way more to them and there's a lot of higher expectations.
I get that.
But at the same time, back then they had to make their own tools to make it work.
Now you've got Unity, you've got Unreal Engine, you can do motion capture with pretty cheap
equipment now.
It's super cheap to do motion capture, to set up a motion capture studio.
Studios that work that just have one and just to have one or whenever they need it.
It's really inexpensive nowadays.
We're not talking like 50 grand to set up a mocap studio.
People can set up mocap with, I remember like six or almost, yeah, six or ten years ago,
somewhere in there, people were getting a whole bunch of, what are they called, the
Microsoft Kinect.
They're getting a whole bunch of those and you get like three or five of them and you
connect them together.
And you had a mocap basically that you sure had to clean up, but what mocap don't you
have to clean up?
And it's way cheaper now.
So it's way cheaper to produce.
You have all these tools made for you.
You don't need crazy, you don't need an army of engine programmers.
You just kind of, you know, you need game programmers and they use the tools that pre-exist
in the engine.
You have tons of tools from online.
You've got all the third party tools like Blender is free even.
You have Affinity or Adobe Photoshop and all that sort of stuff.
And you have AI now.
You have libraries of PBR materials.
Just so much stuff to accelerate your process.
Being in games, at least in the last company, it took us way too many years to develop a
game and that's because we remade it multiple times because it wasn't feeling right.
It wasn't hitting the KPIs.
So in that part, it's kind of your problem, the business problem to figure out.
And maybe with less people, you would have a more clear direction.
So $70 for a game, man, that's a tough bullet to bite, especially for me.
I can tell you right now, I have children.
I'm not going to be spending $70 on a game.
I will wait until that game goes on sale at my local game stores and I will buy it much
cheaper or I'll buy it on eBay.
I will not buy top dollar, $70 games.
Like the Legend of Zelda is out right now and I really want to play it.
First of all, I'm about to have a kid, so I can't.
But even so, I would much rather just wait some number of months to get it at a reasonable
price.
$70 is way too much.
That's like how much money I spend at the grocery store buying like five things.
So would I rather eat or would I rather play a game?
I'm going to choose to eat, sorry.
So hopefully people fight this and they just, I don't know, stop buying $70 games or just
only buy games on sales or third party because that's crazy.
That's crazy towns.
But companies Activision, Blizzard, Electronic Arts, Take-Two Interactive, which owns a lot
of companies by the way, PlayStation, Xbox, and even Nintendo have all raised their prices
and so and Sega now have all raised their prices to $70 and it's a shame.
That's my opinions on that.
If you have a strong opinion on it, let me know.
Maybe a counter argument and let me know why we should be paying $70 rather than companies
kind of fixing their staffing problem and all their other problems to reduce the cost
for them so that they can pass those savings on to the consumer.
That's my thoughts on that.
All right, so I'm going to wrap this up with a couple of shorter things.
So one is the Nintendo 64 controller for the Switch is now available.
I mention this because I missed out on it last time it sold out.
I missed out on the Super Nintendo controller and I bought both of those just now.
So I do want to play the emulator games on the Switch using the controllers I remember
from my childhood.
So that's going to be exciting.
If they're still in stock by the time this goes up tomorrow, tomorrow morning, hopefully
you can grab one if you also missed it.
And another topic that is near and dear to my heart is that Overwatch has canceled their
PvE hero mode.
And that sucks.
I mean, I'm pretty sure that's going to make tons of people angry.
Now, I haven't played Overwatch in some number of months now.
I was an avid player.
I've played it ever since it launched.
I have an Overwatch 2 poster that's signed by the developers because I loved playing
it so much, even with all its quirks and its biases and its angry players and all of those
sorts of things.
I loved Overwatch.
I loved the characters.
Didn't care much about the stories that they put out.
I'm not super into stories for games.
I also don't like it when they retcon a whole bunch of stuff just to please people.
So I just didn't pay attention to the story, but the gameplay was awesome.
The character, like the way the different characters would play, it was just a lot of
fun.
It was fun to play the characters.
Their character controllers were awesome.
Their networking, for some of its flaws, was pretty dang good, or is pretty dang good.
So I was super hyped about the PvE mode for Overwatch.
I don't know who else was.
I've played so much competitive matches and arcade modes that I was ready for a PvE mode,
something where you can have a character, you can essentially level them up, play with
other people, play with friends, randos, doesn't matter.
I thought it would be a lot less toxic.
If you've ever played competitive or any other part of Overwatch, you know it's crazy toxic.
You can be getting along with somebody just fine, one mistake and it's over.
They're just pissed.
They're just going to yell at you and they're going to scream and they're going to say,
it's all, I don't know, choose a character.
They're going to blame somebody.
They always blame somebody else, somebody but themselves.
Being a team game, if you're not being a team player, it's probably you.
But I don't know, the matches where you clicked with people and you had fun, and even if they
were close matches and you lost or whatever and people were still cool about it, that's
what I liked and it felt really good with that.
And I thought the PvE would be that.
I thought it would be that experience that I enjoyed so much from the online play, playing
with people who just were having fun and could cooperate and were just enjoying the game
and nobody was being toxic.
I thought that was going to be just amazing.
So they scrapped that and of course that probably means I won't play anytime soon anymore.
Like I said, I haven't been playing for a few months, but if they said, oh, PvE is launching
in a month, I would be right back into Overwatch, getting prepared after my new kid is born.
And man, that would have brought me back so fast, but man, it's just, I'm so disappointed.
That's the hard part is that I'm not angry.
I'm just disappointed because the game was great and I thought this would be so awesome.
You know, with all the team swapping and stuff they did internally at Blizzard, I can see
how these kinds of things happen.
Being on teams of programmers and game developers who've had that sort of thing happen in the
past, I get it.
Totally get it.
The developers themselves are probably super disappointed.
At the end of the day, it's a business, they've got to make money.
And the live services is what makes their money.
So super disappointed in that.
So that's a random topic on games.
And now to throw out something for the programmers.
This is going to be for the much more advanced programmers, for those of you who are interested
in multi-threaded applications and verifying your code.
If you haven't used, I guess it's a language, it's a logic checker, it's called TLA+, it's
been around for quite a while.
I'm a huge fan of the guy who made it.
Just him personally.
I can't remember his name off the top of my head.
I'm going to have to look it up.
But he works on algorithms.
He's a mathematician in the background.
Let's see, who made TLA+.
So he comes from this algorithms background.
And his focus was primarily on multi-threaded applications or intercommunication between
computers, parallel computing.
Leslie Lamport, how could I forget?
LL.
So TLA is a way for you to check your multi-threaded code.
I think it's kind of the root, his favorite algorithm that he came up with, the root of
it goes back to the bakery algorithm.
And I'll leave that to you to look up.
It basically has to do with a man going into the bakery and getting a ticket.
And there's a bunch of people with tickets and it's like a multi-threading program.
And it's an algorithm to solve that problem.
But TLA+, if you haven't used it, you should use it.
There's a funny story about it.
He works at Microsoft and Microsoft didn't start using it internally, rigorously until
Amazon published that they were using it and was making their web services so much better.
And if you're doing web stuff, if you're doing multi-threaded programming, check out TLA+.
It does use logic notation from mathematics.
It's in ASCII form.
So if you're going to do like an and or or, you've got to use the forward slash, back
slash to make the shape to do the logic.
But learning logic notation is not that complicated.
Just look it up on Wikipedia.
It's a pretty short read.
And I would highly suggest if you haven't used TLA+, this is a PSA, you don't see a
whole lot on it.
I would like you to check it out.
And I'll put the link to an article that I saw recently that got me thinking about it
that kind of talks about the two-phase pizza party.
And there's a step, I think it explains, I haven't read through the whole thing, but
it looks like it explains TLA+, in a basic way, to learn it.
So I'm going to be posting that in the description.
I'll put it on the Twitter, and go check it out if you're into multithreaded stuff, if
you're learning multithreaded stuff, if you do web things, check it out.
It's going to make your algorithms better, and it's going to help you a lot in solving
problems before they happen.
Lots of problems happen with concurrency on the web, and this is a great way to solve
that.
So that's it for today.
I know it was a lot of rant about jobs, but there's been a lot of things going on about
it.
There was that interview with Elon Musk, it really got me thinking about it.
And those are my perspectives on that.
I'd like to hear your perspectives, if you have any, how you feel.
I'm sure most of you have been doing remote work as developers, and I want to know what
you think, maybe from the perspective of somebody who doesn't have children, and how you feel
about that.
Because I remember I started remote work without children, and I thought it was the most incredible
thing in the world, but I don't know what it would be like a few years into it, and
still being, you know, not flying solo.
You may have had a girlfriend or wife or whatever, but kind of that aspect of it.
I'm really curious on your perspective on that, so let me know.
Anyways, have a good one, and bye for now.