Hello, and welcome to the first episode of whatever this might be.
I think I'm going to call it overnight assembly, because I like assembly programming.
It's one of those languages that are just a lot of fun to program in, and I do it at
night, so maybe that's what I'll call it.
Generally, what I want to talk about here maybe is my perspective as a programmer on
technology and computers and games and code and repositories and libraries and game engines
and whatever else.
I have a lot of opinions about a lot of things, but I also like to get the opinions of others
and kind of grow my understanding.
It is very common for programmers to be very biased about things.
We all have worked with programmers, I've worked with them for about 15 years, and we
all have strong opinions about a lot of things.
So I want to try not to be strongly opinionated.
I've changed a lot of my opinions over the years, and I feel like they're going to change
a lot more as we go, or as I go, on programming.
So yeah, that's kind of the general overview.
I also want to talk about games, I love games.
I have thousands of old games and new games.
I have a whole collection of almost every system, maybe, maybe half the systems, I don't
want to say that.
There's some that I don't have, just I collect a lot of the ones I'm interested in, and I
go on a spree of those type of games for a while.
So I just wound up with tons of games, some duplicates that I need to get rid of, but
there are quite a few games that I don't like because you get the games that you do want
instead of a lot.
Anyways, that's a topic for another day, so I'll be talking about old games, new games,
old computers, new computers, technology, who knows, just general things that I find
interesting in the game development and software development field.
So who am I?
I'm Brent.
I've been programming since about 2009.
I went to school for animation, so I know how to animate.
I know how to rig and 3D model.
I draw even, I do a lot of brush pen drawing and that sort of stuff.
But mostly I program.
I program a lot.
I've programmed too much.
I have a huge graveyard of projects because I program essentially the thing that I find
most interesting in the project and then I put it off into the GitHub graveyard.
Just that huge list of just things I'll probably never touch again, but it's there if I want
to.
So I'm currently a professional programmer.
I've been programming for almost 15 years.
I've been in web development, game programming, mobile programming, console programming, indie
programming, PC, all this stuff.
I've programmed stuff for the Game Boy.
I've programmed a little bit on the Game Boy Advance.
I've programmed a lot of third party consoles that are just, you know, people just release.
So just kind of, I just like programming on a bunch of different things and I love low
level code and I love the ease of high level code.
So I'm not partial to anything.
I bounce around quite often.
I'm currently a game engine programmer and an artificial intelligence programmer professionally.
So that's what I'm paid to do.
So yeah, sometimes it is hard to explain the things I'm interested in because I go all
over the place as you just saw.
But here's a not so complete list off the top of my head that I wrote down to kind of
explain the things that I bounce around in.
So there's going to be languages and frameworks and all this sort of stuff just to kind of
give a background of where I'm coming from and where a lot of my opinions on the future
episodes are going to be from.
This is kind of the source of my mindset.
So let's see, I've programmed in C, C++, x86, x64, the assembly languages, ARM assembly
including Thumb, 6502, the C64 and the NES variant of that, the Z80, the Game Boy variant
specifically, assembly code, C Sharp, I've done BIOS programming, GLSL, Java, JavaScript,
Python, Lua, HTML, CSS, XML, you know, those various markup languages, Bash, PowerShell,
OpenGL, DirectX, Direct2D, DirectWrite.
CUDA, I did CUDA for ray tracing, this little ray tracing project I did, I got like a 720p
rendering of like this ray traced scene at 30 frames per second.
It was a very simple scene, lots of spheres because spheres are easy.
And I got that done on a non, on like a 1070 or something, it was pretty nice.
I've dealt with SDL and Scriptum, Android, and Android NDK, Wasapi, if you don't know
what that is, it's a Windows audio, I forgot what the S stands for, it's not stack, it's
like sampling or something, API.
And I did that for a voice over IP thing and I was using C and I was integrating with it,
it was very much a C++ library but I was able to get like the GUID for the various devices
and there's a lot of GUID stuff, you just gotta get those in order to tell Windows,
hey, this is what I want to do.
So I've dealt with that, it was a very interesting kind of random project I did.
I've done network programming on Unity a long time ago, I made Forge Networking, I've since
archived it, I just didn't have the time to support that.
It got really popular at one point and I refactored it to Alloy but I never could finish it, way
too much stuff in life, including having kids.
That makes things a little complicated to kind of do a hobby project like that.
So I've done a lot of multi-threading, WebSockets, MySQL, Redis, Memcached, the various databases,
I've dealt with vertical databases as well as horizontal scaling databases like NoSQL
and all that.
Lots of, SQLite is basically the same thing, why not even put it on this list?
Frameworks like.NET, Node.js, game engines, I've done a lot of Unity, I've done quite
a bit of Unreal 4 and 5 now, and Godot is something I just recently started messing
around with, I've programmed my own game engines.
So that's kind of my perspective.
I jump around a lot, I've done a lot of assembly and low-level stuff but a lot of high-level
stuff in game engines like Unreal and that sort of stuff.
So I love jumping around, oh and lots of web, I've done lots of web, JavaScript stuff, JavaScript
games, all that sort of stuff.
I love to prototype in JavaScript, it's just so fast and easy.
And I have some libraries that I just use, I've been using modules a lot lately, which
is a lot of fun.
I do like modules quite a bit, rolling them up into a single file and all that is annoying,
but modules are a lot of fun, I can definitely say that.
So that's kind of all of that, and I kind of mentioned this, but the most important
thing about me is that I'm a father and a husband, that's what makes my life happy.
So other than that, that's kind of my whole background and kind of my perspective on opinions.
Now one thing that I'm not, unfortunately, is one of those ex-Google employees.
I'm sure you've seen all of those YouTube videos out there that are like, ex-Google
employee blah blah blah blah blah, it says something like that.
I don't know if they do that for like Clickbait or Cloud or something like that.
Google has a lot of employees, so I mean there's a lot of ex-employees now that are all getting
fired.
I'm sorry, I'm not attacking anyone with that.
I'm not one of those, I've never worked at a gigantic company, mainly because I don't
want to.
The more smaller companies, they can sometimes pay more, and also you get a lot of equity,
so you can get a lot in the long run out of it, versus those big companies.
And frankly, I've had a lot of friends who've gone to those big companies, and it's just
boring.
They say that they chill outside, they disappear for a week, and nobody even notices.
They just hardly do any work, and if they do, it's something super minor, kind of just
maintaining stuff.
There's a small group of people that actually do the hard work.
And of course, if you're a programmer, which you likely are, I don't know who would be
watching this that doesn't like to program or is interested in games.
You know the industry has a lot of leads and managers and those sorts of people that don't
really program a lot.
You can have a lead engineer, and they don't do a lot of programming.
The one that I work with does a lot of programming, but typically, especially at the big places,
you can get some that hardly ever program, ever, even on their free time.
So I'm not one of those ex-Google employees says, XYZ.
I like to do work, and I like to participate in a team.
Maybe there's a role somewhere at one of those places that is more research-based or something
like that that I can take advantage of and have a lot of fun with.
But maybe in the core, like operating system part of the business, I'm not sure.
But I don't have any one of those flashy name tags.
I've released lots of games with companies, mobile.
I'm currently working on a console game.
So I've bounced around a lot.
So I kind of want to learn more about a lot of other fields.
I've done so many things roll in my mind whenever I think about those, but we'll probably go
over a lot of these in future episodes, just things that are interesting in programming
and computers and tech and all that sort of stuff.
So yeah, speaking of those ex-Google employee gives you advice on how to get hired or whatever
kind of videos, I don't ever click on them, I don't know why they keep sending them to
me.
But I don't know if you see them, maybe it's just me.
I don't know.
I get a few of them.
I always have to hide the channel or whatever because they pop up.
It's almost like clockwork.
Another thing that I like to do is I like to program very small.
I like very small programs, I like very fast programs, I like elegant code and elegant
functions, very small functions, that sort of stuff.
And if you look at what these big companies produce, they produce simple libraries and
their apps, they have tens of thousands of classes that make up, I don't know if it's
like code generation or what, but they've got tens of thousands of classes, which is
insane to me.
That's a lot of something.
Half of them probably don't know what it is.
Half of them are probably third-party libraries, which is even worse.
And their size is huge, hundreds of megabytes.
And even worse, if you think about a lot of these apps, a lot of people complain about
Google, a lot about their apps.
The experience of YouTube on iPhone is different from Android, which is different from Android
tablet, which is different from the web.
And you'd imagine when we use web technology across devices, I know it's a little bit more
complicated with the iOS ecosystem and how they want to handle with all that and web
views and all that sort of stuff, it gets annoying.
But they invested millions and millions of dollars in V8 to kind of build this platform
they can work off of.
And their apps are just broken across, I mean, their function, but they're just missing features
across the different devices.
You know, that's kind of crazy to me.
Got so much money.
Don't you think they can consolidate it?
I don't know.
I don't know kind of what they set up.
I do know how most teams operate.
I can see how it happens.
But yeah, it's really fractured.
So that's another thing I don't really want to work with is when you go to those big companies
and you got to deal with cross disciplines and all this other stuff, as it's called cross
disciplines.
And you got to deal with all of like, you can't merge two things and you got to deal
with the bureaucracy.
I like small teams where you can just move around.
You can say, I want to work on that.
And they said, cool, we can figure out, you know, if it works with our product, let's
figure out how we get you over there.
That's what I like about smaller companies too.
It's just, it's really nice.
So yeah, I mean, so it's not just Google and software companies like that.
It's game companies too.
Working in game companies and kind of seeing the games that are produced is crazy.
Of course, it's not a fair comparison to say, look at games from the 90s and 80s and they
have so little bugs compared to modern games and they have, you know, they're so much faster
and smaller, blah, blah, blah.
It's not fair because there's a lot of stuff in modern games, crazy amount of stuff in
modern games.
So I give it some slack there.
I do believe that the programmers were much more disciplined in the past because they
had to be working with low level code just with no other option.
So there are differences and similarities in some aspects, but games, man, like the
minimum requirements for games is pretty dang high.
Of course, luckily computers are getting way cheap now.
So pretty much anyone can muscle through and punch through the wall of system requirements
these days.
Like you can run tons of AAA games on something like a Steam Deck.
So you know, sure, they have all the compute power to really muscle through it, but they
make some weird decisions.
Like why are games like 200 gigabytes?
That's crazy.
So we come up with this frame scaling technology, FSR, that sort of stuff.
And then you still put 4K textures in your game and your game is being rendered at like
720p pretty much most of the time or 1080p, but you're putting 4K textures in.
And then we don't know what's the amount of people that have 4K monitors versus, you know,
1080p monitors.
And I would imagine that you can kind of detect that and you can have Steam kind of upgrade
the game based on, you know, what kind of monitor they have.
But you can't, if you have a 4K texture and you're displaying it on a 1080p monitor, that's
just, it doesn't even, it's crazy.
Like it's bigger than the screen in resolution.
And so then you add FSR in the mix and now the 4K monitors aren't even rendering at 4K.
And to make the most of it, of course, you know, this is being a little pedantic because
you can have one texture that goes across multiple objects and you want that to be 4K
in order to optimize your memory and how much you're loading at runtime.
Yes, I get that.
But man, how many textures are actually that versus, you know, a giant 4K rock texture
that they just splatter on rocks?
It's kind of funny, I guess for stretching and stuff.
I don't know, I really think there's a huge waste in memory there.
And it's kind of, you know, so it's not just Google and big software companies that just
absolutely waste your CPU and your storage.
It's games too, a lot of times.
And I think those can be better optimized, but you know what?
The game is about money.
The game of making games is about making money for, I mean, mostly.
It's having fun is sometimes what the designers care about, even though they've got to make
the investors happy.
But 4K textures are kind of going crazy right now.
I think we can probably reduce a lot of that and rely more on the FSR stuff.
It's just, you know, I think that's, yeah, there's a whole rant there.
There's also, when it comes to wasting, and we're going to combine the two now, we're
going to take software and we're going to combine it with games and what they both do
wrong.
One of the things I hate, hate is a strong word, one of the things I strongly dislike
is JSON.
I mean, it's fantastic.
And the argument is always, what if we need to read it and modify it?
But the funny thing about that is they try to compress JSON so it becomes unreadable.
It's just an unreadable garbled mess because you're trying to reduce the string sizes as
you try to compress this data.
So you lose the readability and it's still bloated.
And then your CPU has to pay the cost of parsing it.
Well, first of all, serializing it.
So it takes this binary data, serializes it, and it's got to pay somebody else's poor computer's
going to take the cost of deserializing it, parsing it, turning it back into binary objects.
And then you have to also transport it across the wire.
And then we have to use compression algorithms, so using more CPU to compress that, the strings,
which they can get pretty compressed just with a standard zip algorithm.
And then you want to send that, and then you've got to decompress it.
So I have this theory that JSON files alone, like if you took all of the energy, all of
the power that we use in our computers and our smartphones to parse and read and do all
of that and transmit and zip JSON data, you could probably give an entire small country
somewhere, power for free, because that's how much is being wasted.
And then you can add up all the heat that the CPUs generate by parsing and doing all
that, just that cumulative over like a month or something, every device that does it, and
you could probably heat an entire small country with that amount of heat.
So it's a waste.
It's a weird thing to think about.
We complain a lot about, oh, you know, crypto mining, using tons of energy, blah, blah,
blah.
It's bad for the environment.
Well, you know what else is bad for the environment?
Using JSON files for everything.
When you can simply and easily just serialize binary, where you just take binary, make it
basically into a file and send it.
And you can do whatever compression you want if you want to, but binary is already smaller
than JSON.
So yeah, all the crypto miners wasting tons of power
across the planet, yeah.
You know what else is wasting power?
JSON deserialization, my goodness.
JSON deserialization of 4K textures.
Let's get those reduced and let's save the environment
from just taking those out of the picture.
So yeah, that's kind of my perspective on,
how did I get on this?
Let's talk about Google people on YouTube,
or ex-Google people.
So anyways, yeah, it's just super wasteful.
The entire industry is very wasteful in how they do things.
And I know we don't all use C,
but in C you can just take a struct,
or even a compound struct of plain old data,
let's say there's no pointers,
or even if you just write a little function
to get rid of the pointers.
I mean, I would argue that if you're gonna be
serializing data and there's gonna be pointers in there,
if you have to have them in there,
you should separate them into their own structure
so you can easily strip it out,
or put it as like a head and then do the offset
so you can find the offset of where the POD starts,
POD for plain old data, and then just write it.
But in C you can just take that struct
and just write to a file or across the network.
You don't have to do any compression or serialization
or anything like that, you just,
here's a struct, it's a set of data, and send it off.
And that's how much energy you'd save
from doing that, it's quite tremendous.
But I know we don't all use C.
I know C is, I didn't say it,
but C is my favorite language.
It's just, I love it,
because I can use it in a lot of things,
like Game Boy Advance programming.
So it's just nice and flat,
and I don't have to worry about objects,
I'm a very simple man.
But let's say you're doing C++,
and I do a lot of C++,
obviously my day job is programming in C++.
So in C++, yes, you do have a little bit of a problem,
because you don't have an ABI,
you don't have a standard for ABI,
so you don't know if application binary interface,
basically the byte order of a class or a struct.
So, I guess I can explain that real quick,
for those of you who don't know.
In C, you have this flat ABI,
and now I don't wanna get too much into alignment
and all that sort of stuff,
because you do have to do some work there,
if you're dealing with things like that.
If you're, say, serialize,
if you're sending something
from a 64-bit computer over to,
I don't know, a 16-bit computer,
you're definitely gonna have to do a little bit of work
on that.
But let's say that you set up your struct
with the proper alignment and all that,
in C, you could just send it straight across,
and knowing that maybe your smallest
or minimum spec is 16,
there's gonna be, did I say byte?
16 bits.
So, you can,
let's say that you want to do that,
I've lost my train of thought,
that alignment,
and let's say you have all that,
you can send it straight across.
Now, one of the problems you have in C++
is that it doesn't have that ABI across compilers,
and even compiler versions,
like if you use Clang X and then you use Clang Y,
it's not guaranteed that the name mangling or the,
which doesn't matter in this argument,
but the ABI is gonna be the same.
And that's because,
mainly I think it's because of the Vtable.
A Vtable is a piece,
is a block of your class for virtual classes
where they point to the function it should call
when you call a function.
As you know, you can create a virtual function,
you can override those functions in the child classes,
or the derivatives, whatever you wanna call them.
Now that Vtable could be at the top,
it could be right in the middle of the binary data,
it could be at the end of the class,
there's no telling where that is.
So just serializing and sending it off
is gonna be a little bit of a problem.
And that's where serialization libraries start coming in.
You have other languages where you don't have access
to the raw binary of the class
without turning on special flags
or whatever for the compiler,
like in C Sharp or say JavaScript or something like that.
So sending things straight over,
like you do in C, is not as easy.
And so I do understand that part of where we get into this.
This whole, let's JSON serialize it,
because then I can write my program in C Sharp
and then have a JavaScript client be able to read the data.
And I don't have to worry about,
I don't have to worry about Indian-ness,
or I don't have to worry about, you know,
the alignment or anything like that.
So yeah, it does kind of really help
and it does kind of reduce the cost of effort up front
to do those kind of like, just use a JSON library.
But it's so wasteful.
I think that if you just, it's really,
programs, companies have this weird thing
where they think that it takes months
to do something as simple as serializing some bytes.
They're like, I don't know if that fits into the schedule.
Man, that's a whole other thing.
Let's not go on that.
But yeah, I do understand that, you know,
it's a cost analysis.
No company, I can tell you this,
I've worked at so many different companies,
no company, none of them care about how much power
you're drawing from a wall socket to run their program.
And as long as it's fast and it gets the player,
the client, what they need.
Now this is a different argument for mobile.
In mobile, they sometimes do care
because they want good battery life.
I don't want to say excellent battery life,
otherwise they wouldn't use engines that drain battery life.
They would, you know, write their own stuff.
But they do care a little bit there.
So I'll give them credit on that.
So this brings us to things like,
gosh, what's it called, protobuf.
Okay, protobuf does help you
with that binary serialization.
Now I didn't go through the entirety of the class
or all the classes to determine
whether the binary serialization is efficient.
I assume it's efficient because it's open source
and a lot of people have looked at it
and probably have contributed.
And I do, I know I prefixed this earlier
about Google employees and all that sort of stuff.
It's not to say they're bad programmers.
It's just, you know, there are some bad programs
that come out of Google, a lot of bad programs
that come out of Google.
And it's not the fault of the programmer most of the time,
it's the fault of the company.
So they do have good programmers that do study this stuff
and take the effort and they do the research
and all this other stuff,
which is very important to everybody,
especially when you open source it.
So no complaints from me there.
But protobuf is like hundreds of thousands of lines of code
to serialize some bytes and that is huge.
I have this thought about libraries
and even programmers just inside of a company.
Programmers are often stuck to doing a specific type of work
on these big companies.
So I like to say that if you took a person
and you paid them a pretty good amount of money
and you gave them a rock in the corner of a room
and you said, your job is to manage this rock,
the best thing that person could do
is not do anything.
The rock is gonna be completely fine.
But chances are you're gonna come back two weeks later
and the rock is gonna have a little house set up
with a little dinner table
and it's gonna be laying inside of a little bed
with a blanket over it.
And then once you ask the developer how he's going,
he's gonna say, oh, well, you see,
I've optimized the living situation for this rock
and I've also created a Jira workflow
so that we can keep track of its schedule.
And that's just how people are
when you pay them a good amount of money
and tell them to do something.
They overdo it every time
because maybe it's because they're bored
and they need something to do
and the task wasn't interesting enough
so they go way off the wall
or maybe they're trying to prove something,
they want a higher salary or maybe a different position
so they really kind of polish the rock, so to speak.
So I feel that's the case for a lot of libraries.
You set a library out there, let's say a logging library,
and it does sufficiently what you need it to do
for your program.
So then all of a sudden,
I don't know, it gets picked up by somebody
on a YouTube video or something
and then everybody's using it.
All of a sudden you have half a million people
downloading or half a million downloads
of your software.
Half a million people downloading or half a million downloads
on your library.
You all of a sudden turn over and say,
man, there's a lot of people downloading this library.
I need to improve it.
And so you start going in there
and you start adding tons and tons of features
that are not needed at all.
Remember that you got half a million downloads already.
That means it does what people want.
Of course they're gonna come and complain.
The other part is, and this is not the fault
of the person polishing the rock,
this is the fault of the people
who are using their libraries.
People often think that if a library is not updated
in the past month or half a year,
it's all of a sudden just broken.
You can't use this.
It's just, ugh, it doesn't work anymore.
The code just rotted itself out of existence
from sitting there for too long.
I don't know.
And there's a lot of pressure on that
to keep them updating and doing things like that.
Now, also you have open source,
so you have hundreds of people sending issues
and also pull requests and you start accepting things.
It just bloats.
And so this is what happens with libraries.
And I don't think Protobuf is any exception to this.
I just wanna serialize some bytes.
And so Protobuf is quite bitty.
Here, let me look up the Protobuf here.
So we have the protocol buffers.
And I'll actually just, is this the main library?
Looks like it.
It was updated five hours ago.
This thing worked like five years ago or whatever
when I was using it, but it's still being updated.
And five years later, it's some serious business
taking some bytes and putting them
into a file across network.
And I know I'm simplifying it.
I've done tons of network stuff.
I get it.
Half the time, you don't even use Protobuf
for network stuff, so there's that.
But we're gonna, I'm just gonna,
I'm gonna grab this guy.
Hold on, I've gotta turn off a thing on my computer
that talks to me whenever I copy text.
Okay, so I'm gonna grab this guy
and we will go ahead and,
we'll go ahead and clone it down somewhere.
Put it in a document, documents.
Go to git, git clone that guy.
So we'll clone it down and let's take a look
at where the source code is for this guy.
And of course, a lot of the source code
is gonna be in language wrappers
and that might be where half the updates
are coming from is language wrappers, I don't know.
But you got C-sharp, Java, Python, Ruby, Rust, blah, blah, blah.
So it's probably gonna be in the source folder
and in this Google Protobuf here.
So it's still downloading, but let's take a little
Ubuntu local instance here
and let's go over to,
let's go to, what is it?
Mount C user brand documents git.
And this is gonna be inside of Protobuf.
And then if we go inside of this folder,
so cd to source, cd to Google, cd to Protobuf.
So here we are inside of Protobuf
and we're gonna do a little experiment here
if I type it right.
So we're gonna find dot, we're gonna do a reg x.
I have this written down because I am not,
you know, the most incredible person
at remembering all these Unix or Linux commands.
One of the beautiful things about Linux
is that programs do a single thing and they do it well.
I love that.
That's the best design decision anyone could have.
In fact, I think I can, let me copy.
I think I can just copy this text
and paste it into the terminal here.
I know I can.
Whoop, it looks like I got a weird binary thing
at the beginning there.
Let me see if it's because the way I copied it.
No, here, let's just go to, nope.
You can't see it off screen,
but I have this inside of a little word or something.
Okay, f, there we go.
So I'm gonna do this reg x to just get all the headers,
cc, cfiles, and cpp files,
because this is a C++ repository.
I'm gonna do print zero instead of print
so that I can do x arg zero.
I'm gonna do basically a line count.
I'm gonna count the lines in this project.
So just to serialize bytes in one language
is over a quarter million lines of code.
And I don't know if some of those lines
are comments or whatever,
but this, I've written a game engine
that uses Vulkan and all in C.
So I've gotta do the Vulkan library in C,
and then it works with entities,
and it has all the transformations,
all that sort of stuff, including the shaders,
and it's less lines of code than this,
and it has tons of comments too.
So over a quarter million lines of code
is a lot of code for serializing some bytes.
And that's kind of where I'm coming from on this.
And if we go to the wrappers,
hopefully they're not as big.
Let's take a look at, let's say C sharp.
There's a lot of batch files in here.
Keys, vtest, okay, here we go, source.
Okay, so C sharp, source, and then of course we've got,
what are all these, tests?
Eh, let's just do the whole thing.
Life is short.
So this is much easier, we can just do CS files.
So this one alone is 142,139.
And this is a wrapper to like call.
I don't know if they re-implemented the code in C sharp,
or if they're calling the C++ code here.
Not a percent sure.
But still, it's a lot of code to write some bytes.
So that's kind of my perspective on big companies.
Their code bases, libraries.
I thought this is a nice simple way
to start off whatever series I'm doing here.
It's just talk about some code, I like code.
And I'm not, like I said, I'm not complaining
about all this, it all functions, I've used it.
It makes things a lot easier.
Companies should use them rather than rolling their own
because most likely you're gonna make a mistake
if you roll your own.
And you gotta deal with all that debugging and stuff.
I'm just putting out a hypothesis,
hypotheses or ideas here about how much power is wasted
and kind of how programmers polish rocks.
And I polish rocks all the time.
So yeah, and I think that's,
yeah, that's all I got for my view
on just coding, programming, third party libraries.
I don't know exactly what I'm gonna go over
in kind of future, what are these,
future podcasts I guess these are.
Not 100% sure what I'm gonna go over.
I can go over assembly for Game Boy games,
I can kind of dive into other people's code,
I can just talk about games in general and game design.
I have a lot of ideas or thoughts on game design.
And I'm trying not to ramble on them here.
And I've got lots of thoughts
of how we connect software together
from straight from the hardware in the C and C++ area
or whatever low level language that you use
or like all the way up to how it communicates
with a web server.
Yeah, I think that there's just a lot to think about,
a lot to talk about.
A lot to talk about and a lot to have fun with.
So this is like the first episode of this podcast
and I don't know how many people are gonna watch it
or people are even gonna see it.
But if you guys do exist, feel free to like throw out
some ideas of what to talk about
because like I said, it doesn't have to be just about code.
I love code, I could talk about code all day.
And it's been like 40 minutes,
I didn't even notice this time flew by.
But I could talk about games and game design, old games,
collecting games, I collect a lot of games.
I could talk about art, art as it relates to programming
or games or just art in general, I like to draw.
So I have a lot of thoughts on that sort of stuff.
So yeah, it'd be really interesting to see
if anybody has some ideas of what to look over.
I thought this was a lot of fun.
I like talking about code, this is awesome.
Anyways, see you guys.