All right, welcome back. Today I learned that Valve is getting sued for the Steam Deck.
Other than that, I wanted to talk about private chats, some AI stuff, some local AI stuff,
clean code and GitHub and that sort of stuff. So I guess the very first thing straight off,
I just learned about it a minute ago, was that Valve is now getting sued or, I don't
know, a lawsuit has been filed for the Steam Deck and you may be wondering what on earth
could it be over? And that's exactly what I was thinking. And it's for a patent. No,
Steam didn't, or Valve didn't just blatantly copy a patent or steal it or anything like
that. It's just that Valve is falling prey to a patent troll. If you don't know what
a patent troll is, it's basically a consortium of people who buy up software and hardware
patents and they produce nothing themselves. They just sit around on their thumbs doing
nothing other than they had some money to buy some ideas from people that were probably
smarter than they are. Or maybe they're not as smart as they are because they're the ones
who bought all the patents. And essentially what they do is they sue everybody and force
them to pay them royalties. And the patent that I didn't even know was a patent is haptics.
So the little vibrations that you feel on basically everything from phones to controllers,
those apparently are patented by some dudes somewhere who had enough money to buy the
patent and then do nothing other than sit there and reap rewards of everyone else's
success. I'm a little annoyed at it. I've always disliked patent trolls. I think the
way that I put it on Twitter was the idea guys that do nothing and sit in mom's basement
and perhaps all the other guys went off and they made something successful, but this dude
had equity so he's just going to reap the rewards for existing. It's very annoying.
It sucks. I think it stifles innovation. That's basically my take on that. In fact, here we
can take a look at it. Here I have the link. This is from The Verge. You can see, well,
it's night for you, morning, or it's night for me, morning for you. This just happened
a minute ago. The company is called Immersion Corporation. And that right there, that name
kind of gives away the game. Immersion Corporation sounds like we bought up all the patents for
haptics that we could find on the internet and are going to sue everybody into the ground
and otherwise force them to pay us royalties and also give us a big chunk of change right
at the beginning underneath the table. Otherwise, we're going to sue you. It's really annoying.
Immersion Corporation, I even looked up who the heck is Immersion Corporation and it's
just a bunch of flashy videos of phones and stuff. They produce nothing as far as I can
tell on here. Just some company that I would dare say stole patents with money. Stole it
with money. Anyways, that's really annoying. It happens to the best of us. Valve is probably
just going to pay them the money under the table or out of the court to skip the lawsuit
and just pay them royalties. I'm a little miffed about that. I don't know if other people
have the same feelings about it. I'm sure a lot of people are ambivalent to it. It just
annoys me, the guys who do nothing and prey on others. It's a little... Anyways, well
that's that. One of the things I wanted to go over today other than that, since that
popped out of nowhere, was private messages. Twitter recently released their secure messages.
I think that they were in talks with the guys from Signal and they produced their untrustable
or the don't trust it yet messaging system. That's just something that they mentioned.
Don't trust it yet, give it a try though. Now, I'm not a Twitter hater or I don't know
whatever bandwagon people have about all that. What I like is that there are private messages
at all, secure messages at all. A company like this does not have to add secure messaging
to their app. They could just go on being completely insecure. That's not great for
the people. It doesn't actually... Look, nobody is saying, I'm going to make a Twitter account
now because the messages are secure. I'm pretty sure most people don't even use Twitter direct
messages. I've never even used it. I'd like to use it now that it's secure. I'd like to
see what it looks like. Is there a little padlock or something? I'm curious. Not something
I'm going to jump ship from. I use Signal for all of my private messages with my family,
both my immediate family, like my wife and I almost exclusively talk on Signal. I have
a family group chat on there where I talk with all of my family. Sure, it does use up
a lot of your storage because it's locally stored. That's the whole point is that it's
not stored on somebody's server somewhere. I'm probably not going to be jumping ship
off of Signal anytime soon, maybe even ever. It all depends on where they take it. Companies
like this can promise the world and then swap out from underneath you to doing something
else. I think, though I like Telegram, I don't actively use it because it's hosted on somebody's
server somewhere and they kind of just promise security and safety and that sort of stuff.
You can trust it. Lots of people do. They could be telling the truth. I do like the
idea of it all being locally on my device, even if it is a little bit of an annoyance,
taking up the space and then having to make backups and then not being able to transfer
it to another device like my desktop. There are annoyances for it not being a server.
I would host my own or make my own little messaging app for my family. I've done Diffie
Hellman encryption, the whole process of updating the key on every message and all that sort
of stuff for fun. Making a whole app that my whole family is willing to jump on and
even friends and new friends are willing to jump on, it's not going to happen. It's a
lot easier for me to just use Signal. Moral of the story here is that I love that Twitter
is moving towards these secure DMs. Everything should be secure DMs. It's just out of respect
for the people who use your platform. All in all, they are trying to advertise to you
and you never know what's going on in the background. I think these are also on the
server kind of obviously. Same difference between the Twitter DMs and what's the one
Facebook owns, that one, and Telegram and all of those. So stick with Signal because
it's local. Signal does store it on a server until it gets delivered and confirm that it's
delivered. So there is that little middleman aspect there. It's kind of like a cousin of
mine. He said he loves Apple because of their secure messages. And then I asked him, I was
like, well, you know, they do have secure messages, but if you buy a new phone, you
get all of your old messages out of nowhere. That means that all the messages were stored
on some server and they can be decrypted on a different device. Just the different device
that exists, that just so happens to exist with your phone number. I don't know if it's
locked to your phone number or anything. So you can get all of your old messages and they
all get decrypted. So that right there just means that it exists somewhere and it can
be decrypted. So security is in the promise, I suppose, on that. But yeah, that was my
thoughts on Twitter secure DMs. If anyone exists out there that wants to try it out,
send me a message on Twitter. And yeah, thank you. So that's basically it for the secure
messaging stuff. I don't want to go on too much of a rant for that. Now, I did want to
talk about some AI stuff. As you know, I deal with AI stuff for fun. I like making random
prompts, that sort of stuff. Nothing serious. So I am not up to date on all the crazy newness
and all the things people are doing now and the tricks and that sort of stuff. So I just
learned about GPT4ALL today, which was pretty neat. If you haven't heard of it, it's basically
a local instance of these different models that you can run locally on your computer
without internet. And depending on your computer's processing power, it'll be slower or faster.
And you don't need a GPU to run it. I think that's because most of the training happens
through GPUs. But this is not training it. I think there is a way to train your own stuff,
which would be pretty cool. You'd take all the documents you've ever written or maybe
all the transcripts of all your videos or something like that and train the model on
it to be kind of like a mini-you, which would be kind of neat to see. But I like it just
for its local instance. So I wanted to point that out. I wanted to show which model I'm
using because the website itself says that this is the good model. So let's see if I
can zoom in. Oh, I can't zoom in. It's GPT4ALL JV1.3 Groovy. And if you go to GPT4ALL, here
let's just grab this and stick it up here, on their website they just boast about its
features. If you can't find the model you want, they do have this little drop-down that
tells you about the different models. So the one that's already selected is the one that
I downloaded. For me it was the second from the top, but I'm sure those shift around.
And it's the current best commercially licensable model based on GPT-J. And commercially licensable,
the reason that there is a distinction on these is that you can actually run a server
with this local instance. And you can run Python scripts to query against it and act
as like a client. And you can serve up servers and like make money using it and all that
sort of stuff. However, these models are licensed. Somebody did all the effort in training them.
So this particular one you can pay somebody, I guess, to use it if you want to use it commercially.
There are other ones like this Snoozy one, current best non-commercial commercially licensable
model. And the reason for that is that this is based on Llama13b, which is I think the
Facebook leaked stuff. So that's why you can't be like, yo, Facebook, I'm going to use that
thing that got leaked from your company. Can I give you a couple bucks? So obviously you
can't do that. But yeah, go give this a try. I was playing around with it on my laptop,
which is a Linux laptop with an Intel 11th Gen Tiger Lake, I think. It's not, yeah, Tiger
Lake processor. And it was fast enough. It was pretty decent. It wasn't like incredibly
slow. You'll try some of these offline ones and they're super slow. It was decently fast.
I haven't tried it on this computer yet, this laptop, much more beefy 12th Gen Intel core
processor. So I would be surprised if this one wasn't even faster. So yeah, go give this
a shot and try out that model. It's the second from the top for me, like I said, just review
it on the website and pick the model that you find most interesting. Another thing that
I learned about today, like I said, I'm just passively an AI person, prompter, whatever.
I don't make images or anything. I just like to prompt it and see what kind of stuff it
comes up with and cross-reference it or cross-check it. I don't know, check its work and that
sort of stuff. I do like to generate very small scripts that I really am too lazy to
write. So an example of a script that I wrote that I modified, I asked the AI to write it
for me, was a Lua script that took in a text file and this text file had time marks and
then text of what was being said at those time marks. And it converted it into an SRT
file, which is just a closed captioning kind of timing file that prints out the text that's
being said at that timestamp. So I just told it to write me that script and it busted one
out, had a couple of mistakes in it. It didn't check for blank lines and that sort of stuff
that I just quickly knocked it out and fixed it. And also added a little extra feature
so it would spit out an extra text file, which was just the raw text of what was said without
timestamps. So I do play around with these for all sorts of things, stories and code
and all that. But something I learned about today was super prompts, which is an awesome
name. I do love when names are nice, like, I don't know, fun, fun like this. Some names
can be really boring, like they're just named after people. Like some of these models like
Ada or DaVinci or whatever. Cool, you named it after a person. But super prompt, that's
awesome. I mean, super is used for a ton of things. Basically, you can probably be sued
by Nintendo by putting super in front of stuff. They've used it so much. But I don't know,
I like the title of it. So what I learned about the super prompt today is basically
you either set up a really big prompt, it's this huge prompt that uses almost all of your
tokens. And if you don't know what a token is, it's essentially you get 4096 tokens or
so depending on the service you use and what you pay for and all that. And each, about
a third of each word is a token. So just say like each word is a token. And it really depends.
It could be the characters if you're using UTF-8 or whatever, and you're using foreign
characters it may be per character that's presented. But generally in English I think
what they stated is it's on average about 75% of a word. And you can have up to 4096
of these tokens. And then when you hit that limit it won't respond or it just doesn't
know what to do. Often it'll say too much text or whatever. The webpage or whatever.
Even the local ones do this. They'll say, I filed too long or something like that. But
you can either pre-prompt it with one gigantic prompt and have it try to say things it shouldn't
say. Some people try to make it say bad words or whatever. But others try to make it sound
even more human or like you're talking to some specific character in history and making
it kind of reply as if it was that person. So the super prompt isn't always just the
one big prompt in the beginning. It's also you're able to do it by feeding it multiple
prompts over and over and kind of building out this super context I'll call it. I don't
think it's called super context but I'm going to call it super context. And what people do is they call it hypnosis.
They hypnotize the AI so to speak by repeating things they've previously said in varied ways
in order to kind of shepherd it into a certain direction. And that's just so that they can
hit the neurons that aren't often hit on the fringes of the, I don't know what to call
it, AI matrix mind. And then you can get some pretty cool responses. You can see kind of
the depth of its understanding of things. So those are kind of fun. That's what I learned
about today, super prompting. So go try to super prompt. Maybe you've done it without
even noticing that you've done it. Here I've just for completeness I asked Bing what a
super prompt was. And this was his response. You can pause to see this. I guess if you're
doing an audio only podcast. It says the super prompt is a term used in the context of chat
GPT. I don't know if it's specific to chat GPT. I just know it's used commonly with chat
GPT and other similar language models. It refers to a prompt that is designed to generate
a more advanced and complex response from the model. Super prompts are used to train
the model and generate more sophisticated responses that are closer to human-like conversation.
They're usually more detailed and specific rather than prompts that can include multiple
parts or sub parts. And these prompts can get long, by the way. So I think somebody
recorded like, I don't know if it was 16 minutes or 16 hours for chat GPT to respond with one
of these super prompts. And it was pretty neat. So go try super prompts today.
So we're going to jump from AI. We're going to talk more about some programming stuff.
As you know, I'm a programmer. I love code. I code all the time. I code as a day job.
I love code so much that I make this podcast and I include code stuff because I just love
code. So.
You may have noticed a huge trend in the last few years of people moving to clean code
I want to use quote clean code
or people moving towards
You know
craftsmanship
clean
architecture all the stuff all these buzzwords and
Clean code is basically like testable code test driven development for some people
Tiny functions
Making every making it so that your code doesn't need comments to explain itself anybody can read it
And I like to throw design patterns in there because it's not often said with clean code for some reason as far as I've seen
But there's some really good design patterns that help you create clean code. My favorite design pattern is
the visitor pattern and
Visitor pattern and that's basically where you can create a system that executes
some unknown
maybe
structured concept it's hard to explain and
You pass it a class or you pass it a function and that's the mechanic that it runs
The context that it runs within so in that way you can have this
Core system that does a specific thing and you can alter it by passing in a class with certain functions or functions
themselves to change the behavior while keeping that one particular
Piece of code. So I think an easy example would be like rather than using inheritance to say there's an animal and from the animal
there is or there's a being which
Animal derives from and then you have a dog and a cat and they both have speak and they do a different response
instead of having a hierarchy
you can have a flat class that is
Animal processor and then you pass in a dog which has a speak function you pass in a cat which has a speak function
And it does speak that way so you don't have to do inheritance in that way
Cats and dogs in this scenario don't have any relationship at all
They don't have to you can use an interface or you can pass them as a function the cat function that does
The cat speak function or whatever and so the class itself that's managing it just knows that it gets things that speak and
It runs the speak code on it. So
That's the visitor pattern. There's tons of patterns
Just look up the gang the gang of four book if you have the book you can just go to the very back
The very back of the book and it has a list of all the patterns, which is nice
But yes, I will say
All that being said do not
Do not
Vehemently abide by clean code. I'll tell you this now I
Write test functions to test AI generated code, but I don't often write test functions for my own code in my own projects
I
Make small functions that do very specific things
which it would be nonsensical for me to test because
Especially when I'm working alone when I'm working with a team, it's a different story
But when I'm working alone, I don't need to over complicate it. I know when I write a function
I don't change it if I change it. I'm very specific on how I refactor it whether it gets all deleted and
Replaced with something else or something in that realm. So
All you clean coders out there. Congratulations for knowing what clean code is and clean architecture and design patterns and
Test driven development and all that sort of stuff
but
Life is life is simple. Take it take it easy. Don't be zealot about it and
One of the things that you'll find is
If you adhere too close to clean code and everything's interfaces and everything's abstract and everything's going everywhere
especially for
your own personal projects or
Projects you put up on github as libraries. You'll find that you wind up with
Unreadable code anyways, even though your whole goal was to make readable code you get way too many
Intertwined different things or disconnected things even worse
One of the things I just an aside
When I program in unity, I like to
Leverage unity so all of its signals all of its how it connects different objects
I like to leverage it because when another person who's using unity comes and they they want to work with me
or they they
Just see the code or see the project. They understand what's going on
They can find where things are and what things are doing
they don't have to go through and
Find the class and then go to its manager and then go to the then go to the facade which manages the managers
List which comes from a factory which comes from an abstract factory
They don't need to go through all that to figure out that the character can jump they can see just straight in the code
Exactly what it's doing
And I get trying to abstract a way to make everything interchangeable and all that
But I will argue
That as a huge proponent of clean code by the way
In a lot of scenarios when especially in working with teams
It is a major downside and I will argue that
It'll bloat your code and make it unreadable if you adhere to it too far
And it'll slow down your code because you've you've abstracted everything
Just off to oblivion so
What I like to do in my personal projects is I like to stick to flat
non-hierarchical
refactorable code the most important thing in my mind is
That I write code that is easy to refactor whether it's deleting whole functions and replacing them with another
Or I write code that is easy to refactor
whether it's deleting whole functions and replacing them with another or
just
changing out being able to
Delete maybe an entire set of files or change out the data structure
Easily, that's what I aim for is refactorable code because I refactor my code
Non-stop all the time over and over my game engine that I was I've written NC has been rewritten multiple times
I've converted it to C++ and converted back to C twice and
I've also
Refactored the entire math library and everything else. And so it's been it's like
What's that joke Theseus's ship?
I know that off the top of my head because
My wife has been making fun of this person who fixes her husband's shoes and not making fun of her
But making fun of the people comment on it because every comment is oh, it reminds me of Theseus ship
But that's kind of what my code is. Like everything's been replaced
It's it's not none of the code is the same from the original maybe except for some of my standard string
String functions and stuff like that
So that's my thoughts on the clean code try to do clean code, but don't don't stick to it too strictly
Now I I don't want to speak just to advanced programmers
to to more inexperienced programmers people who are just
Learning or learning the ropes or getting into things or you're an advanced programmer. You've done assembly coding, but you haven't done any web
One of the things that I've seen in repositories recently, which is why I want to talk about it is
you'll find API keys and other sensitive keys and that sort of stuff inside of public github repositories and
You know people can take those keys and wind up racking up a bill for you
in fact, I wouldn't be surprised if there's people who
crawl through the different projects looking for
Keywords for specific API's and see if they can't get a free key for a little bit and
And I've seen people ask about it, what do you do with you know these keys so
Especially in web or any kind of development. It doesn't have to be web. You could be deploying
Game server or anything like that. You don't put your keys anywhere in your code base at all
I if you need to regenerate keys because you forgot it or you've deleted something that you're keeping it
It is a secure place. You were keeping it in no big deal regenerate it
But
What you want to do is when you deploy?
your
Code your application your game server is that you want to push your key?
Through through and add it as the environment variables
Or add it as a file. That's inaccessible
That's kind of in a weird directory that is hard for anyone to accept access without
You know root privileges or something like that
Just you want to push your keys?
Into your server, so don't put it in your code base. Don't put in any code base
Don't even put it in a private repository. Just keep them locally and
Push them if you're using docker
Often you'll put these in environment variables
And just push them off to the server, so
That's just a little tip on that because I've seen some issues with that
so
This one is pretty cool. I found a random project where
somebody was doing a map of
github and
This was a pretty neat project. I
Like these kinds of things I
Like especially and like in these where it connects things
I don't know why they're connected probably because they're forks of each other or something like that
but I have this page here called map of github and
This is who it's made by and that and Vaca
here I mean
and go to his
And go to his in Seattle
There's a lot of web stuff anyways
here
Here's land of unity so we can zoom in on the land of unity
And you can see a whole bunch of little dots starting to appear as you get closer you get
inundated with a sea of dots and you can
Click on I think the circle yeah, and then you can see all these lines connecting it to things
Why they're connected to those things. I don't know like
Let's go to it page not found. Oh, I guess some of these are broken. How about you?
Outline effect. Oh it has a it looks like it's read me here
Yeah, I think it sticks its read me inside of there
Why is it connected to something else maybe it's a sub repository or something like that. It's just a read me
Oh a view code. I'm not in desktop mode. It's collapsed. Oh
Maybe it's these packages
It's probably these packages
Anyways, I don't want to get it. I don't go Bronson through this stuff
And the podcast but I thought this was really neat if you guys know any projects like these just random stuff
It's like a mind map basically
FBX exporter whoo? Unity FBX exporter
Unity technologies, I guess this oh, this must be the unity's FBX
Exporter plug-in no unity 3d Japan. Oh, maybe anyways
Like I said, I can browse these all day long. So if you have any that you like
Similar to this or you know any language? I
It doesn't matter to me
I sent him my way. I love to look through these
So I
This is
On a related note
Have you I don't know if you've explored
Get the hub before it took me a long and like I've had a github account forever and I never went through the explore tab
Which is hilarious because
That's I mean, I just showed you I like to look around at those kinds of things but a
Few years back. I started using the explore tab
And so you can find things like this one that I shared was game engines
And I've done a video in the past like I don't know a while ago
A couple maybe a year or two ago about all the different game engines that you can find
Inside a github for all different kinds of things 2d 3d half-baked all that sort of stuff
Of course, you're gonna have your number one
most starred stuff up here Godot
But you know you'll have
I'm gooey. I am GUI however you want to say it
the popular UI library, so
It's kind of essentially it doesn't
Keep track of the things it creates. It's it's an immediate mode. That's what I am stands for
It's an immediate mode where you have to tell it to render stuff what it's rendering kind of every frame
But I'm not gonna go through all these but there's there's all kinds like that
This is a refreshing a refreshingly simple data-driven game engine built in rust
so
I guess bevy must be a popular one for the rust the rust arians rust atonians
all the rusty's
It's pretty cool
But there
There I was about say hundreds. There are thousands like there's 5,000. Let me scroll down to the bottom here
Maybe it's not at the bottom. There's oh here. It is is at the top. There's almost well. There's
If you round up almost 6,000
Almost 6,000 I game engines and you know, some of them are pretty cool
I kind of spent some time perusing these
a
year or two ago and
They were there's just some really cool stuff and you can get some pretty cool shaders that people have done
There's a lot of you know available shaders
With like demos and and cool stuff I
I like writing shaders, but I do like
Checking out what other people do because lots of other people are way better at shaders than I am
I don't even I don't even really use shader graphs. I I
Find them too cumbersome for me. I like to hand type it but I
Hate debugging shaders. They take forever
So, yeah, I like to look at other people's shaders for inspiration and and that sort of stuff so pretty
dope
Yeah, if you have some time
Come in here
Feel free to browse through
The thousands and thousands and thousands of game engines you'll find one for every language and you'll find one for every scenario
Let's see what you can filter by you filter by star most fewest
most fewest
Most forks that'd be interesting and I've I'd assume it's relative to the stars
All right. Let's find out
Yep, good. Oh, I'm gee. I'm gooey
Coco's 2d, I guess it's a little different about the same though. I feel like those two are superfluous
Or the forks is superfluous that is the stars kind of is basically same thing I wouldn't recommend fewest stars
You're gonna get tons of zeros and I don't know what order those are in so
Recently updated it might be pretty cool
Coco's creator. Yeah, so if you ever get some time
Come out here and explore the github. There's a lot of cool stuff you can
Select on topics and you can select different topics based on what you're interested in
One topic that I have saved is C. I love looking through C stuff. I love
getting ideas from from C and look here's OBS
But I love just looking through C stuff since it's my favorite language lots of good stuff in there so check it out play around and
Send me if you find if you find some cool stuff
Send them my way. I'd love to look I love looking through this stuff. Like I said
So I
Think you know we're coming to the end of this and one of the things that
There's one other thing that bothered me. Hey, I
I'd strongly dislike to end on a sour note, but it's a it's a goofy one to me
There's there's this
Article that was posted and bothered my wife to where I
Don't know if it's called a straw man argument or a gas lighting or what?
But it was about not being able to play Zelda
inside of the
You know Legend of Zelda series. I know
Ironically, you don't play Zelda and Zelda you play as Lincoln Zelda
and I
Don't think this is they made it seem like everyone's gonna be playing Zelda
They made it seem like everybody
Everybody on the planet was wanting this to happen and you could play a Zelda and tons of games
You can play in Zelda, you know Super Smash you can play in Zelda as
What was it called Hyrule Warriors you play Zelda and like tons of like offshoot games
So, I don't know if she's in Mario Kart now she might even be in Mario Kart
I don't understand the need for people to
Come up with problems. Maybe it's because
They're being paid to write articles
And so they've got to figure out how to
Spend their day doing something and so they come up with these weird ghosts that they have to chase
and the way they word it is like
Everybody on the internet wanted this like with no citation of all the people that wanted it
I'm sure there's you know a pocket of people that want to play a Zelda and a Zelda game, but
Generally you play Legend of Zelda as link. That's how it's always been. It's a great game for its mechanics
You want to focus on the gameplay you want to focus on all of that sort of stuff. You don't want to have to focus on
character semantics and altering your story and changing your formulas just so you can play as
One of the other characters in there and they have lots of characters. It doesn't just have to be Zelda people are complaining
And I mean you could just mod the games if you really want to play a Zelda, but yeah, there's this is the
the article in question
by the gamer comm
Nintendo has no plans to make Zelda a playable character
It's a newsflash big old bold headline right there
No plans. Oh, how dare they?
As theories that Zelda would be playable in tears of the kingdom have proven wrong the wrong all those theories
I'd never heard once they're all just
And Nintendo even worst of all Nintendo doesn't plan to change anytime soon
Game that makes them millions and millions of dollars and is huge smash hits
They don't want to change it up and you know
Potentially alienate audiences. Uh, yeah, it's just I feel like this is I don't know like I said
I don't know if it's straw man or gaslight. It feels like one of those things where
companies point at
News people in general point at something and then they say
What do you think about that? And they point it and they they start asking that to like, you know,
What do you think about that and they point it and they they start asking that to like corporations and stuff like trying to get them?
The way on and on stuff they don't need a way in on and in my opinion Nintendo
They make tons of money. They have the IP solid. It's a fantastic
Like everybody loves the characters. Everybody loves the the storyline even though it repeats
It's it's a formula that works that people really like they focus on link doing these interesting game mechanics. So
But yeah, they're saying like
However, yet again is not the case yet again. Oh, no
Every single time I'm let down every time I sell the game comes out. It's a smash hit and
I'm always thinking about why couldn't I play Zelda?
Yeah, it's
It's a they even mention
That here we go. Unfortunately has been
That has many fans wondering if Zelda these many fans. I don't know where they are
Maybe they meant to put in my ni mini fans a small group
Of her playing in the mainline game and that's the thing is like why does it have to be mainline game?
That's why it's like you wanting to make Facebook or something
What's app I just remembered the chat app. That's like saying you want to put what's up on the front page of
Facebook it is I don't know, you know, a lot of people use it or like it so might as well
Swap out your main thing for that. It doesn't make much sense business-wise
You you kind of follow the money when you're in a business if you got a formula that works
Especially that's growing as big as Zelda does
Which I think is like their biggest title
You don't go tweak in that much you you make better games
Mechanics games are about the mechanics games are not about the characters games are not about the stories both of those things
Make games better, but that's not what games are about. They're about what the player does the games are about the player
Everybody has to get that in their their minds. The game is for the player and
Is about the player you don't need to pressure them into worrying about all these things. They don't need to worry about
You don't need to pressure them into worrying about all these things. They don't need to worry about just let them have fun playing their game
Okay, so that was my rant on this particular article, sorry whoever you are this person
This is
This is dumb the waste of I I don't like these kinds of
These kinds of articles that point at random ghosts and say why isn't that the way it's I think it should be
You know so anyways I
Haven't played by the way just a side note. No, don't spoil anything for me. I have not played the new Zelda game. I
Can't play it. You see I'm about to have a baby
I'm very excited about this baby, and I can't get sucked into a video game
Just as I'm about to have a baby. She'll be here any day now, and I probably won't be able to play
This is all that unfortunately, and I really do want to play it
I probably won't be able to play it for a few months until you know, she's stable
You know, my wife is all healed up and feeling better. I
I've already got a child to I'm gonna be looking after my son
Basically the whole time
because he's he's fairly young and
They're they're pretty close in age I can say so I'm gonna have my hands full and I
Though I really want to play this game. I'm gonna have to hold off on it. So no spoilers for me
Don't tell me anything
You can tell me what you like in general the public stuff like hey, I like
building cars and
trees and spaceships or whatever you but
Don't spoil any of the like mechanics. They haven't already kind of exposed or anything like that
I I like to go in blind on these things. In fact, I
goofy story I
I like all the side things in games. I haven't even finished beating breath of the wild
I've done everything like mastered all the cooking stuff
I've got all the best clothes and the last thing that I need to do is beat the final boss, which is Ganon
And presumably I have I like I said, I don't spoil myself on this stuff
I haven't even beat him yet because I did everything else and
There's a few things I haven't done I something I like to do like there's a few of the
Shrines I haven't completed
so something I like to do is I like to
Do all of the side things and then beat the final boss because then it's like a super completionist feeling moment
it feels incredible the downside is six years later have to be the boss, but the upside is it feels amazing when I do and
Because one of the one of the things that I feel suck is is if you finish the game
Beat the boss and then there's a bunch of side things to do
It feels like it's in backwards order like I feel like you should do all of the adventuring
Before you beat the penultimate boss and then say I'm done
That's just me though. I'm sure
But that's just what I like to do in games. So games like Grand Theft Auto
games like I don't even know what the main story quest is and
Things like Skyrim. I have no I have no idea at all
I just I just get plopped in the world and I do everything but the main story. That's just how I am. So anyways
That's my thoughts and thanks for watching I guess I'll see you guys in the next one have a good one bye for now