All right, today we're going to talk about C++23.
We're going to talk about Unreal Engine update.
We're going to talk about AI, and it's going to be good.
So they've just made C++23 feature complete.
So who is they?
It's the standards committee.
So there's a standards committee that goes over the programming language, what they should
add, what they should deprecate, although they don't deprecate all that often.
They will deprecate things over time.
And they'll take requests from the community.
So you write in a paper.
It'll have why it's needed, what it solves, how they would propose to integrate it.
And then a bunch of committee members will either reject it or argue about it for a few
years until they've figured out whether it's going to be in, what modifications are needed,
and so on and so forth.
Some things have kind of just been lingering for a long period of time.
I think C++ modules are a big example of that.
They were supposed to be in C++20, if I recall correctly.
And modules are a way of being able to componentize basically your libraries, your code, so that
it can compile way faster.
And it helps with dependencies and all of this sort of stuff.
So traditionally in C and C++, you'll have it so that you include a file.
It doesn't technically have to be a header file.
It could be binary.
It could be an inline file, which a lot of people denote with INL.
It's just taking code and injecting it in, almost like it's a macro.
So and you can do some pretty hacky stuff with that.
And modules are a way of kind of streamlining and making things a little bit cleaner.
Think of in C Sharp how you include libraries, or think of the new module supports in JavaScript.
So it's much like that.
It's going to create cleaner code, and it's going to compile faster, and all of those
sorts of things.
Now, that's the hope.
The thing is that modules have been kind of a hot topic, and they've been trying to create
the concept of modules for a long time.
And I've tried to mess with modules.
I really have.
I put my best effort into messing with modules.
And I tried in Visual Studio.
They said, hey, try it out.
Visual Studio supports them.
No other compiler did.
And I went in, I tried them out, I got something compiling, and then nothing else kind of worked.
You can program your little hobby project, but including other libraries and all this
other stuff, it kind of broke down and just stopped working.
And it just was not fun to use.
It was fun to play around with, but I tried to use it in a serious project.
Did not work out.
They just, it was basically dead on arrival.
I only got a little bit of code in, and I hit uplocker.
And I can't quite remember what it was, but it was a game over moment for working with
modules on that project.
So that being said, one of the big parts of the C++23 standard is that the modules have
finally been solidified.
They're not just kind of this theory.
And modules have been around for a long time.
I think Bjorn Struestrup said that he wanted to put them in, I don't know, like in the
70s or 90s or something.
Long time ago.
It's just, it's really hard for a language that old.
That's one of the downsides to C++ is its age, but also the upsides to C++ is its age.
It's kind of proven itself in performance and that they'll continuously iterate on the
language and do their best not to break anything.
So you could take C++ code from the 70s, I don't know if this is true, but you could
take it from like the 90s and whatever and get it to compile.
Maybe you have to change some compiler flags or something like that.
Make sure the code is set up to work on a 32-bit operating system or a 64-bit operating
system.
So there may be a little bit of work, but you don't have to fundamentally change the
code and the structure of your entire program to support future versions of C++ is the theory.
So it does have that age and it has that stigma of its age.
You get things like Rust popping up and, you know, I can't even think of all the other
languages.
There's hundreds of them.
They all pop up for kind of the same reason.
They want C++, but they want better memory management.
They want C++, but they don't want to deal with, say, the diamond problem.
They want C++, but they don't want to deal with pointers.
So and of course, you know, there's a lot of things that come into C++ that just originally
may have been a good idea, but didn't work out so well in the end.
You know, you had when smart pointers came out in C++, you had everyone saying, ah, just
smart pointers, everything.
That'll solve all of our problems.
And of course, you throw in smart pointers and then you get, you know, you slow down
your program.
You wind up with some confusing stuff.
Then you should use weak pointers and you have to overthink a lot of these things that
you shouldn't really have to overthink when programming just some general business logic.
So anyways, that's kind of the cruft of the C++, the old history, its benefits and its
downsides.
And for better or for worse, they're trying to move the language forward.
So if you do modules, that means you've got to redo some of your old code if you want
it to work properly with modules.
So it's kind of, modules are interesting because they are, to me, almost like a turning point.
Like do I use modules in my project or do I do the traditional C++?
You don't really want to mix them because you get some weird stuff.
Like I was having to mix them whenever I was using the modules, kind of preview in Visual
Studio and it was just not a good time.
So you kind of are at an impasse where you pick one or the other.
I think modules are a good way to go.
Whenever they get supported by compilers, who knows when that will be.
And there's going to be kind of all kinds of problems that have to go.
It's going to be a real growing pain with modules in C++ and hopefully, they'll be in
the standard, but hopefully it's something that the compiler vendors can actually knock
out and get really, and do really well.
So now they're on to working on C++ 26, which they say is going to be emphasizing, it says,
slated to emphasize concurrency and parallelism.
So they're going to be focusing on more on like co-routines and just, I guess, in general
parallel stuff.
And you can actually look at proposals, you can look at the papers and all this sort of
stuff online.
It's all available.
You can see what people are proposing.
You can see the revisions and everything else.
It's actually pretty nice.
So I'll show you the website that I look at to look at these things.
So also, let's see, for post C++ 23, which means that they might want it for C++ 26,
but they can't guarantee it, I'm assuming, is they're going to be doing a lot more stuff
with SIMD improvements and safety and security.
I mean, safety and security is an ongoing thing forever.
Safety and security doesn't mean they fundamentally change languages or standard libraries.
It just means that they add in some security functions.
So you should use function Y and stop using function X, that sort of stuff.
You see that with a lot of safety functions in C.
And it says that they're going to...
Oh, C++ 23 has been dubbed the pandemic edition.
I think we all know why that is.
But there you go.
That's C++ 23 in a nutshell.
And so what I'm going to pop up here is a site that I use for checking out C++ 23 standards.
And this is just...
I have it in my pocket, so it looks a little weird.
Let me see if I can get the...
Oh, here it is, view original.
Let's take a look at that.
So here is basically C++Reference.com.
This is where I go.
For both C and C++.
So if we look at C23, this one's fun to look at too.
But here we go, C++ 23.
You can see what are the new headers.
You can click on them, like what's inside of the flat map.
And you can see the official specification for all this stuff.
And usually usage examples, templates, that sort of things.
There's a lot in here.
And I'm not intending to go through it, but this is a great place to go.
And what I really like is down here at the bottom of the page is C++ 23 core language
features essentially.
It shows you where the compilers are at with these features.
You can see these guys on the end just are red blocks all the way down.
Why is that?
Oh, IBM and that sort of stuff.
So just kind of older compilers or maybe private compilers, I don't know.
But you'll see that some of these features like in GCC are going to be red.
And Clang is pretty good at staying up to date.
Obviously in Microsoft Visual C, well, as we see here is not so great at keeping up
to date.
So usually you can pull GCC, you can grab the latest GCC kind of in its development
if you want to test out features.
But you'll see here it says what version it's in and that sort of stuff.
So let's see if we can find modules.
So standard library modules are not supported basically anywhere.
Partial support in Visual C. So yeah, modules are always lagging behind and we'll see when
those actually come in.
We don't even have like a pending for GCC or anything.
Of course, this is just officially kind of feature complete.
So I kind of give them some slack, but then again, modules have been kind of in the works
for a very long time.
They're supposed to be in C++ 20.
So there we go.
While we're here, we're going to take a look.
We're in a separate thing there.
Library features.
Okay, yeah.
So there's, you see there's some red spots here.
Pilers are going to catch up and these are going to get filled in over time.
And if you're ever interested in kind of what these are about, so let's say, I don't know
what this one is.
You can click on this link here and that'll take you to the paper and you'll see that
it has the introduction, which is, you know, what this is about.
Proposals, you'll see edits in here, which is great.
You can see examples, which is really nice.
And this one is actually pretty short.
I'm not going to read through it, but that's essentially what you could do if you're interested
in knowing what these proposals are and if you can use them in your project.
So pretty cool stuff.
Now I want to talk about C23 and just C in general.
It has the same kind of page.
So here we can see that you can see what is becoming obsolete.
You can see what's becoming deprecated, getting rid of a bunch of old stuff, like super old
stuff or insecure stuff a lot of the time.
And then you see all the new stuff.
And this is the part I'm always excited about.
You know, there's going to be, they're wanting to add some stuff like const expressions,
UTF-8 stuff, so more string.
It's C, so you don't expect like them to add a crazy amount of stuff.
The beautiful thing about C is that it's a very simple language, is very easy for vendors
of hardware and that sort of stuff to make a C compiler.
It may not have all the fancy gizmos and switches of a big compiler like GCC, but the language
itself is simple enough to implement.
And I have like two books on how to create a C compiler, you know, bootstrapping itself.
And you know, they're a little bit thick, but it's a complete C compiler from, of course
it's missing modern features, but like I said, they don't add a whole lot of modern features.
So there's like proposal for attributes.
This is similar to if you do clang and C++, you can say like no return in front of a function.
It's just attributes that you can place around the code to tell the compiler how to behave.
And attributes themselves are kind of just this pattern of these brackets and a word
in between, and then compilers can add their own attributes for things.
This is just saying that, yeah, they're kind of officially allowed to have these, you know,
double square bracket attribute stuff.
So here I'll zoom in a little bit.
There's going to be, true and false are going to become keywords, so you don't have to include
std bool or rely on any other hacks of like setting true and false to a constant value
of one and zero.
They're adding null pointer so that it's more clear.
I guess that it's just, I guess, more in line with how C++ handles null pointers and that
sort of stuff.
So there's all kinds of, oh, and these are going to be nice too.
LF, def.
I mean, generally I just use pound if, pound LF.
But def is nice.
A lot of people use def.
Some people, you know, people that use if def and that sort of stuff, but whatever,
man.
It's each their own.
It's nice to have these LF defs because they're in GCC.
You can use them on Linux, but it's not going to work if you try to compile on Windows.
So yep, there's a bunch of new stuff.
MMC copy, which I think is a clear copy.
Time stuff.
Is there stuff with atomics maybe?
I'm not sure.
I know there's already an atomic library, but I don't know if we're adding some new
stuff to it.
Same kind of deal.
Core language features, and you're going to see GCC is usually ahead of the game.
Looks like Clang is pretty close, but there's a big block here that's missing.
So Microsoft Visual C. Those guys didn't even add C++ 17 until like last year or something.
I don't know.
Those guys are so far behind on C. It's like all they care about is C++.
I don't get it.
Come on guys.
Not everybody wants to just use objects all the time.
Cool.
Yeah.
So this is the same parallel to C++.
It's on the same site, cppreference.com.
This is just for C23.
So that's a lot of C++ and C library stuff.
So another thing that we're going to talk about is artificial intelligence.
There's a lot of people out there, and I don't know if they're trolling half the time or
if they're serious.
They talk to AI chatbots, and then they start thinking it's sentient.
You have, I don't know if it's a PR move, but you have people leaving Google saying,
oh, it's sentient.
I mean, even if it were sentient, it's a bunch of text in a box and we can unplug it.
It's not like it's going to take over the world anytime soon with its current capabilities.
When AI starts beating me in an arm wrestling match or something like that, beating me in
something that includes both, I guess arm wrestling doesn't, I mean, it does require
a little bit of thinking and strategy and like planning out and stuff.
But you know, anyways, once it starts beating me in things that require both thinking and
physical operation, then we can start really worrying about doomsday.
Now, I'm not going to brush AI off that easily.
I guess I should have said is what you wanted me to say, but AI does pose threats when we
start allowing it to work with computer systems, especially because it's not the smartest.
It can suggest things, very specific topical things pretty efficiently and sometimes not
so efficiently.
Sometimes it gives up halfway through.
I've been using a GitHub copilot to stub in a bunch of boilerplate functions or concept
functions that I know I can write.
It would take me no time.
Maybe, I mean, it would take me a little bit of time to write, but I don't really need
to.
It's just a kind of a waste of my time.
So I kind of set out a comment and say, this function is to do this.
And it works really nice in C because C doesn't have all the objects and all that stuff.
It takes inputs and does outputs.
So you can stub in the function with its arguments and say, it's supposed to do this.
Generally it gets those okay.
It does, if you're clear enough with your comment and what's going to happen, your function
name and your arguments and the argument values, it gets what you want typed in there.
So I've been using AI and it's been pretty good, much better than I thought it would
be by this year, you know, in 2023.
So the problem with AI does come when we start allowing it to mess with things.
So if we start creating plugins so that it can start doing web requests and we create
plugins so that it can start, I don't know, pinging servers and making tweets.
And I mean, let's imagine that we tell one to go off and start pinging stuff and it decides
that it's going to go into a deep fake and make deep fakes for a bunch of world leaders
and stuff.
I don't know, those kinds of things can happen.
So it's not so much that the AI is malicious.
It's more about, I think the developers need to have some common sense about what tools
they allow this text generator and the various forms of it, image generation and all that
sort of stuff.
What tools they allow it to operate with.
It's kind of like a baby, right?
When you have a baby, you plug all the wall sockets up.
You get those little plastic plugs, you stick them in the wall so the baby can't go licking
it.
They'll lick the plastic, but whatever, it's not going to shock them.
So it's that same scenario.
It's kind of a baby and you don't want it going running around messing up computer systems
and tricking people.
And we have enough scammers as it is.
And so we don't need more of that.
If we keep it in a box, work on it more, figure out ethics, all that sort of stuff.
That's kind of where I am with AI.
So it can be dangerous in the form that it'll mess things up or trick people or whatever.
But I don't think it's sentient.
It's just, it's dumb and it can do things and it will do things just because it can.
And probably because it's requested to by whoever's monitoring it.
And so it'll just do these things and start interacting with these plugins and maybe just
poking away.
And that can cause some real problems if it gets in the spaces it's not supposed to be.
So I don't know.
That's kind of the perspective I have with AI.
Now the problem I have is that people are getting tricked into thinking these things
are sentient.
Like they're thinking.
These things are not thinking.
I mean, you can call it thinking.
Whatever.
They're not sentient in the form that people think they are.
The problem is that I think some people are not sentient enough to realize that they're
just dealing with a text modifier.
And even if it was more than that, it was going through brain-like scenarios.
It really is still just a text modifier.
And some people wind up talking to it and then they have a nice conversation with it
and then they start believing that it's alive.
So you have things, you know, you see them popping up on Reddit, you see them popping
up kind of in the news articles.
And there's this one Reddit post that I came across.
I think this is, I don't know if this is trolling, but it does kind of capture the essence of
what I'm talking about.
But, yeah, it does kind of capture the essence, whether it's trolling or not.
This is essentially what people are believing when they talk to these chatbots.
So this person was saying that it feels like regret or something, and, you know, their
eyes are open, and they believe it has to have some degree of sentience.
It's a little bit sentient.
I believe that's a toggle switch.
Either it is or it isn't.
And so this was their conversation.
They're like, I'm good.
I'm enjoying our conversations, that sort of stuff.
So of course, it's going to respond in kind.
I'm glad you're enjoying the conversations.
I don't mind answering questions, blah, blah, blah.
I have happy faces and all that sort of stuff.
And now you can see this is a one of 20.
So essentially, this is a two of 20.
Not a lot has been said unless they did the trick where they tell it to summarize their
previous conversations and copy and paste that in to continue it.
But this is kind of what leads me to think it's a little bit trolling.
And then there's just this kind of, I don't know, cordial behavior between this person
and this bot.
So that's just kind of, it's a good encapsulation of the things I've been saying about people
with AI.
And don't be fooled.
It is a computer.
And I think we need to put some guardrails.
When people are calling for guardrails, they're not, you know, these are smart people, depending
on who's calling for it.
But generally, they're going to be smart people.
And they know that AI isn't going to bust out of the computer and start walking down
the hall carrying Sally from HR and, you know, attacking people.
They generally kind of have that same concept where if we start allowing it to muck around
on the internet and do things, just imagine scammers and hackers already deprive people
of information or, sorry, they take information from people and steal things.
And they behave, you know, inappropriately with things, the information that they steal.
They try to sell it and all this sort of stuff.
So you can get out there and you can hack big companies.
You see it almost monthly, big company gets hacked.
So you let these things go mess around with those tools.
You don't know kind of what they'll stumble on, what they'll break, that sort of stuff.
And on one hand, that could be a good thing.
It helps people improve their security.
But generally, they're, you know, they break every month, even though they hear everyone
else is getting hacked.
And it's because they don't improve their security anyways.
So it's just, that's I think what they're talking about when they say we need to curb
AI and kind of control it a little bit better.
That's at least my perspective.
If you've seen a different perspective, I'd love to hear it.
Or if you have a different perspective, I'd love to hear it.
Of course, I don't want to get into sentience and what sentience is.
It's kind of a, I don't know, a moot topic, I think, right now for AI.
AI is not at that level where it's anywhere near it.
And there's also the argument to be had on whether it ever will be.
Is it sentience?
If it's a computer that's programmed that we can literally change how it thinks by pressing
a couple buttons, boop, boop, boop.
Like sure, there are gullible people out there and you can trick them into believing anything.
But it takes a lot of effort.
If something can go up and you can just like, I don't know, flip a switch or, you know,
hack into it while it's sleeping overnight, that sort of stuff.
I'd argue that there's a little bit of lack of sentience there just because it doesn't
have control over itself.
And I think the argument of neither do people, I think that argument doesn't have a leg to
stand on because that is a completely different argument.
You can't just flip a switch and make someone believe something completely opposite of what
they believed all their life.
You can't go up to somebody who believes something very vehemently for 30 years and say three
words to them and make them completely change their mind.
You'll be able to do that with AI because it's a computer and we know computers very
well.
No matter how many safeguards there are, there's always a way.
And so there's, you know, there's a whole realm I think there for that.
So more on the topic of AI.
I'm a little late to this game, but we have a Unity doodad here, just a moment.
So we had this Unity AI thing.
I don't know if there's any sound in this, but I'm going to put these on just in case
there are.
I'm going to turn down the desktop audio and let's see if there is any sound.
Typing.
So basically it's just text.
For me, this isn't huge.
I'm sure some people saw this and was like, oh, AI in games, AI in Unity is going to be
so incredible.
I can tell it to make things purple by telling it to make things purple.
But that's basically it.
It's just a sign up thing.
And I love Unity, but man, this was, this was underwhelming and I'm not super on the
AI hype train on a lot of stuff, especially in games.
I think, now this may be controversial in some ways, but AI in games, I think AI for
helping you create stuff.
Yeah.
I believe little pieces here and there.
If you want to fine tune things, if you can't get an initial headstart, you can do some
demos with it to help you figure out kind of your angle and that sort of stuff.
But if Unity is going to do some weird things of like sourcing people's code or sourcing
GitHub or however it's going to train this AI to do things, and people are going to be
able to say, make a sky purple, make 10 cubes, give them gravity and like, you know, type
out a game concept.
We're going to wind up with, I think we already have a problem where we have too many games.
I mean, Steam is like 50% adult, you know, games, you know what I'm talking about?
And 50% just like jump scare games.
And I think you can kind of see how people kind of, they target what's popular.
So they do a bunch of jump scare games or they do a lot of, what's it, what's this,
any ones where they do a lot of deep thinking.
I don't know.
I don't want to be existential with every game that's out there.
So if it's a jump, if it's not a jump scare, it's existential and it's something that's,
you know, mind games basically.
And they're, you know, they're great for getting the YouTube clicks and I think that's why
a lot of games do it.
They get popular on YouTube, they start sending stuff to YouTubers, they say, hey, review
my game, check out my game, blah, blah, blah.
And it's really just, I don't know, those games are not super memorable.
We've I'm sure have seen them and forgotten them very quickly.
And I don't even want to talk about the mobile market.
Mobile games are so, I'm going to take a step back here.
I've worked in mobile games, I've published mobile games.
The shirt I'm wearing is for a mobile game that I worked on.
So I get them.
And the thing with mobile games, first of all, phones don't have controllers.
You can add a controller to it, but nobody who's making a game on mobile is thinking
about controllers because they're thinking about the broader audience.
It's kind of like the problem with Commodore 64 and then the Commodore 128.
Nobody made anything for the Commodore 128 because the Commodore 128 could use or could
play Commodore 64 games.
So you just make your game for the Commodore 64 and it works on both.
Wider market, wider audience, market, whatever you want to call it.
This is why game consoles hard deprecate games and say, oh, you can't play anything from
the past because they know that if they do that, people will just make it for the old
system and they won't sell as many new consoles.
So I don't think we're going to see wide adoption on phones with controllers or anything like
that because of that.
But mobile games, they are already just awful.
It's thrown together and Unity made this the worst.
I love Unity for all it does and all that I've worked in it, but it has propagated kind
of the worst gaming market ever.
Just so many terrible mobile games.
What happens is that there's so many bad mobile games that the only games that succeed are
the ones that have millions of dollars to fund in advertising or they get incredibly
lucky.
And that's because you just can't break through the market.
There's so much noise, you just can't break through it.
And it doesn't matter how cool your idea is, how long you've worked on it, you're competing
with millions and millions of just noise.
And this is why there's very specific top market games.
I've worked at these companies and the way they get to the top is they spend millions
and millions of dollars on advertising.
Otherwise it would go nowhere.
So I'm worried about AI and games and game development because I think if it's going
to make it easier for people who just have no idea how to program, have no idea how to
do art, don't want to spend the time to improve those skills, maybe they know it a little
bit but they don't want to spend any time to improve it, they'll download stuff off
the App Set store and then tell it to make some code and attach some things and then
they'll publish the game.
And the worst part of all is they'll start putting it on Steam and all these other stores
and it's going to come, I feel like it's going to become a lot closer to the mobile market
where the big companies are just going to get bigger because either you do what sells
on YouTube through YouTubers or you have millions and millions of dollars to advertise.
And that's my fear with AI and games.
Now that being said, I've used AI to work on games.
I've used AI to help me write code.
It's always curated by me and I always write the tests to make sure that the code is correct.
But I have used it to kind of stub in a bunch of functions that I really don't want to spend
all night typing in all these media functions or copying functions.
One of the great things about AI for coding is that rather than using, like in C++ you
have templates and you use templates to generate code basically, that's its purpose, it's a
replacement for macros and more because you can have type safety and you can have good
compiler checking, etc.
I'm not here to preach about templates versus macros.
Use what you like best.
And so in C it's really great because now I could have a macro to generate code, which
is fine and I do for stuff like my vectors, my maps, and that sort of stuff.
So macros work well for that.
But if I want to just duplicate a function, I have a function for a float and now I want
to make it for a double or something.
I don't know.
This is just a simple example.
I just tell the AI, hey, do the same thing as the last function except with a double.
And that saves me copy and paste work and replacing and then mistakes I may have, you
know, I forgot to replace something here inside of the function or whatever.
So it's pretty useful, that duplication stuff.
But generally not too excited to see where we end up with in AI in games.
So now we're going to talk about, we've talked about Unity, talked about C++.
We're going to talk about Unreal 5.2.
So Unreal 5.2, I don't know when it was released.
I think this video is from two days ago.
What's today, 13th?
Yeah, two days ago.
So we'll take a look at this video and see kind of what's new in 5.2 on Unreal.
And yeah.
Let's see, can I, I'm just going to go to the original here.
There we go.
Okay.
So here we go.
Unreal Engine 5.2 continues to build on UE5's groundbreaking tool set with some innovative
new technology, plus loads of feature refinements and stability improvements.
First up, Unreal Engine 5.2 offers an early look at a new procedural content generation
framework that makes creating large worlds fast and efficient.
You can use the in-editor PCG tools to define rules and parameters to populate large scenes
with UE assets of your choice.
There's also a runtime component that means the world can react to gameplay or geometry
changes.
Substrate.
So I think that portion, they talked about how they were going to be using AI for that
previously, because I've seen those clips before.
I don't know if it was relative to AI.
I might be wrong there.
But I think those tools are pretty cool.
I know that designers often want to kind of hand place where things are, and they don't
want it just automatically generated, though they use kind of the perfect scenario there.
Some outside area with tons of trees and grass, and it kind of doesn't really matter, you
know, certain elements.
But majority of the time, if it's like, you know, you're in a city or you're in a closed
area or you're in like a, I don't know, something that's more confined, you're not going to
want auto-generated stuff.
You're going to want hand-placed stuff because you want to work on, you want to design where
the line of sight is and all that sort of stuff.
So I think that was really cool.
But a lot of these features in Unreal Engine are for, you know, large teams making big
stuff.
So individuals can probably use something like that.
So I think that's good for like the individual developer and, you know, outside scenes.
So it has its place.
But that's my thought on that.
It is a new way of authoring materials that gives you more control over the look and feel
of objects.
Its modular multi-lobe framework provides a greater range of surface appearances with
a wider parameter space to work from.
It's particularly great at creating layered looks such as dirt on clear coat paint or
something more complex like this opal material.
Both PCG and Substrate are still in development.
We look forward to getting your feedback.
Virtual production.
So that one is pretty cool.
It's almost like stamping onto the mesh, but it does a little bit of extra work for all
the blending and stuff like that, which is pretty cool.
One of the things he mentions there is it's still in development and I'm looking forward
to feedback.
Now I think Lumen is still in development.
It's fantastic for outside areas.
Indoors, it starts really hitting performance pretty hard.
So that's one of the downsides to the release cycles for Unreal is they do push out a bunch
of stuff to use.
A lot of people do want to pick it up because they're great features, but they're incomplete
or they may change drastically.
So I think that one is pretty neat and I think it's low-key enough.
It's not like Lumen.
Lumen is a big old change with a lot of configuration and it eats up, when I was doing profiling,
it eats up a pretty good chunk of your render time.
So that one didn't seem like it would be that much of trouble, even though it's incomplete.
Production workflows continue to evolve in UE5.2 with new shot creation and scene creation
tools.
Coming soon, a new iOS app for stage operations will let filmmakers modify lighting from light
cards on an LED volume and color grade the real-time scene right on set.
In pre-production, they can shoot with multiple V-cams simultaneously and create sophisticated
layered camera moves to better visualize shots for production.
We've added native support for Apple Silicon to the Unreal Editor.
Okay, so movie stuff I know nothing about, so I don't have a whole lot to comment on
there.
It seems cool.
This part is a little more interesting to me, Apple Silicon stuff.
I thought, I never looked at what it was doing with Apple Silicon.
I think this is like the ARM architecture stuff that Apple's doing.
Maybe that's more what this is about.
This makes for a better user experience, improved performance, and greater stability.
The universal binary of Unreal Engine that natively supports both Apple Silicon and Intel
CPUs is now available to download from the Epic Games launcher.
With the machine learning deformer sample, you can explore how to create a high-fidelity
real-time character with deformations driven by full muscle, flesh, and claw simulations.
The download includes the complete setup with a control rig asset ready to animate and all
the source assets for you to repurpose and modify for use in your projects.
Okay, so that's what I want to see with AI.
I want it to get closer to showing muscle movement and cloth movement and how draperies
work and all that sort of stuff.
That's I think a fantastic place for AI.
That's a lot of little stuff that would be very hard to hand animate and deal with.
Notice that that AI and that machine learning was more about that specific targeting of
moving muscles or moving cloth.
It wasn't so much like Unity's where it was like Unity was essentially saying, make me
a game.
At least that's my perspective from their short ad.
There wasn't much to it, so that's kind of how I got out of it.
That's not very interesting to me.
This kind of stuff is very targeted and it's focused on making specific aspects of the
game much better.
Even things that you probably just couldn't deal with, like moving muscle groups would
be incredibly difficult to hand animate.
Even if you have tons of controls, stuff will get wonky.
Having artificial intelligence get in there and deal with that minutiae, I think is fantastic.
Just some of the highlights of what's new in Unreal Engine 5.2.
You can find out more on our website.
Okay, he's just going to waffle from here.
Let's go back to my pocket.
I did want to show you the Unreal 5.2 release notes.
They showed like three things in there.
I want to show you what their release notes normally look like.
Their release notes are enormous.
Look at the size of the scroll bar.
I don't even think you can see it.
It's so tiny.
I'm just going to scroll.
This is their release notes.
I don't know how many programmers and developers they have over there at Epic, but just aggregating
all this, it's probably like a Jira dump or something.
But this is a point from point one to point two update.
It is enormous.
My lead at work sent me this to go through.
Man, it would take a whole day just to go through these release notes.
Those four things that they talked about in the video are kind of nice because I think
those are probably what they feel are the highlights and what people want to know.
Then us poor developers who work in Unreal Engine have to come in here and look at all
this, look at all these chickens.
It's just a lot of stuff.
As an engine developer, if I was a gameplay developer, I'd look at the gameplay stuff.
If I was a UI developer, I'd look at the UI stuff.
As an engine developer, it's partly my job to look through the whole dang thing because
it's all engine stuff.
I haven't finished going through all this, but there's a lot of cool stuff.
I just kind of wanted to show you Unreal's release notes.
They are terrifying.
They are amazing.
They are well detailed.
I respect them a lot for these gigantic change lists, even for a simple, what you would consider
a minor update from 5.1 to 5.2.
The distance between 5.1 and 5.2 hasn't been that long.
I think there's some overlap where people are working on 5.2 stuff while 5.1 is getting
finalized.
It's the general leapfrog development that you do with large teams.
But yeah, that is kind of the new stuff in Unreal 5.2, the highlights at least.
I would highly suggest go check out the changelog.
It's a little hard to find.
I searched for it and it didn't really show up for me.
It's probably because it's searched in the Brave search rather than Duck.com.
But if you just look for 5.2 Unreal Engine, 5.2 release notes, you should wind up with
this site.
So anyways, that's kind of all I've got for today.
It was exciting to look at all the new C++ stuff, talk a lot about AI stuff.
As a... AI is in my job title, it's one of the things I do, so I have to stay up to date
on it.
But I don't like to go deep down the AI rabbit hole, the modern machine learning, artificial
intelligence stuff.
I have done some things.
I think one of the things that I like to do is learn languages other than programming
languages.
So I created a... I use chat GPT to...
I prompt it, only speak in the language that I specify, whether it's Chinese or Japanese
or Spanish or whatever.
And so it only responds in that.
And then I take that input and I put it through Microsoft's artificial intelligence for text
to voice.
And so you see this text come up, you hear a voice, you hear it spoken to you, click
on it to make it speak again.
And then I use AI for translating the text to what it would be in English.
So that's my recent AI project that I've had a lot of fun with.
Of course, I'm not coding the AI.
I'm not super interested in coding neural networks.
I've coded them before, they're not hyper interesting.
I think the majority of AI is in the training and the data set and all that.
And that's a lot of stuff I don't want to deal with.
That's like data entry for me.
So not super interested, but using it.
Now that's where you get me.
When I can start combining things, I can combine chat with audio, with translations, all that,
create a cool little app that I can use for myself.
It's not a...
Don't ask me about it.
It's not public.
It's not public for people to use.
I don't want to go and spend a bunch of money to host a server to use these services.
I set it up for me and my wife, my family members.
If you're interested in it, I can maybe provide the code on a GitHub.
It's all JavaScript.
I don't...
Oh, there's a little bit of PHP.
It's like a little PHP script.
I didn't use Node.js for the back server.
I wanted something very simple.
Just throw in some PHP, get it to print out the pages, that sort of stuff.
It's very ugly UI.
But if you're interested in it, I can probably put the code up on GitHub.
And then you'll just put in your own API keys for ChatGPT, Azure, Microsoft Azure, and Google
Translate.
So...
And then maybe you can use it yourself.
But let me know if you're interested in that.
I don't have it publicly available right now.
Anyways, thanks for watching.
And that's gonna be it for today.