jobs for programmers some of us need them some of us have them I was curious about remote work and how
it affects the job market what companies are doing with remote work I work remotely a lot of you maybe
work remotely and just kind of want to take a look at jobs but before I get into remote work I
want to take a look at losing jobs lots of people are losing jobs
yet another story today not today a couple days ago stack Overflow lays off
10 percent of their employees and that's not a lot I was surprised to find out that 10 percent of the stack
Overflow employee base was 58 employees which is pretty astounding I like that they run a
tight ship over there I think that having I mean that means they've got 580
employees I think that may be a little bit too high to run a question and answer site
I don't know I don't run a question and answer site I just think that oftentimes
we hire too many developers we hire way too many people and that's usually what
is uh slowing us down at companies interworking with people
so perhaps they're figuring figuring this out and you know laying off people I've
always said that programming is not an assembly line job you can't just add
more programmers and then all of a sudden magically produce tons more code there's been
studies of this that show that that's never the case you can look at the mythical man month from the 70s and that
still holds true believe it or not they did hire tons of programmers at companies even back then when there
weren't that many so just taking a look at something like that and that information has basically
held true this entire time we can start to see that you can't just
hire more programmers and more developers and expect things to go faster it's just not how it works
in fact I think the CEO of Nintendo he
famously was shown mother three I don't know which one it was Mother the uh the
game that has like Ness as the main character I think it's Ness I don't know who it is kid with baseball cap and uh
and uh the baseball bat
so it's it's this RPG and they presented it to him and he said this is going to take forever to
fix and so he said we can get it done in six
months if we start over from scratch and that's what they did they started over in scratch and I think it took seven or
eight months to complete the game and get it published and that just shows you that
sometimes having a lot of Legacy code it's easier just to scrap it all and do it from scratch and I'm a big proponent
of that however it's very hard to pull off in this day and age
anyways uh we have so stack Overflow fired or laid off I don't know is that
any different than firing I think it's the more PC language but they fired 58 employees which is 10 of their Workforce
they were saying that the CEO stack Overflow perhaps uh or his name is Pratt
I can't I can't even pronounce it pronounce his name I'll call him PC that says initials
um said that layoffs uh were also a result of taking a hard look at our strategic
priorities this fiscal year and the organizational
structure and that's usually how it goes they look in CEO we have a lot of bloat we had a Heyday during you know that
pandemic hired people maybe for things we didn't need and now we're kind of overpopulated and slowing
ourselves down just kind of drudging along once the ship gets bigger it's going to be harder to push it so
that's essentially um you know as vague as it is why Let It Go
the they want to pursue agility and flexibility with the launch of AI ml
focused offerings in the months ahead so everybody's going AI obviously I think
everybody can can look around and see that every company I mean most of Google
I O is just AI that's the buzzword that's what everybody's expecting it's
where all the investors are going even though they probably wouldn't have touched it with a 10 foot a 10-foot pole like five years ago
and so a stack Overflow is in Jeopardy honestly when you have
a I mean I'm I think I've seen articles about a dip in their user base ever
since like um chat GPT was announced and GitHub co-pilot and these kinds of AI generated
code and I can see why it's very easy to just write a comment in your code it's a
save a file and it detects the language and it gives you basically what you
would have went to stack Overflow for a little copy and paste snippet so I don't know exactly what they're going to do
with artificial intelligence I think the only way they can save themselves is if they compete with things like copilot
and they produce an artificial intelligence that takes the entire base of knowledge of stack Overflow and all the
suggestions there and kind of works from that although
Microsoft's you know they bought GitHub for a reason and I was to have access to
all the code on GitHub whether we like it or not to train their AIS so they have a much bigger code base
to work from so that that's that's you know just nature
of the business but I don't want to focus too much just on stack overflow um
ironically and this one is is ironic to me because we all know about all the
layoffs that are happening there's layoffs at every big company you can think of games software nobody is safe
in the um software Realm and the I don't want to say the funniest
but it is kind of funny LinkedIn Cuts 700 jobs and closes their China app so I
can understand why they close their China app I mean that's a whole other discussion about you know
Chinese firewall and kind of their regulatory stuff that
makes it very difficult to do stuff there so besides the point but they cut 700 jobs at LinkedIn
um it's ironic because you would imagine with everybody getting laid off from every big company there's a lot of
people who are going to be paying for LinkedIn and trying to get jobs so it's
weird to me that a job search website and I I have an article here that says
let's see um here let's take a look
says more than 197 000 Tech sector employees have lost
their jobs since the start of 2023. this isn't even talking about 2022.
um so you know 200 000 people looking for jobs and Linkedin is uh they're cutting they're cutting 700 jobs from
from their company which does that mean people are not looking
for jobs does it mean they're not looking through Linkedin or they just is LinkedIn just not a viable thing for
finding jobs I don't know what to take of this um I've I've gotten jobs through
Linkedin recruiters so it's a little strange to me I think that it's pretty effective there's a lot of
Recruiters on there and there's a lot of noise daily I get I get recruiters hitting me
up for jobs I sometimes feel like I need to close down my thing whenever I I take
a job that I'm happy with but there's a lot of recruiters and there's it seems to be a lot of jobs
because I you know I get them for artificial intelligence games mobile
apps just the whole Spectrum so I don't know uh so it's very odd I don't
know what to take of it I don't know if it's a a good omen a bad Omen that they're cut jobs but something to think
about um but they're not the only ones so um it looks like May 3rd Unity conducts
a third round of layoffs this is the unity game engine um if you're not a game developer that's
the one I'm talking about uh they've they've cut uh something about eight
percent of their staff which is another 600 people getting laid off and I guess this is a third round I
have no idea what happened in the first couple of rounds uh how many people went got laid off in that and so
um very interesting again games are doing great right now but
I don't know if if it's just the trend all the big Tech Bros are talking to each other at their
yacht meetups or whatever rich people do and saying hey look we can just cut a
whole bunch of jobs look Elon Musk did it you like cut Twitter to nothing and uh still the thing is running and you
know tons of people are using it and it hasn't totally collapsed maybe we could do the same I don't know
um but usually once one person does it it really starts a chain reaction they
all realize hey maybe we're bloated we need to save some money inflation is happening all kinds of weird stuff's
happening um you know banks are collapsing maybe we should start cutting people to save
money I don't know uh but it's very interesting um you know it's affecting everybody
from games to software to tech companies is the whole Spectrum even LinkedIn if
linkedin's being hit and you know everything's being hit it's uh that's the way I see it so
I have uh I did I did see something
um from times now news amid Mass layoffs uh there's a particular I.T company an
Indian I.T company that is hiring like 1500 people and that's not unheard of I actually was
fired I will call it fired laid off whatever you want to call it
um I was laid off it was it was part of uh I was part of a studio a game studio
and we were making money we the company was already bought once and they were about to be bought again and they
decided to lean up and what they did was they brought in a bunch of um I don't know if they were uh I never
asked them I think they were Russian they may have been Ukrainian the guy
that was kind of communicating with them and working with them he was Russian so I don't know what the people on the
other end was they didn't really explain it much but after working with them and
they got integrated with the team they laid off everybody in the United States
for that company and offshored everything so it makes perfect sense
that it'd be offshoring you know offshore companies would be hiring tons
and tons of new new people and that could be exactly what it is it's uh you
know I think that's going to be unnecessary with all the AI stuff that
we're creating because um it can do it much more efficiently and you can have one programmer who's a
little more effective Maybe he's got a he's got a no code you can't
just hire anybody to just put in prompts for AI you got to have somebody who knows code inside and out so I guess the
upper echelons of coders your jobs are safe so don't worry about
that so there's been a lot of layoffs Intel
did more layoffs on May 9th it looks like so you've got
Intel and Google Amazon meta Microsoft and just tons of companies just even
this month laying off people and I think that we're tired of seeing all the headlines
because we've seen them basically every month for like a year but it's still going and
that's uh that's pretty crazy luckily I've not had any problems with
this um you know since way back when and that scenario I was talking about but it is
unfortunate for a lot of people I I don't know how to deal with job security there when you're in a huge
company like these uh some of these big companies Intel Microsoft they'll probably cut important people
not not even knowing they just need they just need big sections to just disappear
so that they can uh kind of Reserve their funds so that's that's
kind of the crazy stuff that's going on in the job stuff I'm not worried at all if you're secure in your job
you don't have to worry uh if you're a really good programmer and you know many languages and you can go
cross-discipline you really don't have to worry you're going to be fine so
and if you do get laid off like I said I get I get tons of stuff in LinkedIn I know there's stuff out there for you so
if you are laid off if you're not something to think about everything's
good that brings us to remote work so I
started to think about remote work today because um Elon Musk did a long interview and
one of the things that came up with that was remote work you you probably know elon's point of view on remote work
and um you know I'm somewhat ambivalent to
remote work I think that it has its benefits for those of us uh like me who
have family and a place that's not so techy and it has its huge downsides which will
also kind of cover so uh kind of what he went over today
was he opposes the work from home policies and called out remote work and
said it was morally wrong he suggested that work from home policies and are fundamentally unfair since every
employee can work from home pointing to a factory uh appointing to factory and
food workers so um and basically what he's saying is
there they're kind of I don't know if you want to call them Elites who can work from
home people like me who have a job that pretty much is all done on the web and then you have the
other part of the society who are equally important in holding up the
society and producing food and working in factories and and keeping everything
we enjoy afloat and there is an unfairness to that and it
could cause social tension I think is is his perspective on this
um he he mentioned uh like Emma Amazon and apple want their employees to go
back to office which is true game companies like blizzard um and you know Microsoft want that as
well and it's it's kind of a big push to get back to office
um for employees uh the remote work benefits are obvious and you know that's that's kind of what
what was said that's like a quick summary of what was said in that now
my perspective on remote work I know that I have a bias
but I also understand this point of view I understand the unfairness factor to
Society of course there's always been uh you know a disparity between say
programmers who sit and don't have to do much um you know we're not lifting heavy
weights or heavy things and risking our lives like other people are doing and
then other people do that and somehow programmers get paid more and it is it
all comes down to capitalism supply and demand um you know it's it's for example if
computers just died today I'd probably be able to pick up and learn um construction or something like that
as long as I'm mobile and able and that's not so easy like if all if
all the lumber in the world disappeared and all we had were computers it would be much more difficult for someone in
construction to say take a role that I work in and that's not to say one is harder than the other or anything like
that it's just that's just how capitalism works it's a supply and demand scenario and it can be
unfair but you know it's it's created the greatest nation in the world and uh the greatest Prosperity that the world
has ever seen because we do share a lot of our prosperity so it's unfortunate I have no solution
I have no opinion on a solution I I'm just a I'm just a family man who wants to feed his kids
so from the perspective of working from home
I've worked with a lot of people who work from home for the last couple of years I mean my job all the way up till
2020 was going to the office and I would take a
train two hours to get there and two hours back because I wanted to live in a different place than the job was or it
was way too expensive to live where the job was so I sacrificed four hours of my day five
days a week just to get to and from work and I I was on trains where people on
the train before me were attacked by people with machetes and you know I've seen quite a few weird
things on the train so you know I prefer not to do that
especially now that I have children so there is like a rah-rah and a lot of
people who are remote work from home they have this like let's band
together and not allow it to happen now I would like to say if you could make
yourself valuable now this is the same thing between programmers so you have a you have a value hierarchy of supply and
demand within programmers you have programmers who there's a lot of supply and uh you know or yeah there's a lot of
supply and the demand is met but then you have jobs that are much higher
difficulty that have a very low supply of programmers and has a very high demand now I would
argue that if there's a huge supply of programmers for a particular job
then a company may be in their in their rights to say come into work and that's because you don't really have
arguing power there you don't you can't fight for your position you can't do something like that now programmers who
are in much lower Supply let's say their systems programmer game engine programmers those sorts of people
um you have bargaining power it's hard to find people in that realm and you could
say hey I'll take a little bit of a pay cut let me work exclusively from home and
we've got a deal and companies would gladly do that and they even before the
whole pandemic people would have these companies would have gladly done it I've worked with people who worked remote
so that I think just on the perspective of remote work there is uh
you know you don't have a right to just want to do it your way and the reason I say this is because I've worked with a
lot of programmers who work remote who don't do much of anything uh they I know
they came in late came in late they push off things they go to a lot of
meetings and just work doesn't get done and you can tell because timelines get
pushed all the time and part of that is the hierarchy of the business you know
management and all that stuff and having too many programmers and that's a whole other thing to to
look at now one thing I will say is I do miss working in person it is something that I
do miss I I actually liked going in and the camaraderie and you know making the jokes and eating with the eating with
the co-workers and talking about code and projects and Concepts and ideas and game designs and hunting and just random
stuff I do miss that and you know the free lunches were awesome too you get free
lunch every day those those were great a great incentive so there were definitely huge perks that I
really miss now as a father I love being at home with my kids so
working remote is a dream come true I the time that I would spend traveling to
go to work to come from work can be spent with my children and really
there's that's there's no there's nothing that compares it's it's the dream so though I do miss the social
aspect of talking to people and that does um you know as a downside there is an upside to to being with my family
you gotta pay somewhere you can't get everything for free now people who don't have families I'm sorry but
you know I would even encourage you to go to work staying at home all day is not good for your mental health if you
don't have families uh even if you just have a wife and you don't have kids it's not good for you just to be at home all
day locked in a room same room every day nobody around you that's that's not healthy and I would say try maybe
you know going into work when they have those uh they have uh pretty much every
job has open desks for you to go in and work the problem there is if nobody else
is there then you're just in a bigger room alone and you had to travel to get there so there is kind of an incentive
in that way for companies to request people to come in to work so that people
can see each other so that it gives incentive to people who want to come in maybe not all the time to come in
it's a very difficult situation I understand the perspective as a work from home person who does not want to
change it because I have children I will say though if I didn't have children I'd be going back to work I
would actually be going in I would probably get a different job that was closer to me so I didn't spend four hours traveling
but I would likely go into work because I just I love that social atmosphere of being
with like-minded people working together that sort of thing it's I just miss it
so really the only reason I don't is my kids so that's that's kind of
the two sides of the coin I feel the upsides like I said previously of
working from home for even for people without kids are obvious uh lower cost of living
for example I I lived in a high cost area and in 2020 I moved
back to be with family and just my entire you know extended family were
really close so by doing that my cost of living went way down and that was a huge
benefit to me and made it much more comfortable to raise my children and to know that I could provide for
them a home and everything else so there's just so many benefits from
working from home but I do get it and employees are not as
productive as they could be in office this is why if you remember before 2020 wework was booming I think
it's dead now because of everything that happened but it was booming because people would leave home
to rent a space in an office even if it was by themselves if they
were video editors or whatever just because they it made them more productive or maybe it made them feel
more productive I don't know but it I think going to have a space to
work at especially with others does make you more productive in general it's a lot easier to talk to people
now at my last company what we did is we had a Discord Channel and we had a kind
of a structure that segmented the programmers into five groups and my group would be in Discord all day long
and we had push to talk so we'd press a button and talk and it was kind of like being in the office because there was a
lot of banter we made some jokes we we made you know as as employers as employees do with
each other made inappropriate jokes made it just just had you know shooting the breeze and having a lot of fun but we
also did of course use that to talk about random problems so there wasn't a
meeting barrier where we'd have to set up a meeting to talk about something we just press a button say hey yo you know
I have this problem were you guys seen it you guys know what's going on and they would just respond it's very simple
uh also meetings I think exploded I don't even want to get into meetings anyone who has a job in programming
knows meetings are useless I I think this is just to pad the hours of the day
and people uh they say oh hate meetings but then they they make the meetings go really long
because they don't want to get back to work you know get back to work they want to
be able to go into the stand up the next day and say oh you know I had meetings
for this and that and that and this other meeting and you know meetings all day so it was really hard to get anything done
um that's that's common it's not as common as my current job my last job super
common current job I think is a lot more streamlined and they're they're pretty
effective at kind of managing those meetings at least for me others maybe not but at least for me and the one I
work at has tons of remote workers they hire tons of people knowing they're out of state even I'm out of state and you
know everybody on my on the engine team is out of state from the actual office
so I think they've just they're much more educated and well-versed in how to work
with uh work with remote people manage the time and get things done so
it is kind of up to the business if it's a big business it's hard to do that so
at big businesses you're going to see big businesses calling people in the at the more medium-sized ones uh you know
or sub Studios you're probably going to see a lot more remote work so that's my
long rant on remote work and like I said it has
emotional health uh benefits and negatives I think there's a lot of
benefits for families people with children I think that there's a lot of negatives for people who are just a look
you know I don't want to say alone but you know they they're not married or they don't have kids maybe their spouse
goes somewhere to work or their spouse is just in another room all day I can see there being some you know severe
downsides people are social we want to talk you know I talked to my son who can't
really make a full he can't even make a full sentence but there's a lot of social to that and I play with them and
you know it it's I think I fill my social meter if we're talking about the Sims uh pretty effectively with that so
yeah that's that's kind of the perspective on remote work if you're a remote worker
get on hey good for you but uh you know I'm not into the whole rah-rah let's
rally together and never let us never let them make us uh come into the office ever again
I think that there are huge benefits to being in the office in a lot of scenarios and you got to
choose your battles and you've got to have the skills that are worth uh worth
it to the company to argue for remote work in my opinion so that's that's the perspective on remote
work all right due to there not being a whole
lot of news today I suppose everybody is talking about Sega raising its price to seventy
dollars for games now I have heard the argument games have
been the same price for you know many many years uh-huh I hear you I mean it it has
raised you know 10 bucks once before and 10 bucks again I hear that argument
um you know it would be a valid argument if all the methods of distribution were
exactly the same the difference is that all the methods of distribution have changed a lot of
people buy digital I would probably think that most people buy digital just
look at steam sales and those those digital sales still
being you know full box price um is crazy to me it's crazy that the
price is so high it's crazy that we're going to seventy dollars we're going to be at like a hundred dollars soon and I
get that there's inflation and the whole economy thing and you know that's going haywire
but still the seventy dollars for a game that's a lot of money for people
and you know you just can you can imagine everybody from you know kids who
just started working who left their parents house maybe they're they're starting their career and they're
starting to work and develop their skills they want to go home and play games too and you're kind of limiting
them to buying one game a year or something like that like one that you can't you can't buy that many AAA games
at 70 bucks a pop in those scenarios I know because I had a minimum wage job to start and
I couldn't even buy ice cream so I'd have to in that scenario I'd have to save seventy dollars somehow
because I had rent and everything else to pay um so I wouldn't even be able to buy AAA
games I got to wait till they go on sale but then you have companies like Nintendo that just don't go on sale for for whatever reason and since they never
go on sale and they keep their games at top at their top price even when you want to buy used uh you're paying like
52 bucks and uh that's that's insane how are you gonna how you gonna play any of these games
you really want to play in that perspective it's it's unheard of so raising it to 70 that's a ten dollar
jump and you have digital distribution it does not cost you the same that it
would cost you to put a box on the Shelf of a store because you have to make all
that box art you have to produce it you have to publish it you have to work with the warehouses and shipping and
distribution and overseas shipping and all of that sort of stuff
you don't have to do that anymore you just click a button and download it and server space is cheap man with you know
so many Cloud providers competing in the space it's cheapest they're cheap especially when you buy it at scale it's
incredibly cheap so going up to 70 dollars for games I I feel like
is it's kind of it's a it's a real shame because I remember myself in that
scenario and this would have just made it so I couldn't play any games at all I'd have to play like the throwaway
sports games that everybody has as a game collector and if any of you collect
games you know exactly what I'm talking about the wall of sports games uh it would be like all you could afford so
I think another problem uh why the prices have gone up is the same thing with the the companies
they over staff they over budget they spend way much way
too much time managing and meetings and planning and jira and tasks and all this
sort of nonsense uh they they waste so much money and hire
way too many people to to make a video game and we have you know I can't
compare games now to games from the 90s where you had like five dudes working on
it Nintendo and they'd produce a hit title of course games are way more
complicated now you know there's there's way more to them and there's a lot of higher expectations I get that
but at the same time you know back then they didn't they had to make their own tools to make it work
now you've got Unity you've got Unreal Engine you can do a motion capture with
pretty cheap equipment now it's super cheap to do motion capture to set up a motion capture studio and the studios of
work that just have one uh and just just to have one or whenever they need it
it's it's really inexpensive nowadays it's not we're not talking like 50 Grand
to set up a to set up a mocap Studio people can set up mocap with I remember
like six or almost yeah six or ten years ago
somewhere in there people were getting a whole bunch of uh what are they called
the the Microsoft Connect they're getting a whole bunch of those and you get like three or five of them and you
can you connect them together and you had mocap basically that you sure had to
clean up but what mocap don't you have to clean up and you know it's it's way cheaper now so
it's way cheaper to produce you have all these tools made for you you don't need crazy you don't need an army of engine
programmers you you just kind of you know you need game programmers and they use the tools that exit pre-exist and
the engine you have tons of tools from online you've got all the third party
tools like blender is free even you know Affinity or or Adobe Photoshop and all
that sort of stuff and you have ai now you have libraries of PBR materials just so much stuff to
accelerate your process and being a games at least for the last
in the last company it took us way too many years to develop a game and that's
because we remade it multiple times because it wasn't feeling right it wasn't hidden kpis
so in that part it's kind of your problem the business problem
um to figure out and maybe with less people you would have a more clear Direction so seventy dollars for a game man that's
that's a tough Bullet To Bite especially for me I'm I can tell you right now
I have children I'm not going to be spending 70 on a game I will wait until that game goes on sale
at my local game stores and I will buy it much cheaper or I'll buy it on eBay I
will not buy top dollar seventy dollar games uh like The Legend of Zelda is out
right now and I really want to play it first of all I'm about to have a kid so I can't but even so I would much rather
just wait some number of months to get it at a reasonable price seventy dollars
is way too much that's that's like how much money I spend at the grocery store
buying like five things so would I rather eat or would I rather play a game
I'm gonna I'm gonna choose to eat sorry so hopefully people people fight this and
they they just I don't know stop buying seventy dollar games or just only buy games on sales or
third party because that's that's crazy that's crazy towns
but companies Activision Blizzard Electronic Arts uh take two interactive
which owns a lot of companies by the way uh Playstation Xbox and even Nintendo
have all raised their prices and so and Sega now have all raised their prices to seventy dollars and it's a shame uh
that's that's my opinions on that if you have a strong opinion on it let me know maybe a counter argument and let me know
why we should be paying seventy dollars rather than companies kind of
you know fixing their Staffing problem and all their other problems to reduce the cost for them so that they can pass
those savings on to the consumer that's uh that's my thoughts on that
all right so I'm going to wrap this up with a couple of shorter things so one
is the Nintendo 64 controller for the switch is now available I mentioned this because I missed out on it
last time it sold out I missed out on the Super Nintendo controller and I
bought both of those just now so um those I I do want to play the emulator
games on the switch using the controllers I remember from my childhood so that's going to be exciting
if you if you uh if they're still in stock by the time this goes up tomorrow tomorrow morning
hopefully you can you can grab one if you also missed it um
and another topic that is near and dear to my heart
is that OverWatch has uh canceled their PVE hero mode and that sucks I mean I
don't I'm pretty sure that's going to make tons of people angry now I haven't played OverWatch in some number of months now
uh I I was an avid player I've played it ever since it launched I have the over
one I have an OverWatch 2 poster that's signed by the developers because I I loved playing it so much even with all
its quirks and its biases and it's angry uh it's angry players and all those
sorts of things um I loved OverWatch I love the characters didn't care much about the
stories that they put out didn't really I don't I'm not super into stories for games I also don't
uh I don't like it when they retcon a whole bunch of stuff just to to please people
um so I just didn't pay attention to the story but the gameplay was awesome the character like the way they the the
different characters were play it was just a lot of fun it was fun to play the characters their character controllers
are awesome they're networking for some of its flaws was pretty dang good or is
pretty dang good so I was super hyped about the PVE mode for
OverWatch I don't know who else was I've played I've played so much like
competitive matches and arcade modes that I was ready for a PVE mode
something where you can have a character you can essentially level them up and
play with other people play with friends randos doesn't matter I thought it would be such a it'd be a lot less toxic if
you've ever played competitive or any other part of OverWatch you know it's crazy toxic you can be getting along
with somebody just fine one mistake and it's over they're just pissed they're just gonna yell at you and they're gonna
screaming and say I said it's all I don't know choose a character they're
going to blame somebody they always blame somebody else somebody but themselves
being a team game if you're not being a team player it's probably you but I don't know the
matches where you clicked with people and you had fun and you know even if
there were close matches and you lost or whatever and people are still cool about it that's what I liked and it felt really
good with that and I thought the PVE would be that I thought it would be that experience that I enjoyed so much
from the online play playing with people who just were having fun and could
cooperate and we're just enjoying the game and the you know wasn't nobody was
being toxic I thought that would be it was going to be just amazing so they scrapped that and of course that
probably means I won't play anytime soon anymore I mean I like I said I haven't been playing for a few months
but if they said oh PVE is launching in like a month I would be right back into
OverWatch getting prepared you know after my new kid is born and
I I man that would have brought me back so fast but man it's just
I'm so disappointed it's that's the hard part is that I'm not angry I'm just
disappointed because the game was great and I thought this would be like so awesome you know with all the team
swapping and stuff they did internally at blizzard I can see how these kinds of things happen being on teams of
programmers and their develop game developers who've had that sort of thing happen in the past I I get it totally
get it probably super disa the developers themselves are probably super disappointed at the end of the day it's
a business they got to make money and the live Services is what makes their money so super disappointed in
that and uh just so that's a random topic on games and
now to throw out something for the programmers this is going to be for the
much more advanced programmers for those of you who are interested in
multi-threaded applications and verifying your code if you haven't
used uh it's I guess the language it's a logic checker
um it's called TLA plus it's been around for quite a while I'm a huge fan of the
guy who who made it just him personally I can't I can't remember the his name
off top of my head um I'm gonna have to look it up but he he he worked on he works on
algorithms he's a mathematician in the background let's see who made TLA plus
um he so he comes from this uh algorithms
background and his Focus was primarily on
a multi-threaded applications or inter inner communication between computer
parallel Computing Leslie Leslie Lamport how could I forget LL so TLA plus is a
way for you to check your multi-threaded code I think it's kind of you know the
root his favorite algorithm that he came up with the root of it is goes back to the bakery algorithm and I'll leave that
to you to look up it basically has to do with a man going into the bakery and getting a ticket and you know there's a
bunch of people tickets and and it's like a multi-threading program and it's an algorithm to solve that problem
but uh TLA plus if you haven't used it you should use it there's a funny story about it he works
at Microsoft and Microsoft didn't start using it internally rigorously until Amazon published if
they were using it and was making their web services so much better and if
you're doing web stuff if you're doing multi-threaded programming check out TLA plus it it does use logic notation
um from mathematics it's in ASCII form so you know if you're going to do like an
and or or you've got to use the forward slash backslash to make the shape
to do the logic but learning logic notation is not that complicated uh just
look it up on Wikipedia it's pretty short read and I would highly suggest if
you haven't used TLA plus this is a PSA you don't see a whole lot on it I I would like you to check it out and I'll
uh I'll put the the link to an article that I saw recently that got me thinking
about it that kind of talks about the the two-phase pizza party and there's a
there's a step I think it explains I haven't read through the whole thing but it it looks like it explains uh TLA Plus
in a basic way to to learn it so I'm going to be posting that in the description I'll put it on the Twitter
and go check it out if you're in the multi-thread stuff if you're learning multi-threaded stuff if you do web
things check it out it's going to make your algorithms better and it's going to help you a lot in
solving problems before they happen lots of problems happen with concurrency on
the web and this is a great way to solve that so that's it for today I know it was a
lot of rant about jobs but there's been a lot of things going on about it there's that interview with Elon Musk
who really got me thinking about it and those are my perspectives on that I'd like to hear your perspectives if you
have any how you feel I'm sure most of you have been doing remote work as developers and I want to know what you
think maybe from the perspective of somebody who doesn't have children and
how you feel about that because I remember I started remote work without children
and I thought it was the most incredible thing in the world but I don't know what it would be like a few years into it and
still being you know not flying solo you may have had a girlfriend or wife or whatever but kind
of that aspect of it I'm really curious on on your perspective on that so let me know anyways have a good one and bye for
now