hello and welcome to the first episode of whatever this might be I think I'm going
to call it overnight assembly because I like assembly programming uh it's it's
one of those just languages that are just a lot of fun to to program in and I do it at night so maybe that's
what I'll call it generally what I want to talk about here maybe is
my perspective as a programmer on technology and computers and games and
and code and repositories and libraries and
game engines and whatever else I I have a lot of opinions about a lot of things but I
also like to get the opinions of others and kind of grow my understanding
it is very common for programmers to be very biased about things
we all have worked with programmers I've worked with them for about 15 years and
we all have strong opinions about a lot of things so I want to try not to be
strongly opinionated um I've I've changed a lot of my opinions over the years so and I feel
like they're going to change a lot more as we go or as I go uh on programming
so uh yeah that's that's kind of the general overview I also want to talk
about games that love games I have thousands of old games and new games I have a I have a whole collection
um of almost every system maybe maybe half the systems I don't want to say that
it's something that I don't have just I collect a lot of the ones I'm interested in and I go on a spree of those type of
games for a while so I just wound up with tons of games some duplicates that I need to get rid of but
um and a lot of there there are quite a few games that I don't like because you get the games that you do want instead
of a lot anyways that's it's a topic for for another day so
I'll be talking about old games new games old computers new computers technology
who knows uh just general things that that kind of I find interesting in the game
development and software development field so who am I I'm Brent I've been
programming since about 2009 I went to school for animation and uh
so I know how to animate I know how to rig and 3D model I love I draw even I do a lot of brush pen drawing and that sort
of stuff but mostly I program I program a lot I've programmed too much
Lots I have a huge graveyard of projects uh because I I program essentially the
thing that I find most find most interesting in the project and then I
put it off into the into the GitHub graveyard it's a huge list of just things I'll probably
never touch again but it's there if I want to um so I'm currently a professional
programmer I've been programming for almost 15 years I I've been
in web development game programming mobile programming console programming
Indie programming PC all this stuff I've programmed stuff for the Game Boy I've
programmed a little bit on the Game Boy Advance I've programmed a lot of third-party consoles they're just you
know people just release um so just kind of I just like programming on a bunch of different
things and I I love low level code and I love the ease of high level code so I
I'm not partial to anything I bounce around quite often um I'm currently a game engine programmer
uh in a artificial intelligence programmer professionally so that's what I'm paid
to do so uh yeah sometimes it is hard to explain uh
the things I'm interested in because I go all over the places you just saw um but here's a not so complete just
list off the top of my head that I wrote down to kind of explain the things that I bounce around in
because there's gonna be languages and Frameworks and all this sort of stuff just to kind of give a background of where I'm coming from and where a lot of
my opinions on the future episodes you're gonna be from the kind of the source of my mindset so
let's see I've programmed in C C plus plus x86 x64 the assembly languages arm
assembly including thumb 6502 like 60 the c64 and the NES variant of that the
z80 uh the Game Boy variant specifically assembly code c-sharp I've done bios
programming glsl Java JavaScript python Lua HTML CSS XML you know those various
like markup languages bash Power Cell open jail DirectX DirecTV direct right
Cuda I did Cuda for Ray tracing um this little Ray tracing project I did I
got like a 720p um rendering of like this Ray tracing at
30 frames per second um it was very simple scene lots of spheres because fears are easy and uh I
got that done on a non unlike a 1070 or something it was pretty nice
um I've dealt with sdl and scriptum Android and Android and ndk uh wasapi if you
don't know what that is is uh the windows audio I forgot what the S stands for
it's not stack it's like sampling or something um API and I did that for a Voiceover IP
thing and I was using C and I was integrating with it it was very much a C plus plus library but um I was able to get like the guid for
the various devices and there's a lot of guid stuff you just got to get those in order to tell Windows hey this is what I
want to do so I've dealt with that that was a very interesting um kind of random project I did
uh I've done Network programming [Music] um on Unity long time ago I made Forge
networking um I since archived did I just didn't have the time to to support that it got
really popular at one point um and I refactored it to alloy but I
never I never could finish it way too much stuff in life including having kids so it's it made it make that makes things a
little complicated to kind of do a hobby project like that um so I've done a lot of multi-threading
websockets MySQL redis memcached you know the various databases of dealt with vertical databases as long as well as
like horizontal scaling databases like nosql and all that um you know lots of sqlite is basically
the same thing why not even put on this list Frameworks like Net nodejs game engines I've done a lot of unity I've
done quite a bit of unreal four and five now and Godot is something I just
recently started messing around with I've programmed my own game images so that's that's kind of my perspective
I jump around a lot I've done a lot of assembly and low level stuff but a lot of high level stuff and game engines
like unreal and that sort of stuff so I love jumping around oh and lots of web
I've done lots of web uh JavaScript stuff JavaScript games all that sort of stuff but it's I love to prototype in
JavaScript it's just so fast and easy when I have some libraries that I I just use I've been using modules a lot lately
which is a lot of fun I do like modules quite a bit um rolling them up into a single file
and all that is annoying but modules are a lot of fun I can I can definitely say that
um so that's kind of all of that and I kind of mentioned this uh but the most important thing about me
is that I'm a father and a husband that's uh that's what makes my life happy
um so other than that uh that's that's kind of my whole background
and uh kind of my perspective on opinions now uh one thing that I'm not
uh unfortunately is one of those ex-google employees I'm sure you've seen
all of those YouTube videos out there that are like ex Google employee blah blah blah blah
blah it says something like that um and they I don't know if they do that for like click bait or clout or
something like that um Google has a lot of employees so I mean there's a lot of extra employees now that they're all getting fired I'm
sorry it's not as I'm not attacking anyone with that I just um yeah it's just I
I'm not one of those I'm not like a I've never worked at a gigantic company mainly because I don't want to the lower
uh the more smaller companies they can sometimes pay
more and also you get a lot of equity so you can get a lot in the long run out of it um versus like those big companies
and frankly I've had a lot of friends who who've gone to those big companies and it's just boring they say that they
like Big Chill outside they like disappear for a week and nobody even notices they
they just uh they hardly like do any work and if they do it's something super minor kind of
just maintaining stuff there's there's a small group of people that actually like do the hard work and of course if you're
a programmer which you likely are I don't know who would be watching this that doesn't like the program or is interested in games you know the
industry has a lot of leads and managers and those sorts of people that don't really program a lot you can have like a
lead in a lead engineer and they don't do a lot of programming the one that I
work with does a lot of programming but typically especially the big places they you can get some that have that hardly
ever program ever even on the free time [Music] so I'm not one of those
ex Google employee says XYZ um
like I I like to do work and I like to participate in the team and
um you know maybe there's a role somewhere at one of those places that is more research based or something like
that that I can take advantage of and have a lot of fun with um but you know maybe in the core like
operating system part of the business I'm not sure but you know uh
yeah I don't have any one of those flashy name tags um I've released lots of games with
companies mobile currently working on a console game so there's
I've bounced around a lot uh so I I kind of want to learn more about
a lot of other fields I've done I I just so many things rolling my mind
whenever I think about those but we'll probably go over a lot of these in future episodes just things that are
interesting in programming and computers and Tech and all that sort of stuff so
yeah speaking of those like X Google employee gives you advice on
how to get hired or whatever kind of videos I don't ever click on them I
don't know why they keep sending them to me but it's I don't know if you see them maybe it's just me and I
I don't I don't know I get a few of them I always have to like hide the channel or whatever because
they pop up just it's almost like clockwork
another thing that I like to do is I like to program very small I like I like very small
programs I like very fast programs I like elegant code and elegant functions
very small functions that sort of stuff and if you look at what these big
companies produce they produce simple libraries and their apps they
have tens of thousands of classes that make a I don't know if it's like code
generation or what but they've got tens of thousands of classes which is insane to me that's a lot of that's a lot of
something half of them probably don't know what it is half of them are probably third-party libraries which is
even worse but yeah and their size is huge hundreds of
megabytes um so and even worse like if you think about a lot of these apps a lot of
people complain about Google a lot about their apps like on the experience of of
YouTube on iPhone is different from Android which is different from Android tablet which is different from the web
and you'd imagine when we use web technology across devices I know it's a
little bit more complicated with the iOS ecosystem and how they want to handle with all that and web views and you know
all that sort of stuff it gets annoying but you know they invested you know millions and millions of dollars in in
V8 to kind of like build this platform they can work off of and their apps are
just broken across I mean their function but they're just missing features across
the different the the different devices and you know that's kind of crazy to me got so much money don't you think they
can consolidate it I don't know I don't know kind of what they set up I do know how
most teams operate I can see how it happens but yeah it's really fractured so
that's another thing I don't really want to work with is when you go to those big companies and you got to deal with
you know across disciplines and all this other stuff as it's called cross disciplines
and you've got to deal with all of like you can't merge two things and you got
to do deal with the bureaucracy I like small teams where you can just move around you can say I want to work
on that and they said cool we can figure out you know if it works with our product let's figure out how and get you over there that's what I like about
smaller companies too it's just it's really nice um so yeah I mean
so it's not just Google and software companies like that is game companies too
working on game companies and kind of seeing the games that are produced is crazy of course it's not a fair
comparison to say look at games from the 90s and 80s and they have so little bugs
compared to Modern games and they have you know they're so much faster and smaller blah blah it's not fair because
there's a lot of stuff in modern games a crazy amount of stuff in modern games so I give it some slack there
um I I do believe that the programmers were much more disciplined in the past because they had to be working with
low-level code just with no other option so there are differences and similarities
in some aspects but games man like the minimum requirements for games is is pretty dang high of course luckily
computers are getting way cheap now so pretty much anyone can can muscle
through and punch through the wall of of system requirements these days like you
can run tons of AAA games on something like a steam deck so um you know sure they have all the
compute power to really muscle through it but they make some weird decisions like why is why are games like 200
gigabytes that's crazy so we we come up with this Frame scaling technology it
was FSR is that sort of stuff and then you still put 4K Textures in your game and your game is being
rendered at like 720p pretty much most the time or 1080p but you're putting 4K Textures in
um and then we don't know how what's what's the amount of people that do 4K that have 4K monitors versus you know
1080p monitors and I would imagine that you can kind of detect that and you can have steam kind of upgrade the game
based on you know what kind of monitor they have but you can't if you have a 4K texture and you're displaying it on a
1080p monitor let's just you it doesn't even it's it's crazy like
it's bigger than the screen and resolution and so then you add FSR in the mix and now the 4K monitors aren't
even rendering at 4K and to make the most of it of course you
know this is being a little pedantic because you can have one texture that goes across multiple objects and you
want that to be 4K in order to optimize your memory and how much you're loading it at runtime yes I get that
um but man I how many textures are actually that versus you know a giant 4K
Rock texture that they just splatter on rocks uh it's kind of funny I guess for
stretching and stuff I don't know I really think there's a huge waste in memory there
um and it's kind of you know it's so it's not just Google and big software
companies that just absolutely waste your your CPU and your storage it's
games too A lot of times and I think those can be better optimized but you know what
the game is about money the game of making games is about making money for I
mean mostly it's having fun is sometimes what the designers care about even
though they've got to make the investors happy but 4K textures are kind of going crazy
right now I think we can probably reduce a lot of that and rely more on the FSR stuff
um and it's just uh you know I think I think that's uh you know that's a whole rant there uh
there's there's also when it comes to wasting and we're going to combine the two now we're going to
take software and we're going to combine it with games and what they both do wrong one of the
things I hate hate is a strong word once one of the things I strongly dislike is
uh Json I I mean it's fantastic and the argument is always
what if we need to read it and modify it
and the funny thing about that is they try to compress Json so it becomes unreadable it's just unreal unreadable
garbled mess because you're trying to reduce the string sizes as you try to compress this data
and so you lose the readability and it's still bloated and then your CPU has to pay the cost of parsing it well first of
all serializing it so it takes this binary data it serializes it and it's got to pay somebody else's poor computer
is going to take the cost of deserializing it and parsing it turning it back into an uh you know
binary objects and then you have to also transport it across the wire then we
have to use compression algorithms so we're using more CPU to compress that those strings which they can get pretty
compressed just for the standard zip algorithm and then you and you want to send that and then you
got to decompress it so you know I have this I have this Theory
that Json files alone like if you if you took
all of the the energy all of the the power that we use in our computers and
our smartphones to parse and read and do all of that and transmit and zip Json
data you could probably give an entire small country somewhere
power for free because that's how much is being wasted and then you can take
all you can add up all the heat that the CPUs generate by parsing and doing all that just a cumulative over like a month
or something every device that does it and you could probably heat an entire small country with that amount of heat
so it's a waste it's a it's a weird thing to think about you know um
you We complain a lot about oh you know crypto mining using tons of
energy blah blah blah uh it's it's bad for the environment well you know what
else is bad for the environment uh using Json files for everything when you can
simply and and easily just serialize binary where you just take binary
make it basically into a file and send it you can do whatever compression you want if you want to but binary is already
smaller Json so yeah all the crypto miners wasting tons of power right
across across the planet yeah you know what else is wasting power Json deserialization my goodness Json
deserialization and 4K textures let's get those reduced and let's let's save the environment from from just taking
those out of the out of the picture so uh yeah that's that's kind of my
perspective on on how did I get on this let's talk about Google people on YouTube uh or ex-google
people uh so anyways yeah it's just super wasteful the entire industry is
very wasteful in how they do things and I I know we don't all use C but in C you
can just take a struct or even a a compound struct of plain old data let's say there's no pointers or even if you
just write a little function to get rid of the pointers um I I mean I would I would argue that
if you're going to be serializing data and there's going to be pointers in there um if you have to have them in there you
should separate them into their own structure so you can easily strip it out or put it as like a head and then do the
offset so you can find the offset of where the Pod starts pod for plain old data
and then just write it but and see you can just take that struct and just
right to a file or across the network you don't have to do any compression or
serialization or anything like that you just here's a struct it's a set of data and then send it off and
that's how much energy you would save from doing that is is quite tremendous
but I know we don't all use C and I know C is I didn't say it but C is my
favorite language is just I love it because I can use it in a lot of things like Game Boy advanced programming so
it's just nice and flat and I don't have to worry about objects I'm a very simple man but
let's say you're doing C plus plus and I do a lot of C plus plus obviously my my day job is programming in c plus
um so in C plus plus yes you do have a little bit of a problem because you don't have
an ABI you don't have a standard for ABI so you don't know if application binary
interface basically the byte order of a class or a struct
so uh just I guess I can explain that real quick for those of you who don't know and see you have this flat API and
um now I I don't want to get too much into alignment and all that sort of stuff
um because you do have to do some work there if you're if you're dealing with things like that if you if you're
say serial if you're sending something from like a 64-bit computer over to a 16-bit computer you're definitely going
to have to do a little bit of work [Music] on that but let's say that you set up
your struct with the proper alignment and all that and see you could just send it straight across and knowing that maybe your smallest or minimum spec is
16 is going to be a did I say bite 16 bits so
you can uh let's say that you want to do that uh I've lost my train of thought on
that alignment and let's say you have all that you can send it straight across now one of the problems you have in C
plus plus is that it doesn't have that ABI across compilers and even compiler versions like you if you use clang
X and then you use cling y it's not guaranteed that the name mangling or the
which doesn't matter in this in this argument but the API is going to be the same and that's because mainly I think
it's because of the V table a v table is a piece is a is a block of
your your class for virtual classes where they can they point to the
function it should call when you call a function as you know you can create a virtual function you can override those
functions in the child classes or the derivatives whatever you want to call them
now that that V table could be at the top it could be split right in the middle of the the binary data it could
be like at the end of the class um there's no telling where that is so just like serializing and sending it off
is going to be a little bit of a problem and that's where serialization labor libraries start coming in
um you have other languages where you don't have access to the raw binary of
the class um without you know turning on special Flags or whatever for the compiler like in c-sharp or say JavaScript or
something like that so sending things straight over
like you do in C is not as easy and so I do understand that part of where we get into this
this whole let's Json serialize it because then I can write my program in c-sharp and then have a JavaScript
client be able to read the data and I don't have to worry about I don't have to worry about indian-ness or I don't
have to worry about you know the alignment or anything like that um so yeah there it does kind of reduce
the cost of of effort up front to to do those kind of like just use the Json
library but it's so wasteful I think that if you just it it's really
programs programs companies have this weird thing where they think
that it takes months to do something as simple as serializing some bites they're
like well I don't know what that fits into the schedule um man that's a whole other thing let's not go
on that but yeah I I do understand that you know
it's a it's a cost analysis um no company I can tell you this I've worked at so many different companies no
company they none of them care about how much uh Power you're drawing from a wall
socket to run their program as long as it's fast and it gets the uh the player
or the client what they need um now this is a different argument for
mobile and mobile they sometimes do care because they want good battery life I don't want to say
excellent battery life otherwise they wouldn't use engines that drain battery life they would you know write their own
stuff um but they they do care a little bit there so I'll give them credit that on
that so this brings us to to things like
uh gosh what's what's it called protobuf okay protobuf um does help you with it that binary
seller is serialization now I didn't I didn't go through the entirety of the class or all the classes to determine
whether the binary serialization is efficient um I assume it's efficient because it's
open source and a lot of people looked at it and probably have contributed and I do I I know I prefixed this earlier
about Google employees and all that sort of stuff it's not to say they're bad programmers
um it's just uh you know there are some bad programs that come out of Google a
lot of bad programs that come out of Google and it's not the fault of the programmer most of the time is The Fault
the you know the company um so they do have good programmers that do
study this stuff and take the effort and they do the research and all this other stuff which is very important to everybody especially when you open
source it so no complaints from me there but purple buff is like hundreds of
thousands of lines of code to serialize some bytes and that is huge
um I have this I have this this thought about libraries and even
programmers just inside of a company uh programmers are often stuck to doing
a specific type of work on these big companies so
I like to say that if you took a person and you paid them a pretty good amount of money
and you give them a rock in the corner of a room and you said
your job is to manage this rock the best thing that person could do
is not do anything the rock is going to be completely fine but chances are you're going to come back two weeks
later and the rock is going to have a little house set up with a little dinner table and it's kind of a it's going to
be laying inside of a little bed with a blanket over it and then once you ask the developer how he's going you're
going to say oh well you see I've optimized the living situation for this rock and I've also you know created a
Giro workflow so that we can keep track of its schedule and that's just how people are when you
pay them a good amount of money and tell them to do something they overdo it every time because
um maybe it's because they're bored and they need something to do and the task wasn't interesting enough so they go way
off the wall or maybe they're trying to prove something you know they're they they want a higher salary or maybe a
different position so they they're really kind of um you know they really kind of Polish The
Rock so to speak so I feel that's the case for a lot of libraries you you set
a library out there let's say a logging Library and it does sufficiently what you need
it to do for your program so then all of a sudden
everyone I don't know it gets picked up by by somebody on a YouTube video or something and then everybody's using
Olson you have half a million people downloading or half million downloads on your library
you all of a sudden turn over and say man there's a lot of people downloading this Library
I need to improve it and so you start going in there and you start adding tons and tons of features that are not
needed at all remember that you got you know half a half a million downloads already that means it does what people
want and of course they're going to come and complain the other part is and as this is not the fault of the the person
polishing the rock this is the Fault to the people who are using their libraries people often think that if a library is
not updated in the past like month or half a year it's all of a sudden just broken it just you can't use this it's it's just ugh it
doesn't work anymore like code just the code just rotted itself out of existence for setting from setting there for too
long I don't know and there's a lot of pressure on that to keep them updating and doing things like that now
also you have open source so you have you know hundreds of people sending issues and also pull requests and you
start accepting things and it just bloats and so this is what happens with libraries and I don't think protobuf is
any exception to this I just want to serialize some bytes and so protobuf is
is is quite big here I'll let me let me look up the
protobuf [Music] here so we have the protocol buffers
and I'll actually just is this the main library looks like it
it was updated five hours ago this thing worked like five years ago or whatever when I was
using it um but it's still being updated you know five years later it's in serious
business taking some bites and putting them into a file across the network and I know I'm simplifying it I've done tons of network
stuff I get it um half the time you don't even use protobuf for Network stuff so there's
there's that um but we're gonna I'm just gonna I'm gonna grab this guy hold on I've got
to turn off the thing on my computer that talks to me whenever I copy text okay so I'm gonna grab this guy
and we will go ahead and
go ahead and clone it down somewhere um
put it in in a document documents
go to get get clone that guy so we'll clone it down and let's take a
look at where the source code is for this guy and of course a lot of the source code is going to be in you know language
wrappers and that's that might be where you know half the updates are coming from is language rappers I don't know
but you got C sharp Java python Ruby rust blah blah so it's probably gonna be in the source
folder and in this Google Proto buff here
so it's still download but let's take a little
ubunt uh local instance here and let's uh go over to
uh let's go to what is it Mount see users
Grant documents get and this is going to be inside of Proto buff
and then if we go inside of this folder so let's see the source
to use Google so you have Proto buff so here we are
inside of Proto buff and we're going to do a little experiment here if I type it right so
we're going to find dot um we need a little reg X I have this
written down because I am not uh you know the most incredible person
um remembering all these uh Unix or Linux commands one of the
beautiful things about Linux is that programs do a single thing they do it well and I I love that that's that's a
the best design decision anyone could have in fact I think I can you know let
me copy I think I could just copy this text and paste it into the terminal here
I know I can whoop it looks like I got a weird binary
thing at the beginning there let me see if it's because the way I copied it no here let's just go to
you can't see it off screen but I have this inside of a little word or something okay
okay F there we go so I'm going to do this regex to to just get all the headers CCC files and CPP files because
this is a C plus plus repository I could do print zero instead of print
so that I can do x x Arc zero I want to do basically a line count I'm going to
count the lines in this project so just to serialize bytes in one
language uh is over a quarter million lines of code and I don't know if some of those
lines are comments or whatever but this I've written a game engine that that
uses Vulcan and all all in C so I've got to do the Vulcan library in C and then
it works with entities and it has it just it has all the Transformations
and all that sort of stuff including the shaders and it's less code is less lines
of code than this and it has tons of comments too so a quarter over a quarter million uh lines of code is a lot of
code for serializing some bytes now that's kind of where I'm coming from on this and if we go to the rappers
hopefully um they're not as they're not as big let's take a look at
let's say C sharp um there's a lot of batch files in here Keys v test okay here we go Source okay
so C sharp source and then of course we've got
what are all these uh tests and let's just do the whole thing we only life is
short um so this is much easier we can just do
CS files so this one alone is 142 139 and this is
a wrapper to like call I don't know if they re-implemented the code in C sharp or if they're calling the C plus plus
code here not a percent sure but still it's it's a lot of
it's a lot of code to write some bytes so that's kind of
my perspective on you know big companies their code bases libraries
um I thought this is a nice simple way to to start off whatever series I'm doing
here um let's just talk about some code I like code and I'm not like I said I'm not
complaining about all this it all functions I've used it it's it makes things a lot easier
companies should use them rather than rolling their own because most likely
you're going to make a mistake if you roll your own and you've got to deal with all that debugging and stuff I'm just putting out I uh hypothesis
hypotheses or or ideas here about how much power is wasted and kind of how how
programmers um you know polish rocks and I polish rocks
all the time so uh yeah and I I think that's
um yeah that's that's all I got for for our
my view on just coding programming
third-party libraries I don't I don't know exactly what I'm going to go over and kind of future with these few future
future podcasts I guess these are um now I understand what I'm sure what
I'm going to go over I can go over uh you know assembly for Game Boy games I can kind of dive into
other people's code I can just talk about games in general and game design I have a lot of ideas or thoughts on game
design um and and try not to ramble on them here and I've got uh you know
lots of thoughts of how we connect software together from you know straight from the the hardware in the CNC plus
plus area or you know whatever language level low level language that you use or
like all the way up to how it communicates with a web server
um yeah I think that there's just a lot to think about a lot to talk about and a
lot to have fun with um so this is like the first episode of of
this podcast and I don't know how many people are gonna watch it and people are even gonna see it but if
you guys do exist uh feel free to to like throw out some ideas of what to talk about
because um like I said it doesn't it doesn't have to be just about code I love code I could talk about code all day I and it's
been like 40 minutes I didn't even notice this time flew by um but I could talk about games and game
design old games collecting games I collect a lot of games I could talk about art um
art as it relates to programming or games or or just art in general I like to draw some I have a lot of thoughts on
on that sort of stuff so uh yeah it'd be really interesting to see if anybody has
some ideas of what to look over um I I thought this was
a lot of fun I like talking about code this is awesome anyways see you guys