welcome back today we're one step closer to Microsoft buying blizzard
some new sea stuff I got a PHP note uh we got there's a lot of stuff about
programmer health and some other stuff to go over today so I guess the the first big story that
happened today was Microsoft is one step closer to buying blizzard of course this is all part of the
industry consolidation that everyone's talked about for the game industry and it's
part of uh I think it's it's it's related to something I mentioned before which is
we have an issue where a lot of stuff there's just a lot of games being
published out to steam and app stores on both IOS and Android and a lot now even
on the Nintendo switch which used to be a really walled off garden garden and with all that noise it's really hard
for people to punch through it and become successful a lot of them have to go through
YouTubers and YouTubers have a very specific show to put on so a lot of
games are being kind of developed in a way that YouTubers can can use them to be funny
or entertaining and so we've got a lot of noise in that at respect
there's a lot of games that are getting published with unity assets store stuff they just pull some stuff off the asset
store they pay a few bucks for throw it all together do some very light coding
and then they put out a game in in less than a week and sometimes they're really successful on on YouTube there's a lot
of channels out there constantly looking for more content and games to play that are
different and so that constant stream is really nice that being said that makes for a lot of
noise in the game industry lots and lots of noise on all platforms we have a lot
of adult games coming out of nowhere in my my wife complains a lot about how
many adult games she's getting on Steam even though she has so many filters to block them they keep coming through I
think it's kind of the joke now everybody kind of sees that so with all that Madness
big companies they have the money to push their games to push their products
they they can Market to millions of people they have hundreds of millions of dollars to put into marketing and
research and influencer campaigns lots of influencer campaigns a lot of streamers are paid to
pay those the games to uh to promote them and uh sometimes I I don't even I don't
know if the streamers even mentioned that they are um paid to promote them and if they do it's probably at the beginning of the
Stream and a lot of people aren't there for that so they just think that the streamer is like playing this game that they really just found and enjoyed when
those streamers are paid a ton of money to stream and I know this because I've worked with companies that do those
kinds of campaigns and they're a valid marketing campaign because you can get a lot of uh people to play your game using
this technique so how does that relate to Microsoft buying blizzard and consolidating of the
game industry well like I said in some previous videos people these companies are able to spend
millions and millions of dollars to get eyeballs in their games to buy their games and they make tons of money and
all the little companies that can't compete with that wealth have a very hard time even with really
incredible games there's a lot of incredible games that just nobody ever hears of or that never can get completed
because they can't get the funding and um so these big companies get bigger
they spend a lot of money to make a lot of money and then they spend that money to buy up all the other medium-sized
businesses I think every every company I've worked at for the last three companies
all three of them were purchased by a much larger company and one of them got purchased twice by a large company so
it's a it's a very real thing the consolidation of all these companies so the European commission has approved
Microsoft's blizzard purchase um some some other European country I
don't know what it was probably England or something denied it but there's the I don't know
how this works but it still goes through and they're still going to be working towards it I am frankly a little bit
ambivalent to big companies buying up other big companies or big companies buying up no uh medium-sized companies
it's a great way for developers if they get equity in the middle a medium-sized company it's a great way to get an extra
paycheck and it's kind of just the way the system is what can we do we can't tell people to stop developing indie
games or we can't make them promise that they'll spend more than a week on an indie game before they publish it to
steam or any other game store so
just getting past that noise is already a high bar even if you do a Kickstarter
campaign a lot of the times your game has to be some kind of meme to to just to stand out and punch through all that
noise and um that could be frustrating for people who don't want to make meme games they want to make games that maybe
tell a story that means something to them or make a game that that's a story for children or or they want to make a
game that's uh you know more puzzle related but there's no gimmick and it's just a bunch of series of different
kinds of puzzles that sort of stuff and those Developers are basically developing games for
themselves and their friends because it's a hard Market to compete with
um I'm like I said I'm ambivalent to big companies buying up other big companies I think the consolidation just happens
maybe it'll lead to some kind of Tipping Point where um
people get tired of it maybe you know developers will get tired of making stuff of course
then we get into the whole AI stuff and then putting AI into games for really quick and easy content so I don't know
it could be noisy forever or I don't know maybe we can band together all of us game developers who spend a good
quality amount of time on our games there's a lot of us so if we got together and you know bought
and sold each other's games and uh it kind of collaborated in that way to create our own kind of
um group marketing strategy in that way maybe that's the way we can punch through with great game ideas and uh
stop leaving it just to the big guys to get to to be able to get their their games out there
so beyond uh this kind of business news
um the next thing I want to talk about is C C is my is a favorite link is my
favorite language um I love C plus plus I love C sharp I love JavaScript python I'm okay with I'm
learning I mean I'm learning the python variant and Godot and I've used python for
over a decade now um it's not one of my favorites but mainly because the whole tabbing thing
in spacing and all that sort of stuff but it's it's a lot different than it
was back then so I give you some credit anyways back to C uh we got some great news for some sea
people GCC 13 now supports c2x stuff
um and some of the notable things that people like to point out is uh null pointer which comes from C plus plus
that one I'm iffy about doesn't really matter to me I'm fine with null
um this null pointer makes it a little bit more explicit better compiler support that sort of stuff it's not just
a macro that evaluates to zero so that that'll allow some better compiler checking for things like that
um enhanced enums oh also for null pointer that not only for compilers
but kind of uh what are they called a static analysis tools we'll have
you know they won't have to deal with evaluating macros by name to figure out what the context is of that people are
doing so there are some benefits there for the the static analysis and the compilers enhanced enumerations
um if you've used enum you know that it evaluates to an INT an INT on a 16 uh on a 16-bit system is
going to be different than a 32 32 and 64 basically the same and evaluates the
32 bits but it's ambiguous right that's why we have stdent.h which allows us to use very
specific sizes for our integers like n32t unit 32d and all that sort of stuff
so the enhanced enumerations if I recall correctly allow you to put a colon and
then put the the size of the enum you see this a lot like an Unreal Engine whenever they're doing enums
um it's not like in C plus plus the the class enum stuff this is just allowing
uh enums to be a little bit safer in that way and adhere to a proper ABI
because if you put an enum instead of a struct and you compile it on two different systems you can't guarantee or
two different pilers even you can't guarantee that you're going to wind up with the exact same ABI especially
across the network if you're talking to like some super small embedded device you want your ABI especially in C to be
consistent so enhanced enumerations will help a lot with that another thing that I think my
friend a good friend of mine he really really wants from C plus plus which is the auto keyword now you may know that c
plus hijacked the auto keyword Auto comes from B which comes before c Dennis
Ritchie worked on uh when he worked with B he wanted you know see he's supposed to
be somewhat backwards compatible I don't know a whole lot about B but uh the auto keyword came from that and I was for I
think locally scoped variables or or maybe something like that and it just got deprecated and unused over time so
the auto keyword you'll notice is a keyword in C and um now they're deciding you know Auto
bring Auto in and detect types of course you really need that in C plus because some of those types with the namespaces
and everything else the namespaces plus the long class names plus the uh you
know the templating make just just declaring the type of a variable
alone takes up the full 80 columns for people like me who like to call who like
to code in 80 columns you know you're going to wind up with like 120 minimum just to Define your variable not even
assign it so Otto is super necessary in my opinion for C plus plus not as necessary in C
but is nice um for when you just you just want to Auto it in and you don't want to have to
worry about it uh I don't I don't change type names that often if I do I use a refactoring tool so I'm not crazy I'm
not like banging down the door to get Auto in another one is const expression now I
know you see plus plus guys you know what const Discretions are they're a great tool for the compiler we are not
talking about the same const expression this is like a lightweight version of constant expression which does allow
some compile time stuff it's it's been months since I read the spec on constant expression for C so I I don't recall it
off all off the top of my head but go check it out it's the it's kind of like a nice little addition
again see it's supposed to be lightweight and I can take or leave any of these I can code in c99 but I do like
to stay up to date and see and mess around with like the generic macro or or you know some of the modern Atomic stuff
and things like that it is nice to to stay kind of up to date with
with computers and just what CPUs and all the CPUs and gpus are doing these
days so it's good to stay up to date that's what's happening in Sea land now
I'm going to take a second to talk about PHP for you web people who still use PHP
I don't I I love PHP because it's so simple I use node.js for websites too I
use things like Firebase for a random website every now and then to throw it up um you know I I but I do love PHP
because it's very flat straightforward simple and it's well supported on basically everything like coding on
Windows is pretty easy debugging in all windows and all that at least since I've
been doing it for a while maybe I'm cheating because I've used it for many years but php8 came out a while ago and now I
have a little bit of a rant for people who are using PHP and not using php8 I I
love PHP and I love the flexibility of it so I get it you want to use kind of
the old Trend true but please uh try out php8 and especially try out the uh what
do they call type names being able to type name and uh
kind of strongly type your PHP is very nice and it's great because it's not all or nothing you can use some strong types
or you should use strong types in many places where um you know what the type is going to be
and then you can just not use strong types and places that you want to deal with you know strings or network
requests or things coming up you know from a client or going to the client or just the arbitrary data like you know
collections or an array of you know if you want to make an array with mixed
data types inside of them that's completely fine but trial php8 and do
use the type the type name syntax the reason I bring this up is because I
don't see I see I continue to see PHP being used in the modern era and all of them are
like I've even seen stuff on php5 which I used like a decade ago so php7 is pretty
popular but try out php8 get up to date it's faster type type safety whenever you add type
names you automatically get some magical speed up in your code just because it's
known anytime you have something known your code's going to go faster this is this is why native code like C and C
plus plus are so fast other than them not having garbage collectors or being
interpreted everything you want you try to make everything known and like you duplicate
functions that's what templates do they just duplicate the functions for different types and everything is just
statically known and so it could be really fast because it knows what it's doing it knows the size of variables
that are going inside of functions it doesn't have to dynamically allocate the stack so
just a little aside and assembly whenever you compile C or C
plus plus there's a thing called a shadow stack and there's also home space these this is a space when you call a
function it has to allocate it uses some registers for the first few arguments but then it has to allocate the stack
some memory on the stack to be able to know the size of the arguments going in if the size is arbitrary and jumping
around all the time it's going to have to determine the size before it can allocate that X that stack space or it's
going to over allocate the stack space just to uh just to to support some unknown type so
uh it it's yeah type type safety is also good just FYI for all of you PHP
programmers out there give it a try I promise you'll love it I love it and I
I still keep the flexibility and simplicity of PHP I can write a whole routing I can write an entire
router um you know for a request that comes in I can take the URL and figure out which
uh like get or post request or even to to return um you know some content with in like 30
less than 30 lines of code I can write a PHP router so and that's using all the PHP stuff so
give it a try the next thing that I want to talk about is programmers
uh Mental Health I saw a lot of news articles recently about programmers with mental health uh
not issues but like they're burnt out or you know they stopped coding for a while and they're coming back or they just you
know they can't seem to keep a job or get a job the job Market's
hard right now I'm not looking for a job so I I don't know about it I know
there's been tons and tons of layoffs recently um I don't know how many of those are
programmers but I'm I'm certain there's got to be quite a few programmers within there and probably a lot of web
programmers and just because I think they got overstaffed during you know
the the stuff that went on in 2020 2019 that's all that stuff so they kind of
overstaffed and uh you know now it's hard to find work apparently for some people
um yeah if you're getting burnout for programming
um I don't want to tell you take take a break I don't know uh maybe you're not
coding what you love coding I have coded almost Non-Stop
no breaks for nearly 15 years uh hours and hours a day every day I
still have a wife I still have kids I I still have a job I still do random stuff
on the side like this thing and um you know I still could I love code I
sat here and read articles about code so if you're getting burned out maybe you're not focusing on what matters most
to you maybe you're chasing after Trends maybe you're you're you know not you're
trying too hard to complete projects that you're not interested anymore I think the key to my success in
continuing to code and not get burned out is that I just whenever I finish coding a part
of some big Grand idea that I've had I just quit programming and I'm done and I move it on I move on to something else
it's it's not that important to finish the project and you know what you don't always have to be the guy you don't have to go make
a million dollars you don't have to be super you know uh you don't have to make some super cool project that everyone
uses or anything like that you don't have to be the guy give yourself some slack have fun coding is fun most of it
is creative and playing around with different ideas it's all just a game it's a it's a puzzle that you play
around with and have fun with and that's the key and that's also why I've programmed in
so many languages I have dealt with so many different Technologies and also program stuff for like Game Boy
and I've tried out and learned like four different assembly languages I just have
fun it's just a puzzle to me so don't burn yourself out if you're being burned out it's probably because you're
doing something you don't want to do um the there's uh yeah this this guy here
um not gonna show it I don't want to point out anybody specific but you know he's saying that he's having a hard time
with the job market but he seems a really like blase like super chill and like you know get coffee
and chill sip on some tea a very it looks like uh he mentioned the
only reason I know he's a coder is because he mentioned it there's like a one sentence where it was mentioned in
this whole thing um so maybe if you talk more about code and uh update your LinkedIn do some
things like that I I'm not too fond of his advice advice is just like if you're doing front end do back end
um if you're like I don't know stuff about self-care and stuff like that look if you want a job
in Co and programming I'll tell you the secret program a lot impress people do some
math for fun make a whole bunch of websites make some games uh update your LinkedIn recruiters are always looking
on LinkedIn put a whole bunch of keywords of everything you've you've done so you'll see in the first episode
of the podcast where I read off a bunch of stuff that I have messed with that list and more is on my LinkedIn and
um I'm you know recruiters they look up these keywords and that's how they find people so update your
LinkedIn put in all the keywords of the stuff that you know how to do because you will be tested on them if you uh go
for a job interview don't waste anybody's time not knowing how to do something um
that being said my first job when I barely started coding in PHP ibsed it
and said I knew exactly what I was doing and the guy the owner had me come out to the back and he's like look here's my
problem with the code and he left me with it and I had to figure it out in 30 minutes and it was just it was a serious
problem they had with their company and this was a small company and I figured it out in 30 minutes and I blew my own
mind and here's he hired me on the spot because he was so excited that I solved it so sometimes that scenario can work
but don't rely on it don't don't take my advice on that
um there's been also one other thing related to health and programming
is uh people have been talking about software development ethics
now I have a very specific view on ethics in programming
um if it's a game and it doesn't hurt anybody and you don't steal anybody's stuff and you don't take their money and
all this sort of stuff you know if you if you're if you buy a product and you own it for example
um like if you buy a a game a modern game even and you tear it apart to
figure out what's going on inside of it and you learn their company secrets that way
that's fine in my opinion that's you exploring and researching um that's not the ethics I'm talking
about here I think their ethics is more about their focus is kind of on artificial
intelligence and it it talks about uh you know using AI to steal stuff or scam
people all that sort of stuff I don't think I don't think we're gonna
change anybody's mind on programming ethics um you're just going to code the way
that you code if you're going to get more ethical in programming you need to be more
ethical as a person and I don't mean to make this less technical to talk but
the the problems at the source uh you know that's the same truth and code
as it is with people so if if you find that you're talking to somebody or knows
somebody that has um you know they're doing nasty things and
stealing people's info and trying to scam them you're not gonna you're not gonna change their mind by writing a
blog post about programming ethics and trying to get out there and teach programming ethics to groups of people
I've seen it on LinkedIn I've seen it in blog posts I've seen it kind of it's like I don't know if people are just
trying to become speakers at some kind of event or something but ethics are at the source and the
people have to change their own internal ethics they have to be willing not to steal from people they have to be willing not to lie they have to be
willing to have integrity in and not run up the clock for their employer doing nothing a lot of programmers don't do as
much as they should when uh when they're at work or when they're on teams I have a
I have a little story about when I was in college um there was this there's I would always
be on teams in college and I was the one even though I went to school for animation I was the one who was doing
the code stuff and I wound up doing all the code and the coders just didn't uh
they didn't do their their work of course I was a coder at the same time because I was more focused on like on
code at that point but I wound up doing all the work and they didn't do anything and you know that's
not their own software development ethics that's their own personal ethics they were more interesting one of them
was more interested in looking at opengl and making a cube move or something
um that's that's just people ethics you can't you can't preach software software ethics to people you gotta teach if you
want to preach ethics you got to preach people ethics treat people nicely you
know don't steal don't steal from your employer don't steal their time don't
steal their money don't steal from others respect others all these things this isn't this isn't a podcast about
morals but it uh you need to you need to preach morals to
people um not software ethic so um please don't
go to any of these software ethics talks I don't I don't know what they really have to talk about
um so yeah that's that's kind of the mental health aspect of
today's thing and uh yeah I just noticed there was a burst in
all these I mean it seems to be constant ever since 2019 lots of mental health and
kind of existential crises with programmers I don't know why programmers
have have this you know I I feel like I've been playing a game for 15 years so
I had I I've I haven't really felt this but all I can say is what I've done and
hopefully that helps somebody out there um so I want to talk about now
Google is one of those
um they're not part of I can I don't think I see a n n the domain name I don't know
what to call them the domain name uh Consortium or something like that but they are kind of they are associated to
it which means they can come up with domain names and one of the things that they
decided to come up with there I've even got the site here to to show you
one of the things that they came up with is here's the new domain names let me zoom
in on this okay dot Foo okay I feel like that's some kind of
programming joke Maybe okay that's fine um let's see what else we've got
dot zip now the uh
eagle-eyed viewer out there will know that dot zip is probably not a
good idea for a domain extension uh what are they called top level domain name or
something like that tldn or something dot zip is probably not a good idea you probably shouldn't use super well-known
extensions for your domain names and now this is the goofy part uh ZIP this is their
definition this is what they told icann and these are approved I believe
please note that the launch schedule for this is the this TLD has been modified since being announced the schedule is
published below and has been updated and approved by a icannn
zip is a secure domain name for typing for tying things together or moving
really fast hosting content on a dot zip domain means speed this is kind of like
Zip and Zippy's Zip Zip Zip um so
maybe they didn't realize that's also for the compressed file type
I feel like that's just problems waiting to happen like who first of all
I would never make a domain name unless it's a joke as a dot zip because you'll
probably put it be put on all the spam lists and no one will probably click your link they'll think that you're
scamming them with a zip file that's already one problem and good on them too because I I can tell you that dot zip
domains will probably use be used to scam people a lot
you know free music dot zip and it'll download a zip file when you go to it
and then of course the kids or or whoever is downloading this um will then get a virus because they
went to this dot zip domain and I know it's not any different than
freemusic.com zip or slash whatever or if you meet freemusic.com and then get a
you know a zip file sent to you but if something downloads when you go to a
website you are probably questioning it even the kid would be like I didn't click on
anything but if you go to a dot zip domain and it downloads something that's a zip file you probably won't question
it as much I'm just saying the other one is dot mov
um let's see this is a secure domain for moving pictures and other things that
move for anything that moves you dot move is the perfect domain this is also a famous
file extension and if you download a mov file by going to
I don't know pocahontas.mov and it downloads a movie called Pocahontas
and it's not really a movie file and something else then you
have another problem I love dot dad though that Dad is
is a secure domain for dads and I'm a dad I can get behind dot dad that's that's
awesome so I can't get behind.zip.mov but I can get behind.dad
um dot PhD dot Professor hopefully these uh
show off your teaching credentials um hopefully these are locked I don't know what uh if if any of these are
locked like dot edu and dot gov are locked you can't get them as an individual you have to prove that you're
a educational uh Institution for edu and you have to prove your government entity
for dot gov and that's why those are successful and you can use the edu for
you know getting discounts and stuff is because they can trust that those are locked I don't know if PhD and Professor
are locked nor do I care I don't think um
I don't think certain people in society should just get and get special like individuals get
special privileges for domain extensions that seems a little weird
um especially when there's a lot of people with phds that aren't uh you know that study weird that study weird things
and they have a PhD and um or they they studied one thing and they start preaching about another and say they're
a doctor we have a lot of those on you know on the internet my wife shows me a
bunch of them uh just these people masquerading as actual scientists or
whatever and they're not so these are a little weird I can see these scamming people I can see these
scamming people with uh kind of just falsified stuff and even even so there
there are a lot of doctors and PhD people out there that kind of they don't have time to do the research
let's say they're a doctor and they're a surgeon they don't have time to research uh you know some some other field of
Medical Science so they rely on others and so if someone sent them you know if they trust
someone and that person's email got hacked and they sent them a fake thing and then this other person started propagating it we shouldn't have like
Authority domains outside of uh gov so I don't know what Esq is uh
show you are a bar admissions Almar work experience
lawyer okay um yeah so I'm not super down on lockdown
domains outside of edu and gov I think those were two good choices and the only two that I think should exist dot dad
that's the one that wins it I bet you I can saw this list and all they saw was dot dad was like yeah whatever I just
let it go we're getting dead there oh Nexus I skipped that one
um it's like a hub interesting yeah zip and mov are the ones I wanted to complain about and I
have complaint about them so Let's uh move on
so another topic that I've seen um fairly recently
is I mean it's I've seen it recently but I've seen it
essentially the whole time I've done web development and that's people trying to figure out
what database to use now a lot of these sites are going to be one versus the other so like graph
database versus a relational database or a nosql database versus a SQL
database I don't often see vertical databases in here or anything like that so our memory cache databases although
MySQL has memory cache it has you can set it up to have memory cache
as a storage mechanism so anyways the debate on which database to
use um really you should be using many different databases for the different
parts of your program that does different things with data so you'll use
I think it's a really used like a redis for a leaderboard so that you can
quickly sort and select things you'll use a MySQL for long term concrete
storage you don't want messed up like accounts and you know keeping track of
very sensitive data like that you'll use nosql databases for game data and quick
storage of save data or or like where enemies kind of I don't know if you have
like timetables or something you can put those in there just kind of transient data that's not so important that's okay
to refill um and you'll use you know cache databases
for very quick lookups if especially this you you normally front cache like a
MySQL relational database you front cache it so that you can if something's
requested a lot from those structured databases you can get to that
information very quickly another one is uh what did I mention the graph
database so graph database is great for data that is highly intertwined think
friend graphs I think we've all seen that so you have a lot of you know data that's connected
to that's interconnected and it can have some Blobs of information you know like account name and login date and you know
friends and the friends is the graph or something like that so use a graph for that kind of data so
what I'm getting at is stop arguing over database types use them all they all
have a specific purpose for specific things there's not one that's going to be a Magic Bullet there's not one that's
going to solve all your problems I know that if you use things like Firebase or whatever they may only have
support a couple variants of databases which is bad but it does help with those
types of like live apps or whatever um you should use the database that you
need for the time you need it uh cool you know key value stores also I
know that no SQL is often a key value store but you can also just have a flat
like key and value whether it's a blob of binary data or whatever so just pick the database that works for
the task not the program not the whole app for the task
and you'll be happy that's one of the downsides of web development of your web developer you've got to use
different Technologies all the time from the language to the stack to the operating system to the web browser size
whether it's a phone or a desktop window or if the database doesn't matter you're
using different Tech all the time it's the curse of the job so
that's that's my view on all the arguments I constantly see over the
years of database selection so don't fall into which database is better use
the database that works for the specific type of data and is not unreasonable to use all the databases because you need
all those different types of data oh and now I can't uh I can't go on to
the fun stuff without talking about artificial intelligence uh it's all in the news so of course there's a lot of
news for it Google has you know they had Google I O just
recently that's the developer um as the developer conference for Google
however it's also part uh part them trying to
please the investors and also consumers because a lot of people were watching
Google I O that have never programmed in their life because they wanted to see the pixel fold I'm not here to talk
about the pixel fold I'm here to talk about the goofiness of responsible AI
all these people are praising this responsible Ai and I think that it's you
know it's good to have responsible AI however putting some metadata on a photo and embedding some data into a photo is
not responsible AI responsible AI comes from the source not the output so uh
I I know that this is kind of one of the hot arguments on Art and that sort of stuff I'm not
here to talk about artificial intelligence reading people's art and stealing it or anything like that I I
have no strong opinions on that I love Ai and I also love art and I want to see
both of them flourish so one of the things that that felt goopy
goofy to me was the responsible AI stuff and if you know the um if you're in the United States you may
know that all the tech leaders except Elon Musk went to the White House to talk about artificial intelligence and
responsible artificial intelligence so you had like Satya Nadella Microsoft you had whoever was from Google I uh I think
the CEOs left and came back I can't remember the names very well and then of course all the other places probably
open Ai and all that it was there's a room full of uh you know tech people and the
president so they had this whole Meetup about responsible Ai and what does responsible
AI mean now it's always kind of goofy to have corporations and CEOs who are beholden
to their shareholders in those kinds of meetings to talk about their responsibilities to the human race at
large um but you know it is a good thing that
they talk about it and of course they get warnings and say hey we're going to regulate this thing
probably so stay in line uh
anyways the one thing that irked me about the AI thing Google I O was their big push on
uh detecting AI generated images the image thing really got me because
first of all metadata they're going to put metadata inside of images that's fantastic because you know what whenever
you upload an image to any website worth their grain their their weight and salt salt sugar worth their weight in gold
uh they strip meta tags So Meta is useless it just gets discarded by all companies
because well first they read it they read it for themselves they want to get your GPS location all that stuff that's
in your photo by the way turn off GPS on your photos nobody uses the photos where was I GPS
thing um on your phone uh you're just giving people your position
all the time it's kind of strange and who knows who can get access to that but anyways before they take that photo
and send it off and propagate it to everybody they completely strip meta tags just so that it does protect your
personal information because photos The Meta for photos can have a lot of stuff in there that shouldn't and also if
you're a web developer strip The Meta do not just take people's photos and host
them strip them out of there's there's a ton you can just take a photo if you're
doing node.js for example there's a library where you can just take the photo and when it takes the photo you
can have it as part of one of the arguments to just strip The Meta and if you don't know how to do meta
stripping or anything like that the easiest way to do it if you're kind of new to coding or you're not well versed
on how to access the metadata on a file if you take the photo and then use like
Magics or whatever it's called just any kind of image library and just crop it
by like a you don't even I don't even think you have to change it at all but you probably should just so that you
know that it's working just like crop it or change something about it using the
photo editing software or photo editing the library
and then save it and that just strips The Meta automatically because it's saving a new image so strip The Meta
inside of the photos and videos please do not do not do not read it do not take
it do not sell it do not redistribute it strip The Meta so the second thing is
um and this is probably the more clever one but not exactly perfect that's where you can
encode data inside of an image without changing how the image looks so you can
inject data that's not metadata you know like you know into the interlaced into
the pixels or interlaced into the header or anything like that of the file
now that's obviously not something that gets stripped very easily but if you
open that photo inside of a photo editor and save it that's just going to be gone it's the it's not coded in the pixels I
mean even if it is encoded in the pixels it's just going to resave the pixels in a new way when you export from a photo
program so it's like the easiest thing to get rid of so even if you use that Library example where you just take it
and crop it or whatever and then save it again that little encoded data that was in there is now gone because it got
re-saved maybe has a different format or a format doesn't that doesn't support interlaced data inside of the pixels
so that's my rant on on that that was just lip service the the photo stuff just pure lip service by Google on on
trying to make people think that they're thinking about ethical Ai and in fact in my opinion that's a complete waste of
money you shouldn't be putting you know that in fact that
doesn't even cost them that much money to put that in you know on the output of the image instead of investing money in
ethical AI put and the file that gets outputted you need to invest ethical AI in the input
how you train the system what you do with the system that's ethical that is
two different arguments so don't believe the hype on when people talk about encoding will
tell you if it's a if it's a AI inside of the image or AI generated in the
image it's nonsense invest in a in a service where I can upload a picture to Google and it
has a memory of all the photos it generated so it can tell me if that photo was generated by AI that right
there doesn't need metadata it doesn't need to put little tags inside of the binary that just me send you it and you
tell me whether it is just do that that's that's probably way more useful and then just make that an API I can
call so I guess that was kind of a rant on ethical AI so we're going to talk about
some fun stuff now I've seen in in uh like programming humor stuff
a lot of people are fighting over text editors this is funny to me because uh we have people saying I
use notepad and of course we all use notepad to do some code but they're all
ragging on Visual Studio code I don't know why probably because Visual Studio code came out and it became really
popular because it's node.js you can host it on the web you can has all kinds of easy plugins you can use web
technology to write your plugins and I've written like language servers and
stuff like that and for visual studio code it's nice uh but you have all kinds of people
talking about notepad or atom or my text editor runs inside of a terminal uh
Visual Studio code doesn't uh my text editor runs a web page within it and all
this other stuff so that's a lot of fun go into programming humor and please post some more text text
editor uh jokes because I love them they're funny
to me I think nobody's taking it seriously of course there are people out there that are dyards on their text
editors I can use anything I can use notepad I use c-line I use Visual Studio I use Visual Studio code I use Nano I
sometimes use them I use web div editable divs doesn't matter to
me text this text whatever as long as I can press Tab and I get a tab
that's all I need but those are kind of funny so uh here's
here's a I have an example here of one um this is just one I I saw like seven
of these I think there's a thing going on right now where everyone's doing them but go contributes these
and now I'm going to uh and talk about I I don't know anything about
this indie game or anything else I just know it looked kind of fun um so I thought I'd share it just
because I I kind of want to talk about indie games every now and then that uh piqued my interest it may be a copy of
another indie game and maybe a clone like maybe a stolen idea or whatever the
concept is uh pretty fun I'm actually going to turn off as some music I don't know if it's
copyright but but the idea is that you have these little paddles on the bottom
and you gotta slap the boxes that are coming down and as you rotate them the
the paddles on the bottom sticks in place so see you have the blue one on the right now it can wind up all the way
on the left and I thought that was kind of a neat little puzzle game I love puzzle games um I love first person shooters puzzle
games RTS I love all kinds of games so um I thought this one was kind of fun I so I I kind of wanted to shout out
um whatever game this is It's called swap I guess uh pretty neat idea it's fun it's
simple um hopefully it's not just going to be a mobile game hopefully there's going to
be more to it I'm not super into mobile games but it does have IOS and Android here
um and it's coming on Steam so I don't know if you're a developer head add some cool uh some some cool
desktop perks um don't don't make your game lock down
lock down don't lock down its potential to mobile devices um and that's that's kind of another
thing I guess I'll end on is if you're going to make a game
and you're gonna put it on different devices uh one of the things that I don't like
for example is old games like I don't know Grand Theft Auto Vice City or something coming to
mobile because the controls are clunky and I don't I I didn't buy it because I
didn't want to play it on phone I've I have copies of you know I have copies of
Vice City on Xbox and Playstation 2 I think it is over there somewhere so I I'm not I didn't spend any money on
it but I doubt it has good Bluetooth controller support um a lot of games on mobile don't
so if you put your game on Steam or whatever make some controller support on mobile put in the extra effort I know it
kind of sucks but let's make mobile games better by adding more support controls now let's
let's add a whole realm let's Force Google and apple to to have a little tag
on there that says you know controller required or something like that let's just make a whole category for it that'd
be fantastic I would love that but anyways yeah that was a cool little indie game called swap don't know much
more than that video that's all I've seen so uh that's that's about it thanks
for thanks for listening and I'll see you guys in the next one bye for now