all right welcome back uh today I learned that valve is getting sued for the steam deck
um other than that I want to talk about uh private chats some AI stuff some
local AI stuff clean code and GitHub and that sort of stuff
so I guess uh the very first thing straight off I just learned about it a
minute ago was that valve is now getting sued or I
don't know a lawsuit has been filed for the steam deck and
you may be wondering what on Earth could it be over and um
that's exactly what I was thinking and it's for a patent
no steam didn't or valve didn't just blatantly copy a patent or steal it or
anything like that it's just that valve is falling prey to patent troll
um if you don't know what a patent troll is it's basically a Consortium of people who buy up
software and Hardware patents and they produce nothing themselves they just sit
around on their thumbs doing nothing other than they had some money to buy some ideas from people that were
probably smarter than they are or maybe they're not as smart as they are because they're the ones who bought all the patents and essentially what they do is
they sue everybody and force them to pay them uh you know royalties
and uh the the patent that they that I didn't even know is a patent as haptics
so the little vibrations that you feel on basically everything from phones to
controllers uh those apparently are patented by some
dudes somewhere who had enough money to buy the patent and then do nothing other than sit there
and reap rewards of everyone else's success I'm a little annoyed at it I I've always
disliked patent trolls I think they're I put the way that I put it is on
Twitter was uh there the the idea guys that do nothing and set mom's basement and uh you know perhaps all the other
guys went off and they made something successful but this dude had Equity so he's just gonna reap the rewards for you
know existing it's very annoying um it sucks I think it stifles
innovation um yeah I I it's it's basically my take
on that in fact here we're gonna we can take a look at it here I have the
the link this is from The Verge you can see well it's night from you
morning or tonight for me morning for you um this just just happened a minute ago uh
the company is called immersion Corporation and that right there that name uh kind
of gives away the game immersion Corporation sounds like we bought up all the patents for haptics
that we could find on the internet and are going to sue everybody into the ground and otherwise that force them to
pay us royalties and also give us a big chunk of change right at the beginning underneath the table otherwise we're
we're going to see you um it's really annoying immersion Corporation I even I even
looked up who the heck is immersion Corporation and it's just a bunch of flashy videos
of look phones and stuff and they produce
nothing as far as I can tell on here um just some company that
I would dare say stole patents with money stole it with money anyways
that's really annoying um it happens to the best of us valve is
probably just going to pay them the money under the table or out of the court to skip the lawsuit and just pay
them royalties so that's that's
I'm a little miffed about that I don't know if other people have the same feelings about it I'm sure
a lot of people are ambivalent to it it just annoys me um the guys who who do nothing and you
know prey on others it's it's a little huh
anyways well that's that one of the things I wanted to go over today other
than that since that popped out of nowhere was private messages
so Twitter recently released their uh secure messages I think that they were
in talks with the guys from signal and they produced a their
untrustable uh or don't trust the don't trust it yet
messaging system that's just something that they mentioned don't trust it yet
give it a try though and now I'm not I'm not a Twitter hater or I don't know
whatever bandwagon people have about all that what I like is that
there are uh private messages at all uh secure
messages at all a company like this does not have to add secure messaging to
their app they could just go on being completely insecure and
that's that's not great for the people um it doesn't actually look nobody is is
saying I'm going to make a Twitter account now because the messages are secure I I'm pretty sure most people
don't even use Twitter direct messages I've never even used it I'd like to use it now that it's secure
I'd like to see what it looks like because they're a little like padlock or something um
I'm curious not something I'm gonna jump ship from I use signal for all of my
private messages with my family both my immediate family like my wife
and I almost exclusively talk on Signal and I have a family group chat on there where I talk with all of my family
and sure it does use up a lot of your storage because it's locally stored
that's the whole point is that it's not stored on somebody's server somewhere so I'm probably not going to be jumping
ship off of signal anytime soon maybe even ever it all depends on you know
where they take it uh you know companies like this could promise the world and
then swap out from underneath you to doing something else I think
though I like telegram um I don't actively use it because it's
hosted on somebody's server somewhere and they kind of just promise security and safety and that sort of
stuff and you can trust it lots of people do and they could be telling the truth but
I do like the idea of it all being locally on my device even if it is a little bit of an annoying of an
annoyance taking up the space and then having to make backups and then not being able to transfer it to another
device like my desktop there are annoyances for it not being a server and I would host my own and or make my
own little messaging app for my family and I've done you know Divi Helman encryption the whole process of updating
the key on every message and all that sort of stuff for fun but you know making a whole app that my whole family
is willing to jump on and even friends and new friends are willing to jump on it's not going to happen so it's a lot
easier for me to just use it but moral of the story here is that I love that
Twitter is moving towards these secure DMS everything should be security M's
it's just you know it's out of respect for the people who use your platform I mean
all in all they are trying to advertise to you and you never know what's going on in the background and I think these are also on the server
kind of obviously so same difference between you know Twitter DMS and uh
what's the one Facebook owns that one
and uh in Telegram and all those so um stigma signal because it's local I
mean it does now signal does store it on a server until it gets delivered and confirmed that it's delivered so there
is that there's that little middleman aspect there but um it's kind of like a a cousin of mine
he said he loves Apple because of their secure messages and then I asked him I was like well you
know they do have secure messages but if you buy a new phone
and you get all of your old messages out of nowhere that means that all the
messages were stored on some server and they can be decrypted uh on a different device just the
different device that exists that just so happens to exist with your phone number I don't know if it's locked to your phone number or anything
um so you can get all of your old messages and they all get decrypted so that that right there just means that it
exists somewhere and it can be decrypted so you know security is in the promise I suppose on that
but yeah that was my thoughts on uh Twitter secure DMs if anyone exists out
there that wants to try it out uh send me a message on Twitter and uh
yeah thank you so uh that's basically it for the
secure messaging stuff I don't want to go on too much of a rant for that um
now I I did want to talk about some AI stuff as you know I I deal with AI stuff
for fun I like making random prompts that sort of stuff nothing serious so I
am not up to date on all the crazy newness and all the things people are doing now and the tricks and that sort
of stuff so I just learned about GPT for all today
which was pretty neat uh if you haven't heard of it it's basically a local instance
um of these different models that you can run locally on your computer without
internet and depending on your computer's processing power it'll
be slower or faster and you don't need a GPU to to run it I
I think that's because they most of the training happens through gpus but this
is not training it I think there is a way to train your own stuff so which would be pretty cool like you'd take all
the documents you've ever written or maybe all the transcripts of all your videos or something like that and train
the model on it to be kind of like a mini you which would be kind of neat to see
but I like it just for its local instance so I wanted to point that out I
have I wanted to show which model I'm using because uh the website itself says that this is
the good model so um let's see if I can zoom in oh I can't
zoom in it's uh GPT for all JV 1.3 groovy
and if you go to GPT for all here let's just grab this and stick it up here
on their website um they just boast about its features if
you can't find the model you want they do have this little drop down that tells you about the different models so the one
that's already selected is the one that I downloaded for me it was the second from the top but I'm sure those shift around and it's the current best
commercial commercially licensable model based on GPT J
um and Commercial commercially licensable the reason that there is uh
Distinction on these is that you can you can actually run a server with this
local instance and you can run Python scripts to query against it and act as
like a client and you can serve up servers and like make money using it and
all that sort of stuff however these models are licensed somebody did all the effort in training them so this
particular one you can pay somebody I guess to use it if you want to use it commercially there are other ones uh
like this snoozy one current best non-commercial commercial commercially
licensable model and the reason for that is that this is based on uh Lama 13B
which is I think the Facebook leaked stuff so that's why you can't I mean you can't
be like yo Facebook I'm going to use that thing that got leaks from your company can I give you a couple bucks so
obviously you can't do that but yeah go give this a try I was playing around with it on my laptop which is a it's a
Linux laptop with a Intel 11th gen tiger Lake I think
it's not yeah tiger Lake processor and it was fast enough it was pretty decent
it wasn't like incredibly slow you'll try some of these offline ones and they're super slow it was decently fast
I haven't tried it on this computer yet this laptop much more beefy 12th gen uh
Intel Core processor um so I would be surprised if this one
wasn't even faster so yeah go give go give this uh go give this a shot
and try out that model it's the second from the top for me like I said just review it on
the website and pick the model that you find most interesting
another thing that I learned about today like I said I'm just passively
Nai person prompter whatever I don't make images or anything I just like to prompt
it and see what kind of stuff it comes up with and cross-reference it and or cross check it
I don't know check its work and that sort of stuff I do like to generate very
small scripts that I really am too lazy to write so an example of a script that
I wrote that I I modified I asked the AI to
write it for me was a Lua script that took in a text file and this text file had time marks and then text of what was
being said at those time marks and it converted it into SRT file which
is just uh you know a a closed captioning kind of timing file that
prints out the text that's being said at that time at that time step stamp so I just told it to write me that
script and it busted one out had a couple mistakes in it it didn't check for uh you know blank lines and that
sort of stuff that I I just uh quickly knocked it out and fixed it and also
added a little extra feature so it would spit out a an extra text file which was just the raw text of what was said
without timestamps so I do play around with these uh for all sorts of things uh
stories and code and all that but something I learned about today was super prompt
which is an awesome name I do love when names are
nice like the I don't know fun fun like this some names can be really boring like they're just named after
people like some of these models like Ada or DaVinci or whatever cool you named it after
person but super prompt that's that's awesome it's very it's very uh I mean
Super is used for a ton of things um basically you can probably be sued by
Nintendo by putting super in front of stuff and it they've used it so much but
I don't know I I like the title of it so uh what I learned about the super prompt
today is basically you either set up a really big prompt it's this huge prompt
that uses almost all of your tokens and if you don't know what a token is it's essentially you get 40 96 tokens or so
depending on the service you use and what you pay for and all of that and each about a third of each word is a
token so just say like each word is a token and it really depends it could be the characters if you're using utf-8 or
whatever and you're using foreign characters it may be per character that's presented but generally in
English I think the what they stated is it's on average about 75 percent of a
word and you can have up to 4096 of these tokens and then you uh when you hit that
limit it won't respond or it just doesn't know what to do or um often it'll say uh too much text or
whatever the the web page or whatever even the local ones do this they'll say I file too long or something like that
but you can either pre-prompt it with one gigantic prompt and
have it tried to see things it shouldn't say some people try to make it say bad words or whatever but others try to make
it sound even more human or like you're talking to some some specific character
in history and making it making it kind of reply as if it was that person so
the super prompt isn't always just the one big prompt in the beginning it's
also you're able to do it by feeding it multiple prompts over and over
and kind of building out this super context I'll call it I don't think it's
called super context but I'm going to call it super context and what people do is they they call it
hypnosis they like they they hypnotize the AI so to speak by repeating things
they've previously said in varied ways in order to kind of Shepherd it into a
certain uh Direction and that's just so that they can hit the neurons that aren't often hit you know on the fringes
of of the uh of the I don't know what to call it AI
Matrix mind and then you can get some pretty cool responses
um you can see kind of the depth of its understanding of things and I mean understanding of things so those are
kind of fun uh that's what I learned about today super prompting so go try to
Super prompt um maybe you've done it without even noticing that you've done it uh here
I've just for completeness I I asked uh
I asked Bing what a super prompt was and this was his response you can pause uh
to see this um I guess if you're doing an audio only uh podcast uh it says it says the super
prompt is a term uh used in the context of chat GPT I don't know if it's
specific to chat GPT I just know it's used commonly with chat gbt and other
similar language models uh refers to a prompt that is designed to generate a more advanced and complex response from
the model super prompts are used to train the model and generate more sophisticated responses that are closer
to human-like conversation they're usually more detailed and specific rather than prompts that can include
multiple parts or subparts and these prompts can get long by the
way so I think somebody recorded like I don't know if it was 16 minutes or 16
hours for chat gbt to respond with one of these super prompts and it was uh
pretty neat so go try super prompts today
um so we're going to jump from AI I'm going to talk more about some
programming stuff as you know I'm a programmer I love code I code all the time I code as a day job
I love code so much that I make this podcast and I include code stuff because I just love code
so you may have noticed a huge Trend in the last few years of people moving to clean
code I want to use quote clean code or people moving towards uh you know
craftsmanship clean architecture all this stuff all these buzzwords and clean
code is basically like testable Code test driven development for some people
tiny functions uh making every making it so that your code doesn't need comments
to explain itself anybody can read it and I like to throw design patterns in there because it's not often said with
clean code for some reason as far as I've seen but there's some really good design patterns that help you create
clean code my favorite design pattern is the visitor pattern and that's
basically where you can create a system that executes some unknown uh maybe
structured concept it's hard to explain and you pass it a class or you pass it a
function and that's the mechanic that it runs the context that it runs within so
in that way you can have this core system that does a specific thing and you can alter it by passing out a class
with certain functions or functions themselves to change the behavior while
keeping that one particular piece of code so I think an easy example would be
like rather than using inheritance to say there is an animal and from the animal there is or there's a being which
animal derives from and then you have a dog and a cat and they both have speak and they do a different response instead
of having a hierarchy you can have a flat class that is animal processor and then you pass in a dog
which has a speak function and you pass in a cat which has a speak function and it does speak that way so you don't have
to do inheritance and that way um cats and dogs in this scenario don't have any relationship at all they don't
have to you can use an interface or you can pass them as a function the cat function that does the cat speak
function or whatever and so the class itself that's managing it just knows that it gets things that speak and it
runs this big code on it so that's the visitor pattern there's tons of patterns
just look up the gang the gang of four book if you have the book you can just
go to the very back uh the very back of the book and it has a list of all the patterns which is nice
but yes I I will say all that being said do not
do not uh vehemently abide by Clean code and I'll
tell you this now I write tests functions to test AI generated code but
I don't often write test functions for my own code and my own projects I make
small functions that do very specific things which it would be nonsensical for
me to test because especially when I'm working alone when I'm working with a
team it's a different story but when I'm working alone I don't need to over complicate it I know when I write a function I don't change it if I change
it I'm very specific on how I refactor it whether it gets all deleted and
replaced with something else or something in that realm so all you clean coders out there
congratulations for knowing what clean code is and clean architecture and design patterns and test driven
development and all that sort of stuff but life is life is simple take it take it
easy don't be Zealot about it and one of the things that you'll find
is if you adhere too close to clean code and everything's interfaces and everything's abstract and everything's
going everywhere especially for your own personal projects or projects you put up on
GitHub as libraries you'll find that you wind up with
unreadable code anyways even though your your whole goal was to make readable
code you get way too many intertwined different things or disconnected things even worse
um one of the things just an aside when I program in unity
I like to leverage Unity so all of it signals all of its how it connects
different objects I like to leverage it because when another person who's using Unity comes and they they want to work
with me or they they just see the code or see the project they understand
what's going on they can find where things are and what things are doing they don't have to go through and find
the class and then go to its manager and then go to the then go to the facade which manages the manager's list which
comes from a factory which comes from an abstract Factory they don't need to go through all that to figure out that the
character can jump they can see just straight in the code exactly what it's doing
and I get trying to abstract a way to make everything interchangeable and all that but I will argue
that as a huge proponent of clean code by the way uh in in a lot of scenarios
especially in working with teams uh it is a major downside and I will argue
that it will bloat your code and make it unreadable if you adhere to it too far
and it'll slow down your code because you've you've abstracted everything
just off to Oblivion so what I like to do in my personal projects is I like to stick to flat
non-hierarchical refactorable code the most important
thing in my mind is that I write code that is easy to refactor whether it's deleting whole functions and replacing
them with another or just changing out being able to
delete maybe an entire set of files or change out the data structure easily
that's what I aim for is refactorable code because I refactor my code non-stop all the time over and over my game
engine that I was I've written in C has been Rewritten multiple times I've converted it to C plus plus and
converted back to C twice and I've also refactored the entire math library and
everything else and so it's been it's like uh what's that joke theseus's ship I I know
that off top of my head because my wife has been making fun of this person who fixes her husband's shoes and not making
fun of her but making fun of the people comment on it because every comment is oh it reminds me of Theseus ship but
that's kind of what my code is like everything's been replaced it's it's not none of the code is the same from the
original maybe except for some of my standard string string functions and stuff like that
so that's my thoughts on the clean code try to do clean code but don't don't stick to it too strictly
um now I I don't want to speak just to Advanced programmers to to more inexperienced programmers
people who are just learning or learning the ropes or getting into things or you're an advanced programmer you've
done assembly coding but you haven't done any web one of the things that I've seen in repositories recently which is why I
want to talk about it is you'll find API keys and other sensitive keys and that
sort of stuff inside of public GitHub repositories and you know people can take those keys and
wind up racking up a bill for you in fact I wouldn't be surprised if there's people who Crawl Through the different
projects looking for keywords for specific apis and see if they can't get a free key for a little bit
and um and I've seen people ask about it what do you do with you know these keys
so especially in web or any kind of development it doesn't have to be web you could be deploying uh game server or
anything like that you don't put your keys anywhere in your code base at all
if you need to regenerate keys because you forgot it or you've deleted something that you're keeping it at the
secure place you're keeping it in no big deal regenerate it um
but what you want to do is when you deploy your
code your application your game server is that you want to push your key
through through and add it as the environment variables
or add it as a file that's inaccessible that's kind of in a weird directory that
is hard for anyone to access access without you know root privileges or something
like that just you want to push your keys into your server so don't put it in your
code base don't put in any code base don't even put it in a private repository just keep them locally
and push them if you're using Docker often you'll put these in environment variables and just push them off to the
server so that's just a little tip on that because
I've seen some issues with that so uh oh this one is pretty cool I found
a random project where somebody was doing a map of GitHub and this was a
pretty neat project I I like these kinds of things I like especially and like in these
where it connects things I don't know why they're connected probably because they're Forks of each other or something like that
but I have this page here called map of
GitHub and uh this is who it's made by and VA
and vaka here I mean I can go to his uh he's in Seattle
does a lot of web stuff anyways um here's uh here's land of unity so we
can zoom in on the land of unity and you can see a whole bunch of little dots starting to appear
as you get closer you get inundated with a sea of dots and you can click on I
think the circle yeah and then you can see all these lines connecting it to things why they're
connected to those things I don't know like let's go to it page not found oh I
guess some of these are broken how about you outline effect oh it has uh
it looks like it's readme here yeah I think it sticks its read me
inside of there um why is it connected to something else maybe it's a sub-repository or something
like that it's just a readme a review code I'm not in desktop mode it's
collapsed maybe it's these packages
it's probably these packages anyways I don't want to get it I don't want to go browsing through this stuff
uh in the podcast but I thought this was really neat um if you guys know any
projects like these just random stuff it's like a mind map basically fbx
exporter ooh Unity fbx exporter
Unity Technologies I guess this oh this must be the unity's fbx
exporter plugin no Unity 3 Japan oh maybe anyways like I said I can browse
these all day long so if you have any that you like um similar to this or you know any language I I uh it doesn't matter to me
um send them my way I love to look through these um
so I this is On a related note
um have you I don't know if you've explored GitHub before it took me a long and like
I've had a GitHub account forever and I never went through the explore tab
um which is hilarious because that's I mean I just showed you I like
to look around at those kinds of things but um a few years back I started using explore
Tab and so you can find things like this one that I I shared was game engines and
I've done a video in the past like I don't know a while ago a couple maybe a
year or two ago about all the different game engines that you can find inside of
GitHub for all different kinds of things 2D 3D Half Baked all that sort of stuff
of course you're going to have your number one uh most starred stuff up here Godot
um but you know you'll have I'm gooey I am GUI however you want to
say it um it's a popular UI Library it's uh
it's kind of essentially it doesn't keep track of the things it creates it's
it's an immediate mode that's what im stands for it's an immediate mode where you have to tell it to render stuff what
it's rendering kind of every frame um but I'm not going to go through all
these but there's there's all kinds like this is a refreshing a refreshingly simple data driven game engine built in
Rust so uh I guess Bevy must be a popular one for the rest the restarians
restitonians all the rusties it's pretty cool
um but there are I was about to say hundreds there are thousands I think there's five thousand
let me scroll down to the bottom here um maybe it's not at the bottom there's
oh here it is it was at the top there's almost uh well there's if you round up almost 6 000 uh game
engines and you know some of them are pretty cool uh I kind of spent some time
perusing these uh a year or two ago and they were there's
just some really cool stuff and you can get some pretty cool shaders that people have done there's a lot of you know
available shaders um with like demos and and Cool Stuff uh I
like writing shaders but I do like uh checking out what other people do because lots of other people are way
better at shaders than I am um I don't even I don't even really use Shader graphs I
I I find them too cumbersome for me I like to hand type it but
um I hate debugging shaders it takes forever so yeah I like to look at other people's
shaders for inspiration and and that sort of stuff so pretty dope
uh yeah if you have some time come in here feel free to to browse through
the thousands and thousands and thousands of game engines you'll find one for every language and you'll find
one for every scenario and let's see what you can filter by you can filter by star most fewest
most Forks that'd be interesting and I've I'd assume it's relative to the Stars
all right let's find out yep Godot IMG I'm gooey Coco's 2D
I guess it's a little different about the same though I I feel like those two are superfluous
um or the forks is Superfluous that is the Stars kind of is basically the same
thing I wouldn't recommend fewer Stars um you're gonna get tons of zeros
and I don't know what order those are in so recently updated this might be pretty cool
Coco's Creator yeah so if you ever get some time come out here and explore the GitHub
there's a lot of cool stuff you can select on topics and you can select
different topics based on what you're interested in one topic that I have saved is C I love looking through C
stuff I love uh getting ideas from from sea
and look here's OBS uh but I love just looking through see
stuff since it's my favorite language lots of good stuff in there so check it out play around and uh
send me if you find if you find some cool stuff send them my way I'd love to uh look I
love looking through this stuff like I said so uh I think you know we're coming to the end
of this and one of the things that there's one other thing that bothered me I hate I I
strongly dislike to end on a sour note but it's a it's a goofy one to me
um there's there's this article that was posted and it bothered my wife too where
I don't know if it's called a straw man argument or a gas lighting or what um but it was about not being able to
play Zelda inside of the uh you know Legend of Zelda series I know ironically you don't
play a Zelda and Zelda you play as Lincoln Zelda and
I don't think this is they made it seem like everybody on the planet was wanting this to happen
and you could play a Zelda and tons of games you could play in Zelda you know super smash you can play in Zelda as uh
what was it called Hyrule Warriors you could play Zelda and like tons of like offshoot games
um so I don't know if she's in Mario Kart now she might even be in Mario Kart uh I
don't understand the need for people to come up with problems maybe it's because
they're being paid to write articles and so they've got to figure out how to spend their day doing something and so
they come up with these weird ghosts that they have to chase and the way they word it is like
everybody on the internet wanted this like with no citation of all the people that wanted it I'm sure there's you know
a pocket of people that want to play Zelda and a Zelda game but um generally you play Legend of Zelda as
link that's how it's always been it's a great game for its mechanics you want to focus on the gameplay you want to focus
on all that sort of stuff you don't want to have to focus on character semantics and altering your
story and changing your formulas just so you can play as one of the other characters in there and they have lots
of characters it doesn't just have to be Zelda people are complaining and I mean you could just mod the games
if you really want to play a Zelda but yeah there's this is the uh the article
in question uh by thegamer.com Nintendo has no plans to make Zelda a
playable character it's a news flash big old bold headline right there no plans
oh how dare they as theories that Zelda would be playable in tears of the Kingdom have proven
wrong the wrong all those theories I'd never heard once they're all just ugh
and Nintendo even worst of all Nintendo doesn't plan to change anytime soon
game that makes them millions and millions of dollars and is huge Smash
Hits they don't want to change it up and you know potentially alienate audiences ugh
uh yeah it's just I feel like this is I don't know like I said I don't know if
it's straw man or Gaslight it feels like one of those things where companies point at or no news people in
general point at something and then they say what do you think about that and they point it and they
they start asking that to like corporations and stuff like trying to get them the way in on stuff they don't
need to weigh in on and in my opinion Nintendo and they make tons of money they have
the IP solid it's a fantastic like everybody loves the characters everybody loves the the storyline even though it
repeats it's it's a formula that works that people really like they focus on link doing these interesting game
mechanics so um but yeah they're saying like uh
however yet again is not the case yet again oh no
every single time I'm let down every time my Zelda game comes out it's a Smash Hit and I'm always thinking about
why couldn't I play Zelda um yeah it's
it's uh they even mention uh that here we go unfortunately
uh that has many fans wondering if Zelda these mini fans I don't know where they
are maybe they meant to put m-i-n-i mini fans a small group uh of her playing in
the mainline game and that's the thing is like why does it have to be Mainline game that's why it's like
you wanting to make Facebook or something um WhatsApp I just remembered the the chat
app that's like saying you want to put WhatsApp on the front page of Facebook it is I don't know a you know a lot of
people use it or like it so might as well swap out your main thing for that it it
doesn't make much sense business-wise um you you kind of follow the money when
you're in a business if you've got a formula that works especially that's growing as big as Zelda does uh which I
think is like their biggest title uh you don't go tweaking that much you you
make better game mechanics games are about the mechanics games are not about the characters games are not about the
stories both of those things make games better but that's not what games are
about they're about what the player does the games are about the player and everybody has to get that in their their
minds the game is for the player and is about the player you don't need
to pressure them into worrying about all these things they don't need to worry about just let them have fun playing their game
okay so that was my rant on this particular article sorry uh whoever you
are this person um this is this is dumb it's a waste of
it's a I I don't like these kinds of these kinds of articles that point at
random ghosts and say why isn't that the way it's I think it should be
um you know so anyways I haven't played by the way just a side
note no don't spoil anything for me I have not played the new Zelda game I can't play it you see I'm about to
have a baby I'm very excited about this baby and I can't get sucked into a video game just as I'm about to have a baby
she'll be here any day now and I probably won't be able to play the Zelda unfortunately and I really do want to
play it I probably won't be able to play it for a few months until you know she's stable
I mean you know my wife is all healed up and feeling better I I've already got a
child to I'm going to be looking after my son basically the whole time because he's
he's fairly young and uh they're they're pretty close in age I can say so I'm gonna have my hands full
and I I though I really want to play this game I'm gonna have to hold off on it so no spoilers for me don't tell me
anything you can tell me what you like in general the public stuff like hey I
like building cars and and trees into spaceships uh or whatever but
don't spoil any of the like mechanics they haven't already kind of exposed or anything like that I I like to go and
blind on these things in fact I a goofy story I I like all the side things in games I
haven't even finished beating breath of the wild I've done everything like mastered all the cooking stuff I've got
all the best clothes the last thing that I need to do is beat uh the final boss
which is Ganon presumably I have I like I said I don't spoil myself on this stuff
um I haven't even beat him yet because I did everything else and there's a few things I haven't done
I something I like to do like there's a few of the um shrines I haven't completed so something
I like to do is I like to do all of the side things and then beat the final boss
because then it's like a super completionist feeling moment it feels incredible the downside is six years
later I have to be the boss but the upside is it feels amazing when I do and uh because one of the one of the things
that I feel suck is is if you finish the game beat the boss and then there's a
bunch of side things to do it feels like it's backwards order like I feel like you should do all of the adventuring
before you beat the penultimate boss and then say I'm done that's just me though I'm sure
but that's just what I like to do in games so games like Grand Theft Auto games like I don't even know what the
main story Quest is and uh things like Skyrim I have no I have no idea at all I
just I just get plopped in the world and I do everything but the main story that's just how I am so anyways
uh that's my thoughts and thanks for watching I guess I'll see you guys in
the next one have a good one bye for now