all right welcome back today we've got a few news stories we're going to talk about Google Chrome both with misspelled
URLs third-party cookies we're going to talk about how you shouldn't feel so bad about not
finishing projects I'm going to talk about augmented reality I love augmented reality chat GPT has an iOS app.net for
previews here and just general just general text stuff it's going to be
exciting hopefully I can sync up my audio right this time I think I've had some issues in the past but we shall see
chat GPT it's out on iOS I don't know if you heard about it everybody's talking about it there's tons of people tweeting
about it and articles being made it's this big old hubbub I don't have an
iPhone uh it's not on Android and well
my wife has an iPhone so for those of you who don't have an iPhone and have an
Android like me or just not even a smartphone at all maybe you have a dumb phone a Linux phone who knows
I'm going to spoil it for you you launch the app it asks you for your date of
birth and then it asks you for your phone number now the date of birth thing
might be some requirement by Apple for artificial intelligence stuff blah blah blah the phone number thing is annoying
I already have a an account with with open AI I use their apis for just random
toy projects of my own nothing nothing public but
the iOS version of chat chip is it's basically just the web version except
harder to use I think that's the easiest way to explain it I guess it's in your pocket and it's on
your phone so it's easier for people who don't have desktops or laptops or anything that's of that nature
there is a voice input button you press that and a big old voice thing pops up
it's not Siri it's just a big old voice thing it's probably their whisper or
whatever whatever their API is called for voice to text
so you press that you talk into it you press it again the it the big old Circle
that it makes and it just puts the text in the input box doesn't even send it so
I don't see the difference between typing with voice to text normally with Siri versus pressing that other than that one
maybe is more accurate I don't know uh I didn't exactly
over test this thing so I checked that out that was underwhelming and then you can normally type in text and then it'll
respond it does respond pretty quick my wife she typed in the prompt or she
talked in the prompt to hit send and it was almost immediate that it responded which is a little faster than just a
normal question on the web version so maybe there's that browse through the
settings I kind of looked around the app it's very Bare Bones it's mostly just
chat GPD where you get to talk to chat GPT so it really doesn't seem any
different from the web version so if you're on Android you're not missing out on anything if you just open up the web
version of chat gbt that's essentially what it is except in the web version
if you use the web version on your desktop you are familiar with the UI scheme and where things are so I guess
there's a perk there but yeah I was I was a little interested in what was going to go on with the chat
GPT iOS and a little disappointed it would have been at least it would have
been cool if you could have a conversation back and forth you talk to it it talks back to you you didn't have
to press send every time you use their voice to text a little extra features like that would have went a long way so
in my opinion the Bing chat GPT
is better on phones you can talk to it and it talks back with references and
all this other sort of nonsense that you maybe or may not want and you can set as temperament so
if you really want an app to use on your phone to talk to http or type to it I
would use the Bing chat one just in general now if you like chat GPT for like
storytelling and long longer form conversations so it doesn't cut you off of course you're not going to get that
with the bing one the bing one Cuts you off pretty quick as soon as it starts to notice it's building up a temper so
that's that's what the chat GPT official
IOS app is a little underwhelming oh well it's what we got
in a smaller amount of news that not many people may have heard of yet is
that Google Chrome is going to be detecting typos inside of the URL box
and it says that it will make suggestions of what it thought you meant
now I think this can be abused where you could go to type in something and it's
going to overly be aggressive and suggest you things
that are Google services or Google Affiliated services or websites that highly integrate with Google and make a
lot of Google ad Revenue so I think there is room for it to be abused however in principle The Very base
concept of detecting a URL
mistype and suggesting you a correction I think is a good idea
why do I think it's a good idea it's because I don't spell things good I
sometimes I I type like a normal person or I type in the standard way I should
say you know index fingers on the F and the J and thumbs on the space bar all that nonsense
so even though I do that I wind up tripping up or missing a key or my
fingers going in a way where I just I try to hit a number for example and I
hit the wrong number and things get a little offset it's very rare but it happens enough for me to worry about it
so often what I do is rather than typing in direct URL
say some specific website I will
even if I've typed it a thousand times even if it auto fills it and says this is the one that you're likely going to
do because you did it previously I still will type it in as a search
query and when I do a search query I have I have the ability to select the link
that I want I can just click on it and that makes me feel a little more secure in what I'm typing so it's become a
habit of mine to just search for for whatever site I'm going to now if
it's a simple site that I've used a million times say like a YouTube or Twitter or or whatever have you or my
own sites that I've set up I'm not likely going to do that kind of roundabout effort but if it's a site I
use occasionally like bills or things of that nature where I
may check it every month or or I may go to it a few times a week or something like that not bills but you know just
general stuff then I will type it in to a search box and then click on the link rather than
typing it out because the last thing I want to do is for that tiny little text at the top of the URL
on a distance screen for me for me to put an L instead of an i or something and hit enter
and it takes me to some phishing site which is cloned whatever website they know I'm trying to go to
and so you know call me a little bit uh of a worrywart in that way but
it makes sure that I don't mess up and do something that I'm going to regret because those people they'll they'll
steal your whole life away if you if you let them so I think the general concept of
when you type something a URL bar it gives you suggestions I think it's a fantastic idea I wish other browsers uh
like Brave or DuckDuckGo or whatever Firefox I I wish they would all do it
but that they would suggest meaningful sites I can see that Google
does have an incentive they don't just make features especially ones as low-key as this
uh for free so of course they're going to use it for some sort of advertising or or pushing certain types of products
over others which is going to be annoying but the base ideas there and I think that everything should adopt it I
think it's a great way to solve a problem and put my mind to ease I don't
know if I'll Trust it to start but maybe it'll get me over my habit of having to
search for sites and go based off of search engines so we'll we'll find out
on that augmented reality it's it's a specific type of virtual reality
that I enjoy more than virtual reality so you'll find people who are in the
augmented reality camp and really want to be in that space and then you'll find the people in the virtual reality camp
and really want to be in that space now of course people could be interested in both however you usually have people who
are weighted more towards one than the other for me it's augmented reality I really love the idea of augmented
reality having the space around you and being in the real world and augmenting it
that's awesome that's something straight out of you know iRobot or or Minority
Report or whatever you know all those those cool Sci-Fi movies so being able
to put a video and pin it to a wall and just like walk around and have it stuck to that wall where you left it
and place things and pin them to the world is I don't know it's just kind of a really neat concept to me virtual
reality kind of absorbs your senses and that it puts you
into a 3D World so it it's fun and and all that but it really isn't something
you could do for all day I can see augmented reality in some ways be an
all-day thing for work or or whatever something that just because you're still part of the real world you're just
putting things around in it and that I think is where the appeal is for
me now the one problem I have with augmented reality is a lot of the game developers it's not a problem with
augmented reality per se is a problem with the ideas people are having a lot of the time people are having these
ideas of board games you can put a a board game on a table and you have these
3D characters and special effects and meteorites and Dragons come down and moving and that's kind of cool for a
movie aspect but what about games that involve moving around and puzzle solving
and you know different parts it's not just stuck on a table and a lot of other augmented reality is
kind of I don't know what to call it it's the Nintendo DS effect where they give you those cards and then you can
look at them and a little character pops out same kind of concept as the the board game now that being said
there's this cool project somebody's messing around with and I really like it it's basically portals it's there's not
a whole lot to it you've got two portals and you can smack the objects around between these portals so you pass it
into that portal it'll come out the other one on the other side and you can pass it through and that's a really neat concept because now you're getting out
of the space of tabletop things and you're getting into the space of
objects moving within your space and you're interacting with them with your hand in this scenario so of course you
have the challenge of not being able to feel the objects so it's it's a little difficult to to
perceive but this guy seems to be handling it just fine he's
I think it does a palm check from the looks of it kind of like a like a flat plane is where the hand is and that's
what he's kind of using to bash this stuff around it's really cool so this is the kind of stuff I'm hoping to
see more in the future I want to see more games like this imagine escape room kind of scenario where you
can multiplayer with a friend things could be hidden in the room or you can find levers and pull them and things
other things changing the room it's just I think there's a lot of cool things we can do with this kind of
concept and get out of the gimmick realm of augmented reality
so if you guys have any suggestions or concepts augmented reality let me know if you like virtual reality more than
augmented reality I'd love to hear your Arguments for it I I think that
you know there's a lot of things in that space you can think of all the games that are out there you can
think of as Zuckerberg land whatever it's called I can't remember
metaverse so there's a lot of stuff out there for VR so it does have substance I'd like to
see a lot more kind of go into augmented reality and I have another
time I have another thing in this topic of augmented reality and it's this article here let's see let
me open it up it's mainly just text I want to see if I can
get a picture of the person using it so
this this is on the verge this lady is using this augmented reality set from
what it looks like it's a keyboard looks like it has a track pad and it's connected to these glasses now this
isn't anything new there's actually quite a few products out there for glasses that connect to some kind of
device whether it's your phone or a laptop and project screens and all that but in this one it's neat because it
looks like it doesn't have a screen at all it's just some glasses I guess this is the protective case that
you can put the glasses underneath you can close this perhaps a keyboard and a trackpad and oh this this camera must be
for maybe gestures or something like that uh but
I I haven't fully fully figured out everything that's
going on in this thing there's a second person using it and I guess this is either a projected example or it's
potentially a mock-up of what this dude sees it's the same device
I think this might be a mock-up of what they're saying but like this is this is really cool this is
you don't have a screen that you're kind of staring at you can put it at a nice viewing distance if you're like me and
you have eyes with two different that require two vastly different lenses for
glasses this is fantastic because you can get the effect of having things more clear
through this digital medium and what I mean by that is for example it's hard to
explain I have so in my right eye it's it's much more blurry than my left eye
my left eye is actually pretty good my right eye is incredibly blurry his accident when I was a child there is a
when I look at the viewfinder in a camera with my blurry eye it's clear as
day it's I can see everything around it's like wearing super glasses so
augmented reality I feel like has a fantastic benefit of being able to make
those screens clearer because you'll be able to adjust the
kind of the lenses and their focus and all that sort of stuff so it's just uh I
don't know it's going to be wonderful I can't wait for it I I'd really like to try this this device out I'm sure it's
going to be super expensive so I'm probably not going to try anytime soon but the moment this sort of device becomes more commercial and consumer
grade it's probably going to be something that I mess with even if I look like a dork with the glasses on I mean whatever it
doesn't matter especially if I'm in privacy of my own home uh I mean
what does it matter so super excited about augmented reality super excited about seeing these things coming to
augmented reality the concepts and and all of these new gadgets uh I don't know
I'm just really hyped about this unfinished projects this is something
that plagues developers of all kinds as a game developer I know it plagues me
constantly to to never finish projects and I've seen a
lot of Articles there's articles and and basically every single development news
blog site in existence who is either talking about
the graveyard of all of the projects that they've never finished or they talk
about ideas on how to actually finish projects now
I I do feel somewhat incomplete when I have this big
idea for a project big grandiose idea got all the bells and whistles one of the problems I have is that I maybe
replay the entire Concept in my head so many times that it gets boring and I
move on to something else but you know that's the way it works now
some some advice on Dead projects there'll always be another project and
we have all come up with ideas that we gave up on that somebody else wound up finishing and making tons of money on
it's it's happened to all of us at least three or four of my projects Somebody went out and made millions of dollars
doing the same thing except they've completed it so it has extra things that I made I didn't think of
so I generally I think it's good to
first calm down and relax life is long life is short
there are many more important things than finishing projects your kids are having kids in the at all
that's a fantastic thing that I know you think it's probably a cliche if you
don't have kids to think that everybody ugh everyone says that and then they have kids also and they're all about
kids now it does give a completely new meaning to life and a whole new purpose
and just by its very nature but I'm not here to talk about that I'm
just here to say that's one of many things it could be the the studies you
have with friends or the groups that you go and meet up on or the random projects you do with groups or your work or your
church or there's so many things in the list of of more important things than
finishing your project don't let finishing your projects or Dead projects or graveyards of projects
make you feel bad I don't feel bad for all the projects that I've not completed and it is a lot my GitHub is enormous I
have to scroll a long way to look through and find an old project
and that's you know one of the best things that come out of not completing projects
and just doing the Parts you like and then going on to something else or any of that is
that it's iteration you learn from it each time you do that you make some progress on either a new idea or you
become a better developer just in general whether you learn some art learn some programming or what have you
now I know that I've learned tons of stuff as far as networking and art and
tools for art and game engines and code and code paradigms and good structure
and everything else because sometimes my projects are just about doing a project that fits a code
standard that I've never done before and those Dead projects all add up you
know in your mind and it gives you that history that you can then use later
so all the articles that I see a lot of people either complaining about
how it makes them feel absolutely terrible they get burned out and they take breaks I've talked about this
before I've never been burned out burnt out and in the past 15 years and I I
don't see myself getting burned out on programming in the next 15 either or until I die I'll probably probably die
with my hands on the keyboard typing out some line of code or something so
don't let it get to you I I it's just something that I think has been creeping
up a lot it's crept up a lot over the past couple years since 2020 because a lot of people have been trying to
to make some kind of projects now there's a lot of programmers out there and there's a lot of people making
projects you can't expect to be the guy that's that's what I tell
um my friends and some of my family who feel depressed whenever they didn't complete something or they can't stick
to a regiment is you don't need to be the guy the guy is
out there in the world and he'll do great things but the Grass Is Always Greener that person wishes they're you
and you wish there you wish you were them it's just how it goes just enjoy the process of coming up with
ideas writing them down drawing them sketching them making flow charts coding
up stuff trying out new engines and new languages just enjoy it it's would you rather be sitting around watching TV all
day I'm sure that a lot of people who listen to podcasts like this are thinking about something or they want to
work on something or they have it in the background there's it's just a it's another form of entertainment I
would like to I think is what I'm getting at is when you do these projects it's
entertaining and that's what it should be and that's the whole point of doing them is to have fun so don't have high
expectations for your project just do the things that you love about it if you're tired of it move on it's
it's that simple and obviously we're pretty good at that because we have graveyards of projects now don't we
so three quick articles that I came across today one is Twitter blue
subscribers now can upload to our videos I think it was an hour before if you're
into Twitter blue then you get longer videos it's good to see that they're
adding features to Twitter blue I know it was a big old stink I have no opinion I I don't think that
I don't like to make everything a political argument I think some things just you know let sleeping dogs lie so
I in principle because it attempts to move
away from advertising and collecting your data even though they continue to do that I think if
Twitter was able to get the subscriber backing that they needed they would
probably phase out ads just as a feature if you do Twitter blue it'll completely
remove ads so I think that adding these new features
to Twitter blue is is great it's great to see that they're adding them I mean this isn't a huge one it's just
extending the frame uh the frame the the time length of videos but not bad
hopefully we'll see some more and I'm interested to see how that how that goes so the next one is the steam deck the
steam deck is has a full HD uh plus display upgrade and here's the article
on that from XDA Developers it's a hundred dollars
and it upgrades to 1920 by 1200 for the
resolution from what it currently is which is 1280 by 800. I'm assuming the HD Plus the plus is the added pixels on
the on the vertical because it's not 1920 by 1080. now I checked through this ad and I
didn't see anything about how it affects your battery life I assume if you're going to be driving a higher density
display you're probably going to wind up using more battery for me personally
I wouldn't pay a hundred dollars for this upgrade because I hold the steam
deck at a comfortable distance from my face and I can play it it feels good everything looks fine the size of the
screen it plays well with the with the resolution if you're one of those people
who are more affected by seeing the pixels and the density maybe this
upgrade is for you I don't know I I it's it's definitely cool if somebody does this upgrade please let me know how you
feel about it does it drain your battery you know I I do want to see more steam
deck mods because I love the steam deck I have a steam deck I bought my wife the steam deck it's a great device I know
there's New Alternatives now with Asus I think but uh the steam deck is nice because it's a
it's sold a lot and it's a constant kind of a fixed type of device right now so
the dimensions and all that and their uniform and so a lot of cool kind of
gadgets and add-ons and those sorts of things can be added for it so yeah check this out if it's something that
interests you steam Deck full HD Plus display and a hundred dollars doesn't
seem that bad for a display upgrade I don't know I don't upgrade displays it's
cheaper than a monitor a 1080p monitor so maybe maybe that's worth it
and then the third and the third quick story that I have is stability AI
releases stable stable Studio an open source
future of dream studio so this is an image generation uh AI I haven't used it but
maybe once or twice just to play around with it you go to the site you have some tokens it's kind of like the Bing it's
kind of like the being I think being used as Dolly from openai where you get some tokens and you can
generate some some pictures based on using those tokens and then you buy more tokens for Bing you search more and get
tokens that you can use so our coins I don't know what Bing calls them but the
stability AI has released a GitHub repository let me see if I can load it
up here here's their their landing page about it open they
have stable studio if I click on this it'll take me to GitHub now this was exciting at first because I
thought oh we're getting closer to more local AI which is what I want I want private local AI I don't want
cloud-based AI I think that's let's just asking for disaster I want
local private Ai and I want to be able to send my local private AI to go on the
internet to do things for me anonymously so I don't have to go on there and and drudge through the the madness that is
coming from all the AI stuff that's about to spawn on the Internet or already has a spawn on the internet now
this is not a step closer to private local AI it's nice that they made it it
seems like it's just taking their their web studio uh
app web app and allowing you to run it locally now it does not run the the
image generation locally you are required to use your API key for
stability AI so it's basically saying instead of using their website
and costing them money to host the website you host it and still pay for
the API key and that makes sense everybody's got to make their money right it's a capitalist Society no
problem with that I want these guys to continue I want them to thrive I want them to explore and you know go to the
New Frontier of of artificial intelligence but I'm more interested in private local personal AI things that
that's it's kind of like I know that man it's probably a pipe dream because
you know you imagine that your your phone is your private local device but
it's not you have apple watching everything you do knowing everything you're doing how fast you're going
obviously they do the emergency alerts and hiding behind the auspices of
protecting lives is a great way to spy on people honestly they think they've
got it they've got the they've got the formula right there for that but I I really want to see more
private just locally AI that's mine and I doubt we're going to see it we're going to see
companies that come up with private local AI devices and maybe there will be some that are
genuine but the biggest the biggest hitters like I bet you this will be something Google and Microsoft and Apple
and everybody else does they'll probably tie it to the phone and it's not private
and local if it uses their web services or tracks what you do or or any of that
sort of nonsense so I do I'm a hopeful person I'm mostly an
optimist for all of life everything I try to see the the Silver Lining everything and I see wonderful things
with private local ai ai that I can tell to do things or come up with ideas or go on
the internet do things for me all that sort of stuff I think that's a wonderful thing and capturing memories like you
know we use phones to take pictures and videos but if I can store them an AI and AI can replay them and then when I'm
dead potentially be something that I can my kids can review or they could just
throw it away it doesn't matter to me however they want to grieve that's fine with me but I just think it'd be really
cool to do more local private Ai and unfortunately this sounded like it was but really it's
just I think it's just the web I actually tested it it use yarn fire up the web API and then it just does API
requests to their service so I think you might be able to hook it up to something like
it definitely isn't going to be a one-click solution right now I'll have to look more into it and let
you know what what I find but maybe that's the future is it takes this web API front end that or this web front end
that allows you to to query an AI and then you can change the back end that would be pretty pretty
dope but I don't know if that's what it is we shall find out so that's three
kind of quick stories and yeah let me know what you think Google is back at
its shenanigans so there's there's been an there's been an
announcement that Google is going to be turning off third-party cookies for one percent of chrome users
by uh q1 of 2024. so
anybody may be thinking about this and say well that's awesome you know cookies are annoying they track US they they
their way of of saving little bits of data and seeing us
cross sites and all this other sort of craziness especially when you start embedding say Google logins or Facebook
logins or whatever Integrations with third-party stuff then they can start tracking the people who
come to your website or your web application or your mobile app or any of those
so yeah at first it sounds this is fantastic now
those of us who think about security and use browsers that are more secure
um all right you know like Firefox or Brave
we use those browsers because they automatically block cookies or you may have privacy Badger or you may have you
know any of the various other plugins to block cookies and and stop
trackers and you may use duck.com or DuckDuckGo as it's called
the funny news for funny funny story about that Google actually
registered duck.com a while back a long time ago to prevent DuckDuckGo from registering
it I think there was a whole lawsuit about it but DuckDuckGo now finally owns
duck.com which is awesome it's good that they're not into that weird battle and it's a
lot easier to type duck.com than it is to type DuckDuckGo .com or whatever so
anyways that aside you may be thinking this is a great idea Google that sounds
great now what a lot of people point out is that Google as we've stated earlier
is is in the practice of favoring themselves and their third
party partners and people who use their services and ultimately make the money obviously they're a corporation they
want to make money they're going to do that so in general the background of this is
Google has been talking about getting rid of these is the third party
cookies notice it's called third-party cookies since 2020 and in three years that's not happened
at all now uh what Google is announcing is that in Chrome build 115 which is going to be
released in July which is a couple months from now it will include the Privacy sandbox
feature flag and you can go into the the Privacy sandbox so you can go into the
settings the flags of chrome and you can turn it on at that point to block those
cookies the goal is that this is a temporary thing for people and and they're just
going to have it integrated normally so it's going to be a good benefit to
stop tracking but it's going to be a bad thing because they don't mention anything about their cookies and of
course it's their browser they can see every site you go to so it seems a little unfair to to block everybody else
but you're special like uh I think that just one-ups the
browser Wars uh which is which is probably one of the reasons Microsoft has hit so hard with Bing and
Bing chat recently and you know it's been pretty effective from what I can tell
so now in order for Microsoft to do the tracking that they want or need they
have to have people in their browser so just do yourself a favor get out of
the browser Wars of the big companies get off of chrome you don't have to get off of chromium
basically every browser but Firefox is chromium you can you can have multiple browsers
installed I have Brave is my default browser right now and I have Firefox which is my default browser on Linux and
so I interchange them it just it it's more convenient and
I don't know I don't know why it's convenient it's convenient on Linux because it usually comes with Firefox built in I guess
maybe that's why but use browsers like those which already do the blocking and they're not
biased because they block Google and they block Microsoft just the same and
maybe they'll block Google harder than the rest and that's okay with me because Google is a tyrant with tracking so
yeah swap your browsers this is a cool story but
really it seems like it's just a way for for Google to take more control from
other people who aren't Google and it's maybe a way for them to bully people into using their services like AdSense
and all those other uh their their web tracking stuff add words
webmaster tools it's probably a way of bullying people to stick with them which
is unfortunate so just go to another browser ignore Google and the rest so
that's my advice on that piece of news good to see but plenty of other browsers
have already beaten you to it and plenty of plugins have two so it's good for the the less technical
people I guess as you may know I am a programmer by day and by night and by
weekend and always I'm always a programmer but at night I Moonlight as a
podcaster so now we're going to talk a little bit about code .net 8 is being released if you haven't
heard this is all all the.net people rejoice I I find that this one is mostly just
kind of like build stuff which is cool better build stuff easier build stuff
the the that's that's always nice when you focus on that and you don't add ridiculous parts to your languages like
C sharp I love C sharp but man do they add some confusing things in there uh
nullables are a really cool concept for example and they're good if you
start your project with nulls or nullables are non-nullables but
but if you add it in the middle of a project it really just wrecks things and
I've I've had people add them into the middle of projects before and it becomes Madness so some of the features are cool
just in isolation I suppose so this one seems to be mostly
this is from from somebody on dev.2 which I think is a Dev blogging site
um so there's Ms build output upgrade
there is tweaks to the output path there's nougat
stuff um package signing for Linux
dependencies auditing I don't know what this is I handle
vulnerable packages like a pro oh I guess this is just old packages or haven't been updated in a while
uh embrace the power of you uh oh YouTube span formattable so utf-8's been
in c-sharp for a long time so you should have been embracing the power of utf-8 all along by the way I
embraced the power of utf-8 in my C code which I have to write functions for
utf-8 myself so you should be using it in a language that fully supports it but it looks like it's getting some added
niceties which is always nice to say the least
let's see ahead of time compiler so uh did you know I've done
any preview for console ahead of time now one of the problems like with iOS is
it does not allow for support of just-in-time compilers it doesn't like they don't want you
adding scripting stuff in there or anything like that you got to have pre-compiled ahead of time all the way
and this is one of the reasons Unity had to swap and create il-2 CPP to convert
everything from c-sharp IL to C plus plus now there's a lot there's a
misconception that people have that that just magically makes your code faster it does not I don't know if you've seen the
generated C plus code it is madness now it may be faster in certain algorithms
because the compiler that compiles the C plus I don't know exactly which one they use it's probably clang
can pick up on code patterns and optimize a lot of the code in that way so
there are areas where it can get faster but in general it might actually be slower than the standard c-sharp stuff
so anyways that's that's a whole tangent on just in time compiler sorry about that we've got some Json deserialized
stuff more Json stuff and some logging updates so this is kind of I think a
a quality of life upgrade not not a whole bunch of new
system libraries or any of that I don't think it really needs a whole lot more there's quite a bit in C sharp to take
advantage of you can't really use everything in one project there's so much stuff so those of you who like dot net are
probably gonna like this I will uh put the put the link to this article I'm sure you can find any there's tons of
net eight uh things out there I just thought this was nice because it was a kind of a
little breakdown with with animated images so yeah I'll put this on Twitter I'll
put this in the description for you to check it out but net eight is here okay
so that's going to do it for today hopefully uh hopefully that was informative let me know if you have any
ideas for things you want me to talk about or maybe some cool stories in Tech
or programming or game development or just any of those kind of fields that you think I'd like just Cinema my way I
love going over this kind of stuff so thanks for watching and until next time
bye for now